<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="4139258" lastUpdate="Wednesday, October 12, 2011 at 11:26:03pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="4139258.F" expirationDate="Thursday, July 21, 2011 at 9:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of CB^A16 earnings conference call or presentation 21-Jul-11 9:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2011 Chubb Corp Earnings Conference Call

WARREN Oct 12, 2011 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Chubb Corp earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, July 21, 2011 at 9:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  John Finnegan
      Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO
   *  Paul Krump
      Chubb Corporation - EVP
   *  Dino Robusto
      Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO
   *  Ricky Spiro
      Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jay Gelb
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Matthew Heimermann
      JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. - Analyst
   *  Michael Nannizzi
      Goldman Sachs - Analyst
   *  Greg Locraft
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Jay Cohen
      BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst
   *  Mark Dwelle
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Josh Shanker
      Deutsche Bank - Analyst
   *  Vinay Misquith
      Evercore Partners - Analyst
   *  Ian Gutterman
      Adage Capital Management - Analyst
   *  Jeffrey Cho
      MFS Investment Management - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day, everyone, and welcome to the Chubb Corporation's second quarter 2011 earnings conference call. Today's call is being recorded. Before we begin, Chubb has asked me to make the following statements. In order to help you understand Chubb, its industry, and its results, members of Chubb's management team will include in today's presentation forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995.
  It is possible that actual results might differ from estimates and forecasts that Chubb's management team might make today. Additional information regarding factors that could cause such differences, appears in Chubb's filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. In the prepared remarks and responses to questions during today's presentation of Chubb's second quarter 2011 financial results, Chubb's management may refer to financial measures that are not derived from generally accepted accounting principles or GAAP.
  Reconciliations of these non-GAAP financial measures to the most directly comparable financial measures calculated and presented in accordance with GAAP and related information is provided in the press release and the financial supplement for the second quarter of 2011, which are available on the Investor section of Chubb's website at www.chubb.com.
  Please also note that no portion of this conference call may be reproduced or rebroadcast in any form without the prior written consent of Chubb. Replays of this webcast will be available through August 19, 2011. Those listening after July 21, 2011 should please note that the information and forecasts provided in this recording will not necessarily be updated, and it is possible that the information will no longer be current. Now, I will turn the conference over to Mr. Finnegan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for joining us. We are pleased to report excellent results for the second quarter and the first half of the year, both of which were periods of record catastrophe losses for the property and casualty industry. Operating income per share for the second quarter was a $1.27, reflecting a $0.72 impact for catastrophes. That compares to a $1.41 in last year's second quarter when the impact of CATS was $0.38.
  The ex-CAT combined ratio for the second quarter of 2011 was 83.6, which is in line with the 83.5 ex-CAT combined ratio in last year's second quarter. For the first 6 months operating income per share was $2.62 and the combined ratio was 94.3, including a 10.4 impact of CATS. The ex-CAT combined ratio of 83.9 for the first 6 months compares with 82.4 in the first half of last year.
  During the second quarter, our investment portfolio produced a net realized gain before tax of $69 million or $0.15 per share after tax, bringing our net income to $419 million or $1.42 per share. At June 30, our net unrealized appreciation before tax stood at $2.1 billion, which is an increase of $445 million over March 31. Reported book value per share at June 30, 2011 was $55.23, 12% higher than a year ago.
  Despite the significant catastrophe losses that we incurred in the second quarter, our sustained profitability and strong capital position enabled us to continue repurchasing our shares at a pace similar to that of the first quarter. As we have said before, we expect to complete our current share repurchase program by the end of January 2012.
  In January this year, we provided 2011 operating income guidance of $5.35 to $5.75 per share, based in part on an assumption of 3.5 points of CATS for the year. Substantially higher than expected CATS in the first half have led us to change that assumption to 7.5 points of CATS for the full year.
  Nevertheless, based on our excellent overall results year-to-date and our outlook for the second half of the year, we are increasing our earnings guidance to a range of $5.55 to $5.85 per share. Ricky will discuss the progress we made in our share repurchase program and will also elaborate on our updated guidance in his remarks.
  Let me now turn it over to Paul, who will talk about our commercial and specialty insurance results.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, John. At Chubb Commercial Insurance, net written premiums for the second quarter were up 8% to $1.3 billion. The combined ratio was 102.5 versus 92.9 in the second quarter of 2010. Excluding the 15.2 point impact of catastrophes, CCI's second quarter combined ratio was 87.3, the same as in the second quarter of last year.
  In the United States, while the standard commercial market remained competitive, we are encouraged that CCI's average renewal rates were up 2%, the first increase in 5 quarters. Retention for the second quarter was a strong 87%, the same as in the first quarter.
  Our new to lost business ratio, was 1.3 to 1, which was also the same as in the first quarter. Within the overall 2% renewal rate increase, our property in Marine renewal rates were up the most, led by increases in the geographic regions, which are most catastrophe prone.
  Our average general liability renewal rates were also up as we pushed aggressively for rate increases in select customer segments that are having adverse loss experience. Average renewal rates for Workers' Compensation were also positive, led by California. Umbrella excess renewal rates were up slightly, while package and commercial automobile rates were flat.
  Given all the unusually severe weather in the first 6 months of the year, insurance buyers were reminded, almost daily, that no region of the country is safe from catastrophes. Against this backdrop, our US agents and brokers who handle standard commercial lines are generally having an easier time articulating the need for higher rates.
  Approximately 70% of the CCI business we renewed in the United States in the second quarter had flat or positive rate increases. That compares to about 60% in the first quarter of this year and 50% in the fourth quarter of 2010.
  In CCI markets outside of the United States, the geographic areas that have experienced recent catastrophes, namely Chile, Australia, New Zealand, and Japan are experiencing substantial property rate increases. There were several factors, in addition to higher renewal rates, that contributed to CCI's 8% premium growth in the second quarter.
  We received additional premiums from mid-term endorsement activity and from premium audits. These are both encouraging signs since endorsement activity often relates to things like new equipment purchases by our insureds, and more audit premium, means that the actual payrolls and sales of our customers were slightly higher than they originally expected.
  CCI's premium growth also reflected a positive effect from currency movements, continued strong renewal retention, and a slightly better flow of new business activity compared to last year.
  Turning now to Chubb Specialty Insurance, net written premiums for the second quarter were up 2% to $680 million. CSI's combined ratio was 80 versus 82.5 in the second quarter of 2010. Net written premiums for professional liability were up 2% to $595 million, and the combined ratio was 84.6 compared to 87.2 in the second quarter of 2010.
  Renewal rates for professional liability in the United States in the second quarter of 2011 were down 2%, an improvement over the first quarter when they were down 3%. Renewal retention was 89% in the second quarter, 2 points better than the first quarter's 87%.
  The new to lost business ratio was 1.3 to 1 in the second quarter, an improvement over 1.1 to 1 in the first quarter. Within the overall renewal rate decrease of 2% in professional liability in the United States in the second quarter, public D&amp;O rates were down the most even though they improved slightly from the first quarter.
  At the same time, the renewal rate change for the other professional liability segments were within a tight range from slightly negative to slightly positive. The rate environment outside of the United States for professional liability was unchanged in the second quarter from the first quarter with rates down in the low single digits.
  For our surety business, net written premiums in the second quarter were up 2% and the combined ratio was 44.5. And with that, I will turn it over to Dino, who will review personal lines and claims.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Paul. Chubb Personal Insurance net written premiums increased 5% in the second quarter to $1.1 billion. This represents our sixth consecutive quarter of growth with particularly strong premium increases outside the United States. CPI produced a combined ratio of 96.9, compared to 92.9 in the corresponding quarter last year.
  The impact of catastrophes for the second quarter of 2011 was 14.5 points, compared to 13.8 points in the second quarter of 2010. On an ex-CAT basis, CPI's combined ratio was 82.4 in the second quarter of this year, compared to 79.1 in the second quarter of 2010, and 86 in the first quarter of 2011.
  Homeowners premiums were up 5% for the quarter and the combined ratio was 97.7. Excluding 22.5 points of catastrophes, the homeowners combined ratio was an excellent 75.2.
  Personal auto premiums increased 8% driven by strong growth outside the United States and the combined ratio was 92. In other personal, which includes our accident, yacht and personal excess liability lines, premiums were up 4% and the combined ratio was 98.6.
  Now, let me say a word or 2 about the personal lines market in the US. What we continue to see is general rate-taking in the industry for both auto and homeowners. We have observed across the broader insurance market rate increases for auto in the low single digits and more aggressive increases for homeowners in the mid-single digits, which is understandable given the industry's poor results over the last several years.
  Among the companies that are taking rates are those that compete directly with Chubb in the high net worth space. We think that recent industry catastrophe experience in the US has instilled a greater sense of urgency in the market for taking even larger rate increases going forward.
  At Chubb, we are reviewing rates on a state-by-state basis as we normally do, and we are filing rate increases where warranted; however, since we are starting from a far superior position in terms of profitability, you will not see our rate-taking matching the industry's. This in turn will further improve our competitive position.
  We are pleased with the momentum of homeowners and personal auto in the US as both premiums and policy count grew this quarter from higher levels of new business and by ongoing improvement in our policy retention, which in the second quarter was 91% for homeowners and 88% for auto.
  We are also encouraged by improvement in our endorsement activity, which has been positive for the fifth consecutive quarter. We believe that the increased price sensitivity on the part of customers that we experienced during the height of the recession has abated and that customers are increasingly more willing to pay for Chubb's unique value proposition.
  Turning to claims for the Company overall, the big story for the quarter is catastrophe, just as it was in the first quarter. For Chubb, the largest second quarter events were the tornadoes and other storms in Alabama, Missouri, and North Carolina. You will recall that on June 20, we announced estimated CAT losses of between $250 million and $310 million before tax for the months of April and May.
  Our current estimate for April and May events is close to the midpoint of that range. The total for the entire second quarter, including June, was $329 million or 11.3 points of the combined ratio. It was the highest second quarter CAT impact in the history of Chubb by a wide margin.
  For comparison, the impact of CATS amounted to $193 million or 6.9 points of the combined ratio in the second quarter of last year. Until this year, that was the highest second quarter CAT impact in Chubb's history. If there is a silver lining to these extreme CAT events, it is that they allow us to show our customers as well as our agents and brokers how seriously we take our promise to be there at the time of a claim.
  When a CAT occurs, thousands of customers can be affected, but every customer cares first and foremost about their own claim and rightfully so. The idea is to let them know that we share their sense of urgency. For example, from the beginning of this year through mid-June, 95% of CPI's US customers were contacted within 6 hours of their first claim report. Not 6 days, 6 hours.
  Little wonder that in the first half of this year, 97% of CPI customers who had a claim said they were highly satisfied with our claim service. We never wish a loss on anyone, but the best word-of-mouth advertising we have comes from customers who have experienced our claim service. And now, I will turn it over to Ricky.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Dino. I will review our financial results for the quarter and discuss our updated guidance. As you've already heard, we are very pleased with our performance in the second quarter, particularly in light of the usually high-level of catastrophes. Looking at our second quarter operating results, we had underwriting income of $135 million, property and casualty investment income after tax was up 2% to $318 million. About half of the increase was due to the impact of currency.
  Net income was higher than operating income in the quarter due to net realized investment gains before tax of $69 million or $0.15 per share after tax, largely driven by gains from our alternative investments portfolio. For comparison, in the second quarter of 2010, we had net realized investment gains before tax of $90 million or $0.18 per share after tax. Unrealized appreciation before tax at June 30, 2011, increased to $2.1 billion from $1.6 billion at the end of the first quarter.
  The total carrying value of our consolidated investment portfolio was $43.1 billion as of June 30, 2011, compared to $42.5 billion at the end of the first quarter. The composition of our portfolio remains largely unchanged from the prior quarter, the average duration of our fixed maturity portfolio is 3.8 years, and the average credit rating is AA2.
  We also continue to have excellent liquidity at the holding company. At June 30th, our holding company portfolio had $1.9 billion of investments, including about $600 million of short-term investments. Book value per share under GAAP at June 30, 2011, was $55.23, compared to $52.24 at year end 2010, and $49.39 a year ago. Adjusted book value per share, which we calculate with available for sale, fixed maturities at amortized cost was $51.34, compared to $49.05 at 2010 year-end, and $45.61 a year ago.
  As for reserves, we estimate that we had favorable development in the second quarter of 2011 on prior year reserves by SBU as follows. In CPI we had approximately $35 million, CCI had $80 million, CSI also had $80 million, and reinsurance assumed had $10 million. That brings our total favorable development to approximately $205 million for the quarter. This represents a favorable impact on the second quarter combined ratio of about 7 points overall.
  For comparison, in the second quarter 2010, we had about $180 million of favorable development for the Company overall, including about $55 million in CPI, $55 million in CCI, $70 million in CSI, and none in reinsurance assumed. The favorable impact on the combined ratio in the second quarter of 2010 was about 6.5 points.
  During the second quarter of 2011, our loss reserves increased by $157 million including an increase of $189 million for the insurance business and a decrease of $32 million for the reinsurance assumed business, which is in runoff. The impact of CATS increased reserves by about $195 million, and the impact of currency fluctuation on loss reserves during the quarter resulted in an increase in reserves of $55 million.
  Turning now to capital management. During the second quarter, we repurchased 7 million shares at an aggregate cost of $455 million. The average cost of our repurchases in the second quarter was $64.86 per share. For the first 6 months, our repurchases totaled about $842 million with an average cost of $61.99 per share. At the end of the second quarter, we had 14.9 million shares remaining under our current share repurchase program; and as John mentioned, we are on pace to complete this program by the end of January 2012.
  Before turning it back to John, let me provide you with some details on our revised guidance. As John indicated, we have increased our guidance for operating income per share for the full year to a range of $5.55 to $5.85 from the range of $5.35 to $5.75 that we had provided in January. Our revised guidance is based on the following, underlying assumptions. We expect net written premiums for the full year to increase 4% to 6% including a benefit from foreign currency translation of about 1 point based on exchange rates as of June 30, 2011. The January 2011 guidance had assumed that net written premiums would be flat to up 2% with no impact from currency.
  Based on our actual catastrophe losses of 10.4 points in the first half, we have revised our CAT assumption for the full year to 7.5 points, which implies about 4.5 points of CAT losses in the second half. For those who would like to make a higher or lower CAT assumption, the impact of each percentage point of catastrophe losses for the full year on operating income per share is approximately $0.26. For a 2011 combined ratio, we expect a range of 92 to 94 compared to the January guidance assumption of 91 to 93.
  The increase in our catastrophe assumption is largely offset by an expected improvement in our ex-CAT combined ratio, reflecting our strong, underlying performance year to date. We expect property and casualty investment income after tax to be about flat, including a benefit from foreign currency translation of about 1 point. Our January guidance assumed a decline of 2% to 4% in PNC investment income after tax with no impact from currency.
  Finally, we assume $291 million average diluted shares are outstanding for the full year, which is unchanged from our earlier guidance. And now, I will turn it back to John.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Ricky. As you heard Chubb has performed extremely well in the second quarter and the first 6 months of the year. Some of the highlights were second-quarter operating income per share of $1.27 and an annualized operating ROE of 10.3%, by 11.3 points of catastrophe losses in what was the worst second quarter for CATS in the history of the industry.
  Six-month operating income per share of $2.62 and an annualized operating ROE of 10.8%, excellent performance in the face of 10.4 points of catastrophe losses for the first half. Terrific ex-CAT combined ratios of 83.6 for the second quarter and 83.9 for the first half.
  Net written premium growth of 6% in the second quarter and 5% for the first 6 months. And an increase in book value per share to $55.23, which is 12% higher than a year ago.
  In summary, despite an unprecedented level of catastrophe losses in the first half of the year, we were still sufficiently profitable to increase our full-year earnings guidance and reaffirm our intention to complete our authorized stock buyback program by the end of January 2012. I think this speaks volumes to the strength of our underlying performance.
  And with that, we will open it to your questions.
 
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) Jay Gelb, Barclays Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Gelb,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks and good afternoon. Two questions for you. First, on the level of rate improvement in commercial insurance, it seems like you are bit more constructive on the outlook than perhaps a couple months ago; and I just want to delve into that a bit in terms of do you believe that the trend you saw in the second quarter is sustainable? And related to that, do you feel there is enough excess capital that's been removed from the industry to keep that in place? And then the second issue is on investment income, it came in a little strong -- about $10 million stronger than we were expecting after tax for the quarter; and I just wanted to get a sense whether there were any one-time issues in there we should be aware of?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay, let's go to the second one first, and I'll ask Ricky to address that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Jay, on the investment income, half of the increase was related to currency, so there really weren't any other particular one-time items that I would call out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Gelb,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're talking about the $7 million year over year increase?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Gelb,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And, Paul, why don't you talk about commercial?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, Jay. Yes, I think that the feeling here is that the market certainly improved a bit here in the last 3 months. I touched on the fact that property was up, especially in the CAT prone areas. Our feeling is that we are out there pushing rate across the board, and we are seeing the resistance levels a little bit easier than they were and we're hopeful that that will continue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Gelb,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And to sort of tie onto that, do you feel enough excess capital has come out of the industry to support that, or is this essentially a reaction with the rates following the big losses we've seen both in the US and internationally?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think the numbers would show, Jay, that there's still plenty of excess capital in the industry. So, I'd say that the second is more likely, that there is a need to make -- in addition to excess capital, I mean, I don't think we should think a carrier just simply burn down losses to the end of their excess capital. Now, history has proven I may be wrong in that area, but I think that what we've seen is that with the recent CATS and the new CAT models that there is a significant need for pricing in the industry, price improvements. And we started down that road.
  Now, is it sustainable? I don't know. I mean, it's probably sustainable at the levels we've gotten so far. Is it going to get significantly higher? I guess that's still to be proven.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Gelb,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's helpful. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Heimermann, JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Heimermann,  JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess, first question for Ricky maybe. The last quarter we asked you about RMS and you said you needed some time to digest it. So just be curious now that you've had some time to look at it, how that has changed your PMLs, or just how you've thought about exposure? And I'd be curious if you could kind of contrast that with the comment with respect to homeowners that you probably won't be pushing as hard as some of your peers. Just was wondering, is that also related to kind of the work you've done on the modeling side?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. I'll attempt to answer the question on where we stand on the new model and maybe Dino will touch a little bit more on the homeowner side. We've done a lot of work to better understand the model itself and validate its impact on our book of business. And as you likely know, RMS has already come out with a couple of corrections to Risk Link '11, so we're updating a check on our data with these new patches.
  All of this is going to continue to take time before we can reach any real definitive conclusions, but let me share just a few thoughts with you. As we've said before, the new version of the model is generating higher risk estimates for our exposure to hurricanes in the United States, but the impact of the new model on our book of business varies greatly among the regions that we model for hurricanes. Going forward, we are going to continue to monitor and analyze the new model as we incorporate it with the other CAT models that we use, and we intend to take underwriting actions and/or purchase additional reinsurance in order to reduce or mitigate our exposure in regions or states where we believe warranted.
  Although our analysis of the impact of the new model is still a work in progress, we have enough information I think at this point on a directional impact to begin taking certain actions and we've already done so. For example, we purchased some additional catastrophe reinsurance during the quarter in order to more efficiently manage our risk. In particular in June, we purchased $200 million of additional limit for the Northeast US, which is our peak zone; and this was in addition to about a $100 million increase to our North American CAT reinsurance program that we outlined on our April earnings call and in our most recent 10-Q. And although not related to the new model, during the second quarter, we also purchased $100 million of additional limit to cover certain non-US catastrophes.
  At this point, that's about as far as I could go in terms of where we stand; and now, I will turn it over to Dino to comment on the homeowners side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. I think the way to look at it, as I indicated earlier, it's where we start from on a profitability basis. We had an ex-CAT combined ratio on homeowners as I indicated at 75.2%, which is an excellent number. So, we are not in a position with homeowners where rate is needed to fix the profitability issue.
  Nonetheless, we will take rate where it is warranted, which is reflected in the fact that in the second quarter, about 0.5 point of our homeowners net written premium in the US was attributable to rate, and I would say this impact should increase as we move forward based on our regular state-by-state reviews. Now of course, any plans we have are subject to regulatory approval so we're not really in a position to give you an exact number, but I can say that homeowners rate movement should be increasingly positive through 2011. Something else to keep in mind is that in the premiums that we charge on homeowners, it also includes an inflation guard projection for replacement cost increases; and over the last 3 quarters, we've experienced a homeowners premium change associated with this exposure protection of about 2.5 points.
  Incidentally, some of the other carriers include this factor in their renewal change that they quote. Homeowners outside the US really varies by geography. In Canada and the UK we're trending similar to the US. In Australia, we are increasing our homeowner rates much more aggressively in response to the elevated catastrophe activity.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Heimermann,  JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Is it fair, then, to kind of -- based on what both you and Ricky said then to kind of think about the rate you are taking -- what rate you're taking is more in response to what you need relative to perceived exposure or changes in the CAT models? And -- but there is not kind of -- I guess your comments are kind of saying, you're not gratuitously just going to follow the market up even if you could maybe get a little bit more, you're just going to get what you need?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think, Jay, I think that the issue is that -- we're pretty profitable now on an ex-CAT basis as Dino cited; but, however, CATS count. And we've had 10 and 11 points of CATS the last 2 quarters, and we have a new CAT model system that will end up requiring additional capital that we'll either have to accept or reinsure at a cost. So, we absolutely have to take some rate especially in CAT prone areas.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Heimermann,  JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks that was like a 2-for-1 so I will go ahead and cede the floor. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Matt.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi of Goldman Sachs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much. Just a couple here. So, is pricing outpacing loss trend? I mean, can you -- within commercial lines and specialty lines in particular, are you seeing that on a dollars written basis?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is John. No. I mean, first of all, the most recent pricing was 2 points in the quarter, so I don't think you can say that that's outstripping loss trend.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But, this year, our earned premium book is still more like flat so it's certainly not outstripping loss trend now. That's expected loss trend, the truth has been, of course, that loss trends haven't come in line with expectation, they've been more benign than that over the last few years. If you look back at standard commercial, though, we've probably had about a 2-point margin compression over a 2 year period, which is pretty good considering rates were flat, too, to negative.
  In specialty, you're talking about we've had negative rates for a while; but the actual results in any 1 quarter in specialty, professional liability specifically, is really driven much more by the existence or absence of systematic events -- systemic events rather than the long-term trend line. So, you really can't -- the margin compression thing there isn't as relevant; but we are not getting rate that's going to cover a long-term trend line cost for sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thank you. And then just one question I had maybe for Dino, you had mentioned on personal lines; and I was just surprised that folks are taking rate higher -- you are maybe being more selective and not having to compensate for issues in other parts of your book. But it seems like there are a lot of people moving into that space. And so I was a little, just curious, are you not seeing more competition, or is it just that the competition is more reacting to issues they are having elsewhere?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Clearly, there is more competition in this business and how they are pricing, I guess, is a function of what their underlying profitability is; and again, I can comment on it in terms of what our profitability has been. And we do our regular rate reviews, and we are comfortable as we are seeing it, as John indicated. Clearly this is going to continue to be positive going forward for the rest of 2011 and into 2012.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, you are not seeing people specifically come in and undercut more of the activity as to raise pricing?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We see people come into our space and obviously offer -- the only way they can get the business is offer much lower rates, of course, or offer CAT exposure that we wouldn't take.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's a fact. But as I've said before, a couple of the major competitors with us in the years gone by aren't as strong, so it always seems very competitive in every industry, whether it is more or less, it is hard to say. We've got some new ones, we've got some old ones gone. So it's a mix and match.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Okay, thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft, Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wanted to follow-up on the pricing commentary and how it goes into the margin line? What is the lag, if you are able to actually continue do what it seems you guys are doing, should we begin to expect the year ex-CAT margins to be increasing at this point next year, or could it be even sooner?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At 2% on commercial only, let's say personals probably flat. Specialty, certainly isn't positive and again it's dependent more on what's occurring out there, 2% on commercial only in rate is certainly not going to drive an improvement in margins. Hopefully, when we talk next time it will be a little bit more than 2%. 2% to 4% would probably get us even with loss costs when you consider that the 2% to 4% of rates on the whole premium where the lost cost number is on 60% of that. So no, I would think that it depends where loss cost trends whether they develop as they projected; again, they haven't, they've been more benign in recent years but certainly at 2% you're not going to increase margins.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, but just to be clear, you are pushing -- you're going to be pushing more than that too; and therefore, if you do that and loss trends don't change, we will see some margin into next year? That's the way it should come through the income statement from an earned perspective, or am I --?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So let's say we got that 3% of 4% in the fourth quarter. You can only see that over a period of time, of course. You're going to see next year the stuff we've written already and the stuff we write next year. So it will be a lag basis. I mean, for example, we are 2% in this quarter on a written basis, but we are probably flat on an earned premium basis. So, there is a lag there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, okay, good. And then again, Ricky, coming back to the net investment income line. You guys have actually done a nice job in an incredibly low interest rate world. In fact, you're taking your guidance up versus 6 months ago and I don't think the interest rate environment has gotten better. So, I'm just curious what are you guys buying that's allowing you to kind of hang in there better than perhaps we might think given the duration of your book?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, you know what's in our portfolio. You can see it in all of our financial statements, and our portfolio really hasn't changed; and we are getting a bit of a benefit, as I said, from currency. Some of the cash flows you get from some of our investments, whether they be limited partnerships or others in terms of dividend income, it is kind of hard sometimes to predict that. But we are really not doing anything different than what we've been doing over the last number of years.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay, good. And then last on cash is just -- is this sort of a new normal in terms of you've got 7.5 points coming through this year, 3.5 was the guidance at the beginning of year, which I assume that looks more in line with the historical averages. Should we be thinking in '12 that the averages are going up given what we've seen the last -- not just this year but last year and even the last 3, 4, 5 years? It just seems like the average CATS as a percentage of premiums is migrating higher. Any thoughts there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm sure hoping that's not the new normal. If it is, I am retiring early, I'll tell you. Yes, the statistics are pretty interesting on it. Paul, why don't you talk a little bit about CAT experience?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, John. Let me just back it up here a little bit. The background, our average CAT impact per annum since 1983 is about 3%. And the average since 1986 is about 3.5%. Obviously, there is a huge variation by quarter, a little less variation by year; but as underwriters, we tend to think about CAT loads over a longer period of time.
  For example, I can recall a number of years where we experienced very benign CATS and nobody ever around here suggested at least that we lower our loads because of that. That said, we believe that the recent high level of catastrophe activity and the changing catastrophe risk models will place pressure on property underwriters throughout the industry to integrate these into their capital cost, and hopefully, adjust their rates accordingly, because we certainly will be taking a hard look at that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me give you an example of volatility. Katrina obviously was a big year, and then in 2006, we only had 1.4 points of CAT losses; 2007, another 3 points; 2008 was a bad year at 5.2 points; but we came back in 2009 with less than 1 point. So, it's all over the place; I would say the last 18 months have not been good. But interestingly enough in the last 18 months, we haven't had any -- or last four since Katrina, we haven't really had any bad hurricane experiences. A little bit one year, but hurricanes have been relatively benign, so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, okay. No, I mean, I've largely gone with 3.5% in the forward model for '12, etc; and I'm just wondering if it begins to bump higher from a guidance perspective into '12 and beyond. But it sounds like you guys -- it's not different based on what you're saying, it's just a period of bad luck and we will see what the future brings. So, okay. That's helpful. Thanks, guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And Greg, it's Ricky. Just a quick follow-up on the investment income question, I just want to make something clear. For the first half of the year, our investment income was up 1%. It was actually flat when you take into account currency. So if you look at what we are actually projecting out for the second half of the year with the 1 point of currency, we are actually projecting a decline in investment income over the second half of the year to get us to the flat. So I just want to clear on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greg Locraft,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's helpful, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen, Bank of America Merrill Lynch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Just one question. When you were talking about CCI segment, you referred to some lines of business where you've had adverse loss experience and you were looking for higher prices there. Can you talk about what those lines were? And I guess as a follow on, maybe it is two questions, if you could talk in general on the commercial side, the latest information on claims trends?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Jay, this is Paul. I'll take the first piece and then pass it over to Dino to talk a little bit about claims. Just to be clear, in my prepared remarks I was talking about general liability and certain segments of our general liability that are having some adverse loss trends, and we are pushing rate very aggressively there. What we are talking about here is really thinking -- I encourage you to think about say, 4 digit SIC codes in a state and we are saying, boy we think that the rates there are down too much, and our experience has been adverse and we are pushing it. So this is really a lasered approach that I was talking about. I'm not talking about an overall product line, I'm talking about segments of a specific product line and that is general liability.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. And then in general, what are you seeing from a claim standpoint? In comp, if you can zero in on that one too?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay so, let's start with frequency. As far as the frequency is concerned, our claim counts -- obviously the statistics vary by line of business. Overall, US new arise counts, including catastrophes decreased about 17% against the prior year quarter and they are down 10% in the first half over the prior year first half. New arise counts, excluding catastrophes were up 7% against the prior year quarter and they are up 6% for the first half of 2011 versus the first half of 2010.
  The most significant factor driving this account increase was the effect of the non-CAT winter storms in the mid-Atlantic and Northeast. Excluding catastrophes and these storms, property new arise counts were actually down 2% and overall accounts were up 3% for the first half of 2011. On severity, the trends obviously again here vary significantly by line of business due to the very different cost drivers, whether it's the building material costs or the labor rates for property and medical inflation. But overall, we aren't seeing any evidence of any quickening pace of claims inflation. We're seeing claim cost severity increases that are generally consistent with our trend assumptions.
  Focusing, you asked, I believe, on Work Comp. Our period to period claims statistics are not as stable as the industry stats just because we have less than 2% of the market share. This quarter, we're comp new arise claims accounts were actually up 2%, which is partly due to the increased volume of business we're writing. This was driven, though, by an increase in medical-only claims, which are significantly less expensive than claims where the employee misses time from work. These loss time claims actually saw a slight decrease this quarter 1%.
  Overall, we are seeing claim costs severity increases that are generally consistent, as I said, what our trend assumption -- some are up and some are down in certain areas. One place where we are seeing somewhat higher pace of cost dislocation emerges in California for Work Comp. The benefit reforms in California clearly reduced cost significantly but there are some signs that some costs are creeping back into the system, and causing the rate of increase there to steepen again. Just one point of clarification, Jay, to go back on the -- I had indicated that the increase was driven by the medical-only claims, which is the case, the lost time claims just saw a slight increase of 1%. I may have said a decrease, and I meant a 1% increase.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, just to clarify something. So the initial statement was frequency for a new arising claims or -- a number of new arising claims in the US was down 17%, that was, I'm sorry with catastrophes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that was including catastrophes decreased 17%. Excluding catastrophes it was up 7% against the prior year quarter and up 6% for the first half. And as indicated, the most significant factor that was driving that was the effect of the non-CAT winter storms in the mid-Atlantic and the Northeast that we saw, particularly in the first quarter; and if you exclude even that, the property new arise counts were down 2%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Thank you very much. That was thorough.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle, RBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, a couple of questions. It seems like for several quarters now, you've been talking about the -- in CPI that the non-US has been growing faster than the US. What proportion of that overall book -- of overall CPI premium is now non-US premium?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 About 30% or something.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A little bit less I think it's 20 -- probably about 26%, 27%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just by way of reference, how would that compare to say 3 years ago? I mean, just in general terms obviously?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Probably up 3, 4, 5 points. But again, a lot depends on the currency at any point in time too. So if it gets pulled around, you'd really have to do a thorough analysis of it. You'd have to look at it ex-currency too and then adjust and see how much you want to weigh in currency, but it's up. It's significantly up for the Company in total.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Is the business mix within the non-US comparable to the overall book, which is to say sort of 60% homeowners, 20% to the other 2 lines?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, in personal lines the mix is essentially the same in Canada, the UK, in Australia. The mix is a little bit different in Latin America, in particular in Brazil. Where there we lead with our auto, there's just less demand for homeowners, but the auto business that we have in Brazil is also related to high net worth clientele. So the mix in general is the same essentially everywhere with the exception of Brazil, where we have a much higher proportion of automobile.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you for that. And then one other question, is just we've heard a lot of the brokers talk about the differences, different level of late stickiness between kind of large and middle market and small; and I was wondering if you could comment on that with respect to what you are seeing in your book?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, Mark, I don't know if I have a whole lot more to add to that conversation. I think the general consensus in the industry is that the larger the account, the more competitive it is right now. We are not real big player when it comes to the term risk management business out there. If we write any of it, it's very selectively done in niches that we really understand. So, but that said, we do see a premium attract a little bit more competition. We are also not a BOP writer, so I can't comment too much about the small, small stuff; but what we see in the middle market is the higher up you go in premium, the more it attracts people to try to compete on it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mark Dwelle,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker, Deutsche Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Good afternoon, everyone. I was wondering if you elaborate on the inflation guard protection you were speaking about in terms of, I guess, that's part of the masterpiece policy? And how as a component you're getting rates through on that? I just don't really understand how that plays in.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, as part of our replacement cost provision on our policy, --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is the masterpiece policy we're talking about, yes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Correct. On our homeowners we put through an inflation guard. That number has changed over time, it used to be higher, obviously, and in the last few years it has come down. And we -- and now it is roughly at about 2%, 2.5% percent as I indicated, and that is just a factor of we look at what material costs are, what labor costs are; and based on that, we put an automatic increase on to the homeowners policy.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And so, if I am a policyholder and I've been with you for a long time, that guarantees that the replacement cost will have at minimum risen -- I'm just trying to find what does it say in the policy how that plate comes in?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, we have a provision on our policy that we provide replacement cost based on reconstructing the home; and what we do is we insure the value, we inspect the home, we insure it to value; and then, every year, we add on an inflation guard based on, as I say, material costs, labor costs. So that if the limit on the homeowners' policy continue to move up in line with inflation, based on as I said, our first insurance to value inspection that we do when we first insure the home.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then the premium impact of that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And the premium impact it's roughly about 2 points. Actually in the second quarter, a little bit less impact. The little bit under 2 points, the effect on premium.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Shanker,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay Misquith, Evercore Partners.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay Misquith,  Evercore Partners - Analyst   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, good evening. Two questions, the first is on pricing. I just wondered -- it seems that it is a tale of two cities out there with the CAT exposed property lines getting rate increases as the more casualty focussed and the professional liability lines, softer. Can you tell us what the environment out there is? How clients are reacting to rate increases despite not seeing loss cost strains on some of the casualty lines?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Obviously, as I mentioned in my prepared remarks, the property is an easier sale right now on our book of business. But we are taking rate and general liability and as expressed earlier on the call, certainly we are getting more sizable rate increases in those segments that have had adverse experiences. So, we are out there pushing it and articulating it and our underwriters are explaining loss cost trend and the soft market in all of our value proposition. When you come back to workers compensation, there we are getting a couple of points of rate, we are getting payroll increases. So we are getting true exposure growth there of a couple of points, and on the premium audit side, we are getting a couple points as well. So, we are taking that and moving on.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay Misquith,  Evercore Partners - Analyst   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, do you think that rates are low enough right now that -- that carriers will have to take pricing up just a tad just in order to meet loss cost inflation versus the past where they were more willing to let pricing slide a little bit more?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay, When you think about casualty lines, at least around here, we recognize very much that loss cost trends are always out there. We just don't believe that they are negative, so they're certainly above 0%. I think John tried to give you a sense that on our overall book of commercial business, we are running at 2%, loss cost trends overall might be around the 3% to 4% range, it depends on the mix. But clearly, we are out there pushing and we want to ultimately see margin expansion, not margin compression.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay Misquith,  Evercore Partners - Analyst   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, fair enough. The second question is on growth outside the US. I believe it was in personal auto, could you add some color to that as in which countries are you growing in and how you are getting that business? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dino Robusto,  Chubb Corporation - EVP, CAO   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. The personal auto combination in Brazil and also Canada and some of the UK; but keep in mind that the base is a lot smaller also, so the percentage increase is much higher than in the US. As indicated, we only have about 25% of our personal lines business is outside the US.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vinay Misquith,  Evercore Partners - Analyst   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fair enough. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ian Gutterman of Adage Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ian Gutterman,  Adage Capital Management - Analyst   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi. I have two hopefully quick ones. First, I was just looking at the expense ratio was up about half a point for the quarter and for the first half. And your premiums are actually growing again, so I'm wondering why there's pressure on the expense ratio?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, you are right, we're up about 0.4 points from the second quarter of 2010; and that reflects the impact of some higher commission rates and changes in our product mix particularly outside the United States. The 31.3 expense ratio in the second quarter and the 31.5 for the first 6 months of 2011 are up only slightly over the 31.2% expense ratio. When you look at -- we you look at it, our commissions are up some, but commissions go to mix, personal lines have higher commissions than commercial lines and personal lines were negative for a while and growth that was positive.
  Overseas, you generally attract higher commissions than US. And our overseas business has been growing. And then some of our businesses such as where we are growing, accident and health is a line where commission rates are significantly higher than it might be in traditional property and casualty. So, Ian, I don't really see -- it's just a very slight movement mostly related to commissions, which are related to product mix and geographic mix. I'd say overall our control, what we call controllable expenses the non-commission stuff is flat and probably down on a percentage basis even if written premium is up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ian Gutterman,  Adage Capital Management - Analyst   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good. That's what I was most concerned about. Then my other one is a similar type number's question, if I look at the casualty segment within CCI, again for the quarter and for the half, it is sub 84 combined, which as best as I can tell is a record; and by a good margin a record. And I am kind of wondering why that is happening at this point in the cycle, is the development much more favorable there this year than last, is there a mix well, or are you really picking the axe in here a lot lower than in the past?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Krump,  Chubb Corporation - EVP   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is Paul. The casualty line benefited from significant, favorable development again in the second quarter. The majority of that came from the excess portion of the book, which continues to see lower loss activity than we expected; and broadly speaking, that was across almost all the accident years.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Development being really the answer, not the accident year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ian Gutterman,  Adage Capital Management - Analyst   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Is the accident year up year over year, flat, been improving? I'm just trying to get directionally a sense of what the accident looks like in that line?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's about flat.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ian Gutterman,  Adage Capital Management - Analyst   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and the development, I guess you said the line should answer that part. Okay, that's all I had. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeffrey Cho, MFS.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeffrey Cho,  MFS Investment Management - Analyst   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, good evening. Can you give me an update on your priorities for excess capital? Have you considered any M&amp;A, if you have any comments on any type of the businesses that you're interested in, would you ever get back into reinsurance or any other type of insurance? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, reinsurance, we made a strategic decision to get out of it. Not because whether or not it was a good or bad business but basically, after Katrina you had -- it was the property market that was the attractive reinsurance market, not the casualty market; and we just couldn't take the aggregate exposure we'd have piling on reinsurance exposure on top of our primary insurance exposure. Secondly, we are not an active player or an active looker in the M&amp;A area. So I think you can feel comfortable that we will be more focused on returning excess capital to the shareholders than use it in M&amp;A transactions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeffrey Cho,  MFS Investment Management - Analyst   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it, thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi, Goldman Sachs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Just a quick one here, on following up on RMS in your capital position, is anything you're doing maybe -- are you thinking about holding on to more capital with changes in models? Or is reinsurance kind of the solution you're mostly looking at? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I think we are looking at a number of solutions. Reinsurance being one, underwriting actions, which I mentioned in my earlier comments as well. And just to be clear, we use more than one CAT model, so this isn't all solely driven by the RMS model.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Do we need to hold more capital because of the RMS model? We are in a what we believe to be a significant excess capital position based on our own internal models as well as the external rating agency models. So we are fine with our capital position. It's a question of how much exposure and risk we are willing to take given what the models are telling us. So, we are being prudent and we are approaching it from that perspective.
  We've already taking, as I mentioned, some action. We're probably going to be taking to more on the underwriting side as we learn more and we get our arms around all this; but from a capital perspective, we feel very -- we feel good about where we are from a capital perspective. We certainly don't think this is where we're heading. We certainly don't think this impacts our share buy-back plans for this year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And just -- I'm just trying to understand if like if the 0.8 is kind of the new normal for you? And if you feel like RMS is kind of makes -- or any model change or any risk perception change makes that the case?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You say 0.8, you're talking about a premium of surplus ratios?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, 0.8 insure. Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ricky Spiro,  Chubb Corporation - CFO, EVP   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I don't think I would attribute the impact of RMS to a change in the view of where we think the appropriate level is.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Nannizzi,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [107]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen, Bank of America Merrill Lynch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [108]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. I was looking at the accident year loss ratio in the specialty business, and I guess it's probably the best I've seen in years. And I understand that several years ago, of course, you had the credit crisis claims and those were probably overstated; but even versus just the last 5 quarters, it looks like it's at least a point better than what we are seeing despite price decreases. And I'm wondering -- I know surety plays a role in that too, but I'm wondering what else is going on there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [109]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're right, surety does play somewhat of a role in that I think this quarter on a loss ratio basis was about the same as last quarter in the accident year; but we have some seasonality to expenses, so I think expenses were a little bit higher in the first quarter. To some degree, Jay, you kind of suggested that the lack of CAT events and the credit crisis was sort of one almost implying it was a minor factor. The credit crisis, that was a lot of money put up for a credit crisis in the accident years 2008 and 2009. So not having that kind of event -- that systematic events in our accident year picks are much lower provision for systematic events has a significant impact.
  And, plus, all of the years as we've gone on, remember each accident year we re-up the assessment, but we re-up the assessment based upon what's happened in past accident years as we roll forward trends; and all of the past accident years have continued to improve, so we're coming off a lower base. So, overall, I think the second quarter is in line with the first quarter; and the good news is that the systematic events don't seem as prevalent in the system.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jay Cohen,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [110]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's great. Thanks a lot.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [111]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Two more questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [112]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Actually, gentlemen, at this time there no further questions. I'll turn the call back to you for any additional or closing remarks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Finnegan,  Chubb Corporation - Chairman, CEO   [113]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for joining us tonight. Have a good evening.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [114]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Once again, ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude today's conference we would like to thank you all for your participation. Have a great day.
 
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2011 Chubb Corp Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>WARREN</city>
  <companyName>Chubb Corp</companyName>
  <companyTicker>CB^A16</companyTicker>
  <startDate>21-Jul-11 9:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>64902</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL />
  <ISIN />
</Event>