<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="5599772" lastUpdate="Thursday, February 5, 2015 at 3:14:27am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="5599772.F" expirationDate="Wednesday, February 4, 2015 at 10:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of DOW.AX earnings conference call or presentation 4-Feb-15 10:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Interim 2015 Downer EDI Ltd Earnings Presentation

North Ryde, New South Wales Feb 5, 2015 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Downer EDI Ltd earnings conference call or presentation Wednesday, February 4, 2015 at 10:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Grant Fenn
      Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO
   *  Kevin Fletcher
      Downer EDI Limited - CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Andrew Hodge
      CIMB - Analyst
   *  Craig Wong-Pan
      Deutsche Bank - Analyst
   *  Ben Brownette
      CBA - Analyst
   *  Brent Walsh
      B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt
   *  John Purtell
      Macquarie Group - Analyst
   *  Nathan Reilly
      Goldman Sachs - Analyst
   *  Richard Johnson
      Citigroup Inc - Analyst
   *  Sam Theodore
      UBS - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, ladies and gentlemen and thank you for joining us for the presentation of the Downer EDI Limited results for the six months to December 31.
 My name is Grant Fenn and I'm the Downer Group CEO.
 The order of events this morning will be that I'll take you through an overview of the results at the Group and divisional level and then Kevin Fletcher, our Group CFO, he'll cover the financial position of the Company in more detail. I'll then come back to present our work-in-hand and the outlook for the full 2015 Financial Year. We'll take questions at the end of the presentation.
 So let's move on to the overview. Look, in summary, I'm very pleased with how the Group has responded to the current difficult market. We're forging stronger relationships with our customers in each of our businesses and that's very clear to me. Our capabilities and strategic options continue to improve and we're bidding and winning a good proportion of the available work.
 With our commitment to our customers and our strong reputation for delivery, our brand is continuing to gain strength. Now, our aim is to navigate this period to become the market leaders across all of our business streams. Now that doesn't mean we can defy gravity and completely avoid the current downturn in the sector.
 As you can see from our results, Downer reported net profit after tax of AUD94.7 million, which is 4.4% lower than this time last year.
 Operating cash flow remains a huge focus for the business and again, we have had a very strong result at AUD257.9 million, with cash conversion at 103.5% of EBITDA.
 The consistent delivery of high cash to profit conversions should give investors comfort on the quality of Downer's earnings. I believe this is a point of difference to most of our peers.
 Our work-in-hand at the end of December was AUD18 billion. Now it did get a shot in the arm yesterday when we announced a AUD1 billion asset management contract with Pacific National, which hasn't been included in that number.
 Net debt was AUD252.7 million at the half. That's after the AUD300 million acquisition of Tenix and Downer's gearing is 11.2% at that time. If we were to include off-balance sheet obligations our gearing would be 17.4%.
 The Board has decided to declare a fully franked interim dividend of AUD0.12 per share, payable on March 19 to shareholders on the register at February 19.
 As you will recall, the Company announced a share buy-back program on August 5, 2014 and we've bought back and cancelled 2.7 million shares under that program. I should just recall to you that the Dividend Reinvestment Plan remains suspended and will not operate for this dividend.
 Our Lost Time Injury Frequency Rate of 0.93 is below one incident per million hours worked and our Total Recordable Injury Frequency Rate is 4.17. The number of recordable injuries is down 27% for the same period last year. Now this is a very pleasing performance. We are doing a lot of work on identifying and managing our critical risks and hopefully this will continue to drive a downward trend in injuries and in particular, the severity of the injuries.
 I'll now move on to each of our divisions.
 On the surface, the Infrastructure result appears poor, with revenue up 1.1% to just over AUD2.3 billion, while EBIT was 16.7% lower at AUD72.8 million. But as you dig into it, 85% of the earnings reduction relates to the losses incurred in our minerals based consultancies, QCC, MT and Snowden. Now they're still losses for the Group but, importantly, the base contracting businesses have managed to limit their EBIT reduction to around 2% and in the current environment, this is a very, very credible result.
 A number of Infrastructure's markets do remain very challenging, with a severely reduced mining related capital investment program from most of the miners. The tendering environment is very competitive, with fewer opportunities and pressure is on bid margins.
 New Zealand has also experienced a tightening of margins and a reduction in volume on the UFB project.
 But it's not all bad news. We continue to win work across all of our businesses. We are amping up on major gas projects, as we speak. The roads business in Australia and New Zealand continues to win new work and improve market share. I believe there will be significant opportunity in telecommunications and further government outsourcing.
 Now we're continuing to reduce costs in the Infrastructure business. There were restructuring costs of around AUD4.8 million during the period.
 Let's move to Mining. Australia's mining services industry remains under intense pressure due to the impact of low commodity prices on our customer base. Revenue for Downer Mining was down 20.4%, due to the Daunia contract coming to an end, the early termination of the Goonyella contract and reduced volumes at other sites.
 There were also fewer opportunities for the blasting business and lower sales of ammonium nitrate.
 Cost reduction remains a key priority and Downer Mining's EBIT margin remains strong due to a number of initiatives to improve productivity.
 Our Mining division is held in high regard by our customers because we work very hard at improving their business. Despite the reduction in revenue, this business continues to provide good returns to the Group and we will continue to invest as opportunities arise.
 Those predicting the end of contract mining as an industry will be proven wrong. We are more efficient and provide great flexibility to our customers. The tougher the commodity markets, ultimately, the better it will be for contract mining.
 In December 2014 Downer received two Letters of Award from Adani Mining, valued at over AUD2.0 billion, for mining services and construction of infrastructure at the Carmichael Coal Mine in Queensland. Now, both Letters of Award are subject to the parties executing binding contracts. As it stands today, mine infrastructure construction is scheduled to commence in the fourth quarter of 2015, with the first mining scheduled for the second quarter of 2016.
 Now to Rail. As you can see from the results, the Rail division has begun to climb out of its depths. Whilst Rail revenue was down 28% to AUD424 million, due primarily to the completion of the Waratah manufacturing contract, EBIT improved to AUD17.5 million from AUD4.6 million.
 The Waratah Through Life Support contract is performing strongly, with many of the learnings from the project helping to improve performance on other passenger and locomotive maintenance contracts, including the Millennium contract in Sydney.
 We are bidding on a number of projects, including the refurbishment of the Tangara fleet, new rolling stock for the New South Wales intercity fleet and the local content for Rotem, as they pursue new rolling stock opportunities in Victoria.
 Keolis Downer began operating the Gold Coast Light Rail in July 2014 and Yarra Trams continues to perform well.
 Keolis Downer is pursuing a number of other public transport opportunities in Australia and New Zealand. This will be a significant growth area for the Group.
 The 10 year, AUD1 billion management contract with Pacific National, announced yesterday, demonstrates how far we have come in transitioning in this business to align with our customer's needs. This is a huge milestone for the Rail business. It's a new contract form, a new level of service delivery and integration and a real advantage for our customers.
 In October 2014, Downer acquired Tenix Holdings Australia for AUD300 million on a cash and debt free basis. The Tenix business is now branded DownerTenix.
 DownerTenix is a leading provider of operations and maintenance services to owners of electricity, gas, water, wastewater and industrial resource assets in Australia and New Zealand. The integration of the business is proceeding well.
 Now I've recently taken the opportunity to refresh the business by making a number of changes to the divisional and group structures. These changes will take out a management layer, or two in some cases, and also increase our customer focus. We intend to further invest in capability, whilst at the same time ensuring we are as efficient as possible.
 The Downer Group now consists of five Divisions: Infrastructure Services, which includes the Australian road and rail infrastructure, telecommunications and power businesses and DownerTenix; Engineering, Construction and Maintenance, which includes the Australian electrical and instrumentation, and structural, mechanical and piping businesses; New Zealand; Mining; and Rail.
 The restructure also involves the establishment of a new Strategy, Growth and Innovation function at Group Head Office.
 Downer will report its results for the 2015 financial year though under the existing divisions of Infrastructure, Mining and Rail. Kevin will have more to say on this in a few moments and I'll hand over to him now to discuss in more detail the group financials. Thanks, Kevin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Grant, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Once again let's go straight into the results. Total revenue, as you can see, has declined by AUD345 million or 8.8% to AUD3.6 billion, with the major movements, as Grant has outlined, coming from Mining, which was down AUD210 million due to the completion or early termination of contracts on the East Coast and Rail which was down AUD165 million, largely reflecting the completion of the Waratah Train build phase in May last year.
 Revenue in Infrastructure was broadly in line with the comparative first half at AUD2.3 billion, although this did include two months of trading following the acquisition of Tenix on 31 October. Overall, the revenue environment within Infrastructure has been challenging, with our resource related consultancies particularly hard hit, lower work in our transmission and renewables businesses and lower volumes coming through in New Zealand on the UFB rollout.
 Revenue within the Telecommunications business in Australia was up, with more volumes coming through from the NBN, albeit not at the levels we would like. Similarly, we saw increases in our Transport business following the successful tenders by our DownerMouchel joint venture to manage and maintain roads in Sydney's West under a seven year stewardship management contract and to maintain Intelligent Transport System assets in Sydney's West and regional New South Wales, both on behalf of New South Wales Road and Maritime Services.
 Group EBITDA and EBIT decreased by 11.4% and 11.5% respectively, reflecting in part the compression of margins we are seeing in a highly competitive bidding market, but also due to the performance of our resource related consultancies, which lost just under AUD13 million in the half on revenue of AUD38 million, compared to a break-even result last year on revenue of AUD103 million.
 Significant costs have been removed from these businesses to a point of maintaining key capability and expertise and flexibility to respond to an upturn in market conditions when they return. Adjusting for these businesses, group EBIT would still be down, albeit at 3%, but EBIT margin would improve from an adjusted 4.2% to 4.4%.
 Again, our performance shows that our business leaders have taken active steps to adjust the cost base in line with market conditions and have minimised to the overall Group EBIT margin reduction by 12 basis points. Reflecting our focus on cash and work (technical difficulty) net interest expense has fallen by just under 42% to AUD13.8 million, which included approximately AUD1.8 million repairable to the Tenix acquisition.
 Our tax expense of AUD33 million equates to an effective tax rate of 26%, which is below the Australian statutory rate of 30% due to non-assessable research and development incentives and non-taxable distributions from joint ventures. This all adds up to NPAT of AUD94.7 million, which as Grant has said, is down 4.4% on the corresponding half year. Not shown on this slide, but in note 5 of our financial report, we report basic earnings per share of AUD0.208, which is down broadly in line with the NPAT at 4.6%. However, after adjustment of AUD5.2 million in acquisition costs related to the purchase of Tenix, the underlying EPS was AUD0.221, up a modest 1.4% on the comparative half.
 Return on funds employed declined by 16 basis points to 15%, in part due to the full impact of the debt for the acquisition of Tenix, but with only two months of earnings. Pleasingly, the Directors declared an interim dividend of AUD0.12 per share fully franked. This dividend equates to a net dividend yield of 5.1% based on the closing share price on December 31 of AUD4.72 and a payout ratio of 54.8%.
 For summary of earnings, we continue to include this slide to show favourable and unfavourable items that have impacted our results, but also to answer questions that typically arise from a discussion on our results. Redundancy costs of AUD11.6 million were incurred across the Group as the businesses adjusted to current market conditions. In the case of Rail, as it continued its transformation to a 24/7 Rail Asset Manager.
 We anticipate there will be further redundancies in the second half, as the businesses continue to right size and strive for improvement and efficiency and as a consequence of the broader Group restructure. As discussed earlier, acquisition costs related to the purchase of Tenix were AUD5.2 million and AUD1.6 million amortisation of customer related intangibles was expensed in the period.
 We continue to close out residual working capital matters related to the Waratah build phase and recognised AUD4 million in manufacturing delay account interest in Rail in the period, after a detailed reconciliation of that account. I'll talk more about working capital runoff for the Waratah Project shortly.
 Finally, AUD11.5 million of provisions against customer contracts taken up in earlier years was released in the period, as we continue to clean up contract portfolio and minimise our exposure to unapproved variations and claims. Adjusted corporate costs are shown at AUD15 million, although is after recognising AUD10 million in research and development incentive in the period. I did say at the full year that we would be recognising R&amp;D incentive in the divisions going forward, which is the case.
 This amount, the AUD10 million I just referred to, relates to a true-up of 2014 claims following the submission of our 2014 income tax return in November. We are still projecting underlying corporate costs to be in the mid AUD60 millions for the year. Operating cash flow. Now, this continues to be a standout for Downer at just under AUD258 million. Adjusting for interest and tax paid, less the net working capital recovery from the Waratah build phase, cash conversion came in at 103.5%.
 Now, this is actually stronger than we anticipated and includes advanced payments on a number of locomotive deliveries in the period of around about AUD30 million. Adjusting for this, as we actually have to pay for these locos in the second half, our cash conversion was around 92%. In the balance sheet commentary within our financial report on page 9, you will note our debtor days have improved marginally from 28.6 to 26.4 days and the majority of our suppliers continue to be paid on time, with creditor days marginally lower at 30.2 days. I will let these statistics speak for themselves.
 In relation to working capital unwind from the Waratah build phase, in addition to the AUD18.9 million recovered in the half, we have roughly AUD50 million to come, with AUD18 million scheduled for the second half and a similar amount in fiscal 2016, with the balance due in 2018 assuming Reliance Rail can refinance in the normal course.
 The AUD50 million is a mixed bag of final completion payments, MDA interest, which is effectively the amount that's recoverable in 2018, payment for a spare trailer driver car, when this is delivered next year, less supply payments and related costs. If I turn to our total cash flow statement, this is pretty self-explanatory, with net capital expenditure of AUD79 million, with minimal new project investment in mining in the period, and AUD309 million referable to the acquisition of Tenix.
 Other investing cash flow of AUD16.5 million includes AUD9.3 million, which includes the acquisition of a small business VEC, which is a civil and engineering services company with capability in Rail and Water Infrastructure and Bridge Design and Construction that complements our Road Services Business. Excluding acquisitions, we project full year net capital expenditure to be around AUD200 million. Financing cash flow totalled AUD55.7 million.
 This included the Tenix bridge loan of AUD300 million, less the AUD11.7 million for the share buy-back, AUD57.5 million in ordinary and roads dividend payments and AUD114 million in facility repayments. The principal component within facility repayments was the repayment of two USPP facilities that matured in the period at around AUD100 million. Under the buy-back, we bought back 2.7 million shares, reducing issued shares outstanding to 432.7 million.
 Cash held at December 31 was AUD378 million, which when combined with undrawn facilities of AUD612 million left us with liquidity of just under AUD1 billion. Turning to the balance sheet, shareholders' equity has increased to just under AUD2 billion and net debt was AUD253 million, which translate to on balance sheet gearing of 11.2%, which is well on the way to the 10% by June 30 we guided the market to when we announced Tenix, assuming no further acquisitions or share buy-back, although we continue to assess opportunities through both these levers to improve shareholder value.
 We also continue to remain well within our credit rating and debt covenant metrics with adjusted net debt over adjusted EBITDAR improving to two times and then interest cover of 9.7 times. Our credit rating remains at BBB, with a stable outlook. Average debt maturity at December 31 is 2.1 years, which is relatively short, although this is highly influenced by the Tenix bridge loan, which is 10 months to maturity. As outlined on the slide, we intend to refinance the bridge loan in the Aussie dollar medium term note and USPP markets, targeting tenors of between seven and 10 years.
 Assuming we are successful in this regard, we expect average debt maturity at June 30 to be somewhere between 3.5 years to four years, which sits nicely within our target range of three to four years. Now, just going further into the restructure. As Grant has outlined, we've undertaken a restructure of our business to better align to our end markets, take advantage of future opportunities and best meet the needs of our customers.
 We will report our full year results for 2015 under the pre-existing structure of Infrastructure, Mining and Rail. However, going forward, while from an operational perspective we will be five divisions, we intend to report our results to the market from fiscal 2016 onwards along service lines, being Transport services, Telecommunication services, Utility services, Engineering, Construction and Maintenance services, Mining services, Rail services and Corporate.
 Geographical segment information will also continue to be provided. We've included a schematic in the appendixes that shows how our operational structure maps to these service lines. We are taking the restructure of our business as the opportunity to change the way we report our results, as investors and analysts have been telling us for a while that they would like more information on the composition of our Infrastructure business, given this is our largest and most diverse division in terms of revenue and service offerings.
 We acknowledge our efforts to put a spotlight on Infrastructure to date have been muted in terms of a pie chart of Infrastructure revenue and an indicative percentage split between services and construction at group level. Having given this significant thought, we have elected to report going forward on the above service lines, as this is the way we effectively think about and service our customers, cognisant of the geographical challenges.
 The new structure provides greater clarity between our construction, production and asset maintenance offerings and aligns more closely with economic and market intelligence produced on these sectors, making it easier for analysts, investors and indeed ourselves to assess our performance in that context. We acknowledge this change will require a not insubstantial amount of work by many people on the call today to migrate their modelling tools to the new format.
 To support the transition, we will provide supplementary financial information in August when we report our full year results, which will include as a minimum revenue, EBITDA and EBIT along these service lines for at least fiscal 2014 and fiscal 2015 and likely fiscal 2013 to support trend analysis. We will obviously listen to feedback on this proposal in the lead up to fiscal 2016 and intend to provide a further update at our investor day in May.
 On that note, I'll hand back to Grant. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Kev. As I said earlier, work-in-hand for the group is down from AUD19.6 billion to AUD18 billion, with this reduction principally due to the fall in Downer Mining's work-in-hand from AUD5.2 billion to AUD3.3 billion. Now, the main reasons for this, early termination of Goonyella contract, the completion of the contract at Daunia and some volume reductions at a couple of other sites.
 Now, the new Pacific National contract worth AUD1 billion over the next 10 years is not included in the AUD18 billion. Nor is the AUD2 billion from the proposed Adani contract.
 Through to the outlook.
 On current trading conditions, we are on track to meet our target NPAT of around AUD210 million for the 2015 financial year. So that's it for the formal part of the presentation and I would now like to invite questions, please.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. (Operator instructions). Your first question comes from Andrew Hodge at CIMB. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, guys. Just a few questions, if I could. The first relates to the -- I guess we'll call it the collective of the consulting business -- have they been restructured sufficiently through the first half to sort of on a current run rate be break even on a second half basis or you think they will still be loss making in the second half?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. They'll still have -- well, unless something picks up on the revenue side, they'll still be loss making in the second half. We're in a position through the last six months that we have taken a lot of costs out there, mate, but they'll still be negative unless revenue picks up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. But would you expect -- are we seeing a slowing in the rate of loss or are you thinking (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. We expect so. Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 All right. And just within -- you mentioned sort of obviously the conditions really relate to very tight tendering condition margins. Have you -- not just with a -- I guess, the contraction of a bid margin, but in general, as risk becomes greater on some of the contractors, have you got any problems within your Infrastructure division that are a result of tenders that were taken over the last 12 months that are tight? So, I guess, does this result include anything that performed more poorly than you expected or will there be something in the second half that will perform more poorly than you expected when you bid?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. I don't think so, mate. Look, we've always got a portfolio of -- we've got a portfolio of jobs just full stop and, of course, not all of those go exactly to plan and some go better than we expected. But our book is relatively clean. I mean, it's very good. I'm not expecting any major issues there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 All right. Great. Then just one last question for me. Just, I guess, the buy-back was probably a little bit lower than I expected in the first half. Is there a reason for that? I guess in conjunction with that, we're starting to see some very small unlisted businesses start to go out of business. Are you seeing more -- I guess, maybe not the size of Tenix type opportunities, but are you starting to see opportunities that you want to take advantage of, given the environment, or do you think you're more likely to go back to a higher rate of purchase on the buy-back in the second half?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. It's a good question. Look, when we announced the buy-back -- a few things have happened since then. The opportunity for purchasing Tenix came up for a start. We also, I think, from our perspective, the market is -- and commodity prices continue to fall, so we have pulled back a bit there.
 But we want to make sure that we're in the best position to take advantage of whatever. If that means that we can't see opportunities for improving our abilities through acquisition, then we'll buy-back. The buy-back is really now a part of how we will manage our capital. But, of course, the position in the market is pretty tough right now, so we're just going to watch and look for a while. I think that's a prudent thing to do.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hodge,  CIMB - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Your next question comes from Craig Wong-Pan from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. I just wanted to follow on from the margin question. There's a lot of commentary talking about tightening of margins. I just wanted to get a feel for is that kind of pressure, has that been reflected in the numbers to date or is that -- so what you're bidding on now, putting aside further cost out, will that result in a further contraction going forward? Or has that been fully been felt at this point in time within the December 2014 numbers?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. It's a bit hard to answer that with any great detail, mate. As you would know, we've got a portfolio of jobs. Some of those were bid and won when there were higher margins and some of them have been bid and won with lower margins. Of course, as the higher margin business rolls off, you've got more lower margin.
 Then, when things ultimately pick up, you're going to have the opposite effect. So we're on that curve right now and, yes, we have got some higher margin jobs which will roll off.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. The next question, just around the settlement of customer contracts, is there many sort of new contracts or ones that are currently being worked through that you need to settle or is most of those discussions already had and so at this point forward there's not really many more contracts to settle?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We've still -- we've always got discussions with customers, but all of them are progressing as we would expect. As you can see from our cash numbers, mate, we don't have too many issues sitting there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. All right. Would you say, I mean given what's happened with commodity prices, has there been any more intense kind of pressure from clients to not pay some of those claims? Like are you getting more of a push back on some of that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think no doubt that as you would expect, the customers are looking very closely at the claims, and often you know where you've been working through an EPCM, the EPCMs under pressure. But all of those are generally being resolved mate in you know -- according to what we think.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, and then my last question, just on the work-in-hand for the Infrastructure Australia business, I mean that reported some good growth. So could you just kind of give some more details on what was the drivers behind that from the June 2014 balance to now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes we'll you've got Tenix coming in there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay that was the main driver?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, there's a slight reduction if you don't have the Tenix numbers in there, which is I guess expected. But you know there's opportunity out there as well, we are ramping up on some gas jobs here. And if some of those are as positive as I think they might be, then those numbers might move.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, your next question comes from Ben Brownette from CBA, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes hi, I was just wondering if we could get the number for what Tenix has contributed to work-in-hand please?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 AUD1.2 [billion].
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and is it possible to get any kind of indication for what the burn on the work-in-hand will be? It's obviously difficult to compare to other companies because you include everything. So is it possible at least with the work-in-hand at some point we could get some sort of idea about what the burn might be you know over the next 12 months, or for the next financial year? That would be good at some point. Also I was just wondering...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben, (multiple speakers) it's a bit hard, because you know as we're burning it we're building it up as well, right? So there's a lot of things dependant, so I'm not sure that we'll give you too much more than we give you on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Is it possible also just what the Tenix contribution was? I know it was only two months, but I think most people probably would have modelled that aside. So just considering those consultancy losses, just trying to actually have a look at Infrastructure from period to period?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes I think it was AUD5million, Kev? About AUD5 million EBIT.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and just for clarification on that contract for yesterday, isn't that the contract you've had for 10 years or something already? So just wondering what's the new part about it, is it a different risk profile or are you doing something different than you were doing before?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes it's a very different contract, and we haven't been running to contract there for quite a long time. Right so we have been running on a short term basis and our customer there has been very keen to make sure that they're getting best in class. They've looked around internationally and domestically and they've looked at what we're going to be doing for them. The contract is far more extensive than what it has been previously. It's much more of a total asset management solution rather than sort of point and shoot maintenance. This is where the industry needs to go in Australia and I'm very very pleased that we're really the first ones to do this. Of course, we're also doing it on the Waratah Train, so there's a lot of learning's that our guys are taking between the two parts of the operations. So I'm very happy with it, as is the customer.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it will be -- for the next work-in-hand you'll see a billion dollar boost that in terms of revenue, is there likely to be a massive change from what you've been earning already from PM?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No not a massive change, no.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, just that comment on corporate costs going, was it going to AUD60 million for the full year and does that exclude any of the other unallocated plusses and minuses?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes AUD60 million, what I was sort of saying for the call is on that slide, it's shown as sort of AUD15 million. But in that AUD15 million is AUD10 million of R&amp;D true-up from fiscal 2014. So I guess you could say the real number was AUD25 million and you know given that we've got some costs coming through in the second half as we go through our restructure. We're actually consolidating all of our shared service centres into two centres, one in New Zealand and one in Australia in the second half. There's a little bit of cost referable to that, so we're sort of saying mid AUD60 million as a guide.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and just lastly the reduction in maintenance CapEx, is that a reflection of lower mining work or have you actually made a more of a cognisant decision to limit what you're actually spending, particularly in your mining business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No it's just the way it's panned out mate, and of course we're going to be tightening everything we spend, so there is pressure from our mining team to make sure that we're not spending money where we don't need to. But there's no real decision there to stop spending on anything, no.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay great thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question comes from Brent Walsh from Merrill Lynch please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes thanks guys. A quick one just following up on the mining consultancy work. I mean if you strip that out as you mentioned before, the underlying earnings to client wouldn't look so significant. I guess my question is, is there a strategic reason, if those businesses are going to continue to be a drag on an earnings, is there a strategic reason you need to be in those businesses? It seems to be a pretty small part of the mix. I mean does it compliment the Mining division as a whole or just thinking from a portfolio perspective?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, no it's a great --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes no it's a great question and it's one that we have spent a lot of time on here. We've made a lot of money out of particularly our coal consultancy joining with our construction side on EPC fronts. We've made a lot of money out of the last number of years. Now of course we need to look forward and see what that's going to be. But in our view, these are very important, it's very important that we have a smart front end. All of the geological consultancy in Snowden QCC on the coal side and MT on mineral sands and other commodities. They give us a smart end it gets us in the front end with our customers, it's important for us to keep them. Now of course as you say we don't want them to be a significant drag on the business. So we're working hard on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay cool. Maybe just a comment on what your customers are saying at the moment, particularly the impact of a weak Aussie dollar. How is that I guess improved their optimism, the economics for particularly the coal producers? Any feedback there that'd be great.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh I don't have too much mate. Obviously they're happy with the Aussie dollar fall, but they've still got tough businesses.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes sure, sure. Just one final one, you made a comment on ammonium nitrate pricing being tight, and volumes down I think. Is that a market thing, do you think you've maintained share there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh no I'm not sure that we've maintained share, but the pricing has come back up as we look out into the futures market, it looks as if it's coming back up. So the pressure may not be there as we roll into the future, but it's certainly been -- the last six months have been quite tough.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You know we're not a producer so it's not as easy for us to deal with those things.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brent Walsh,  B of A Merrill Lynch - Analsyt   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, your next question comes from John Purtell from Macquarie Group, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Morning guys, look first question. Was there much, just on the Infrastructure side, was there much impact from Wheatstone and Gorgon projects in the periods, or are you expecting those to ramp up in the second half. You know that's a key part of full year guidance achievement?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes there's virtually nothing in the first half, they will start to have an impact in the second half, but it's more a 2016 case.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, so they've been slow to start up Grant, is that fair?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh I think you know Wheatstone's just starting, Gorgon we're partway through the ramp up, but we've still got a long way to go. You know there's a lot of work to be done and I think they'll be very good contributors. Yes, 2016, 2017, so we're very happy with them, because on Wheatstone it's all electrical, but on Gorgon only 30% of that will be electrical. The rest is sort of multi trades and that's great for making sure that we keep our best project managers, our best supervisors et cetera foremen and tradies on the job. It's great.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Second question, outlook for New Zealand, obviously flagged the timing of margins there. Does that change much in the second half, are there any sort of micro dynamics happening there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, you know it's very similar wherever you are in the world I think. All of our customers are having a tough time, you know the USB side, Chorus has had some regulatory stuff and they've got to reduce their OpEx, so we're helping them out there. I think in the next half, our volumes may improve to cover some of that, but yes it's a tougher margin environment than it was certainly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, and last question, in terms of the new or the restructure, are you able to quantify the savings you expect from that restructure?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No not really mate at this point. The restructures more around -- is more around making sure that our focus is on our customers, and that we are aligning ourselves with their needs. And that we've got our capabilities you know working hard in the particular service lines that we have. So it's more about that, it's about I guess there's some de-layering and stuff. But it's not about cost reduction. Now there will be, there'll be a fair bit of stuff that comes out of here, but it's too early to say. I guess that's evolving.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, your next question comes from Nathan Reilly from Goldman Sachs, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nathan Reilly,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Morning gents, just a quick question on the Mining division. Looks like another pretty commendable EBIT margin outcome there, coming in at, I think it's the upper end of your target range for that division. Albeit below I think it was a pretty strong comp last year. Can you just give us an idea of some of the initiatives you're working on just to defend that margin in what is a pretty challenging environment for that business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, look there's no silver bullets there mate, I think they're running their business hard across all the angles. They're getting production wise they're getting good utilisation out of their fleet, they have a good mix of fleet to diggers. You know they've got a productive workforce. The fact that the mining boom has come off. We have very experienced operators et cetera and all of that helps and continues to help us. We're also taking costs out of head office et cetera in Brisbane, so I think across the board there's no one single thing mate.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nathan Reilly,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you make a quick comment maybe around sort of labour cost trends in that business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes look we've had some success in trying to put a more sustainable labour cost position in place in some parts of our business. I think that's very good. Hopefully that will be something that will be sustained across that part of our business, and also I think there's more to be done across other geographies.
 But it's not easy. The workplace laws are not easy to move wages and labour costs. Particularly when you're not having a lot of new investment, right, so where you've got mostly existing mines and you're talking about wage reductions or labour reductions in existing mines. That's pretty tough for the industry and I think we're seeing that. But hopefully over time we'll see a move. We have had some success as I said, and we're pretty pleased with that. There's a lot to be gained also about more productivity. You know it's not just wage rate, there's a lot on the productivity front and you can see from our numbers our guys are doing very well there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nathan Reilly,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Your next question comes from Richard Johnson from Citi, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much. Grant I just wanted to ask you a question about mix and particularly as it relates to your guidance. I mean does the consulting businesses through the first half sort of performed worse than you'd anticipated originally. So by implication have the other businesses actually held up a little better given as you've effectively held your guidance right through the half?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I think that's probably a fair call. Certainly the mining consultancies we just perhaps weren't expecting that everything would stop, which is what's happened.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There's also been some geo-political overlays as well for our mineral technologies business. They do a lot of beneficiation and spiral separators and they've delivered a lot of product into Eastern Europe and the Ukraine area. With everything going to a stop there, that certainly affects some of their volumes. So we wouldn't have anticipated that for sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But as I said in the, as I said in the start of the presentation, I'm pretty pleased with, generally, how the business has gone, and that includes the Infrastructure. I think the guys have been out and winning work and they continue to win it, and the delivery side of the business has been very good as well. So we can't complain too much, as I said it's a bit hard to defy gravity here. But I think they're doing as good as they can do. Our brand is important to us right now. I think we are seen as a business that can deliver and that is helping us win business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So by indication then, we should have seen that you're taking share, correct?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I'm not sure what share is at the moment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No I know what you mean. Sorry just one more thing on consulting, I mean what kind of visibility do you have in that business? I mean it sounds like you're relatively comfortable with where you've got the business to now from a cost perspective, but what about the revenue lines?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, well that's the difficult position. You know when there's obviously in the consultancy side there's pre-work, who's going to fund it. So a lot of this depends on commodity prices and whether people are prepared to fund this stuff, right? So we're working with a lot of people at the moment on potential things that might come to fruition. But you know it's been tough to convert those into paying jobs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then just one small one for Kevin and I apologise if I missed this, but the tax rate for the year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Probably going to be around the same level as the half year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's on effects?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Johnson,  Citigroup Inc - Analyst   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great, thanks very much and well done.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Your next questions comes from Craig Wong-Pan from Deutsche Bank, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just going on from that tax question, I mean the rate going forward, should we expect a similar level going forward, or is FY15 an unusual year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Look I think we've certainly had a fairly sizeable true-up reputable to 2014 come through, but the business is working very hard on optimising what they get out of R&amp;D. I think that's been a benefit of us actually giving risk and reward for that activity to the divisions. There's some muted comments coming out of government previously about putting some restrictions around what you can claim. But that's not been legislated yet. Look I think this year's probably a little bit abnormal, certainly I'd like to see our business focus very very hard on optimising what they can get out of this. But the very smart things that they're doing and doing with our customers, so it will have an impact on our tax rate going forward, and I certainly expect it to be below 30%. Whether it's just going to be down as far as 26% I don't know yet.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and then just the restructuring that you're doing, have you quantified the costs for that, the total costs incurred?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Look not exactly, I mean Grant's point earlier to say there will be some restructuring done, I mean one of the things that we're doing in taking the opportunity here, is effectively amalgamating what was effectively the Infrastructure head office with the corporate head office. Clearly there's some overlap within those two functions. So to the extent that there's going to be some savings come out of that, they'll probably be offset by termination costs in the half. So it'll probably be neutral, but certainly going forward I'd expect us to be a more efficient and streamlined business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, and the point about this restructure as you get with most, it's all about reinvigorating the business, and that's what you get out of this. You make way for some new people to come up and show their wares, and they come in very excited and they go hard and that's really what we need right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Wong-Pan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Your next question comes from Ben Brownette from CBA, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes hi, sorry I was just wondering with the 2010 stat guidance, just in relation to the segments just sticking my numbers into the segments and having a look. It appears there either needs to be a reasonably large pick up in the segments of the operating business. Or should there be some expectation of some further positive unallocated costs delivering the 2010 stat number?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You've got the -- if you take the AUD45 million, AUD55milion, I mean if you just took the first half result and doubled that, you're sort of up around the AUD190 million, and then we've got the benefit of a full six month of Tenix coming through in the second half. We do have some seasonality in our business, that's typically why it is sort of more skewed towards the second half. Particularly in the servicing and the asphalting business. So we're pretty comfortable where we are and I guess the differentiator is the fact that you've got six months of Tenix coming through.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We have had some what we'd call operational sort of wet weather which we're not highlighting too much, but hopefully we don't have that in the second half and that'll help us as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right, so with the respect to unallocated costs, you obviously don't have Tenix acquisition of cost. Should we be expecting any of the R&amp;D positives or the customer contract positives? But you've said that corporate costs are going to be mid AUD60 million, so they go up quite significantly. There's no Tenix cost but then there's double the amount of positives, so should we just assume that comes out as even?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fletcher,  Downer EDI Limited - CFO   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If you take the -- as I said if you get to the adjusted AUD15million on that quality of earnings slide, that's backing out that provision release or customer settlement. Then I said if you add back the AUD10 million of R&amp;D true-up to 2014 you get AUD25 million. Now if you just double that you're up to AUD50 million. We have got some costs coming through in the second half preferable to the centralisation and initiative to bring all of our shared services activities together going forward. So we're basically bringing four shared services centres in Australia into one, we'll be announcing that, well that's being announced as we speak in the business. We also do, we tend to skew in our first half second half, effectively the group offers bonuses, because we do take up some provisionally for bonuses in the first half. But it is more oriented towards the second half because they've not been achieved yet. So we tend to forecast for that in the second half and that's why we sort of go from the AUD50 million, add some costs for shared services and then other bits and pieces.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and I was just wondering if you can comment on any other major contract renegotiations or retendering that might be happening right now within the business. I mean are there things that just in talking to people around the place, it seems like there are some major renegotiations going on. Are you able to talk about any of that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh we don't talk about those mate until we've got a position on them I think.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Brownette,  CBA - Analyst   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, your next question comes from Sam Theodore from UBS, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sam Theodore,  UBS - Analyst   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, hi guys. You know obviously the business needs to win work consistently. I'm just wondering to get to that second half number, has the second half revenue now largely been locked in? So it's not about risk around winning extra work from here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We never have 100% of our work done mate, so we've still got work to win. Remember a large part of our business revolves around small parcels of work right across the country, but we've still got work to do yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sam Theodore,  UBS - Analyst   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I know it's still a little bit further away, but you've obviously got some bigger contracts starting next year. Can you give us a view on how much of the -- maybe looking more at the larger contracts, what roles are relative to the start-up of Gorgon and the like? Trying to get a view on to 2016?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No I'm not going to do that today. We're going through our planning cycle as we speak, so we'll have more to say to that, on that mate at our investor day.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sam Theodore,  UBS - Analyst   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay cool, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [107]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, your next question comes from John Purtell from Macquarie Group, please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [108]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sorry guys just one quick follow up on Tenix, are you expecting overhead and cost savings to being to flow through in the second half there, or is that more a 2016 story?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [109]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No I think stuffs flowing through already, so the guys are well into it. So yes you'll see stuff floating through into 2015 and yes there'll be more in 2016.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Purtell,  Macquarie Group - Analyst   [110]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [111]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, at this time we are showing no further questions over the phone.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Grant Fenn,  Downer EDI Limited - MD and CEO   [112]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well that's great. Thanks very much for your time and thanks for coming on the call, bye.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Interim 2015 Downer EDI Ltd Earnings Presentation]]></eventTitle>
  <city>North Ryde, New South Wales</city>
  <companyName>Downer EDI Ltd</companyName>
  <companyTicker>DOW.AX</companyTicker>
  <startDate>4-Feb-15 10:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>164565</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>6465573</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>AU000000DOW2</ISIN>
</Event>