<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="3678719" lastUpdate="Saturday, February 12, 2011 at 6:59:27am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="3678719.F" expirationDate="Friday, February 11, 2011 at 3:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of GS.TO earnings conference call or presentation 11-Feb-11 3:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2011 GLUSKIN SHEFF & ASSOCIATES INC Earnings Conference Call

Toronto Feb 12, 2011 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Gluskin Sheff + Associates Inc earnings conference call or presentation Friday, February 11, 2011 at 3:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  David Morris
      Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - CFO
   *  Jeremy Freedman
      Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO
   *  Bill Webb
      Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer
   *  Brian Ginsler
      Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - COO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Paul Holden
      CIBC - Analyst
   *  Fred Westra
      Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst
   *  Doug Young
      TD Newcrest - Analyst
   *  Geoff Kwan
      RBC Capital - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates second-quarter fiscal 2011 results and conference call. As a reminder, today's call is being recorded. It is February 11, 2011.
 I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. David Morris, Chief Financial Officer. Please go ahead, Mr. Morris.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Morris,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - CFO   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates second-quarter fiscal 2011 conference call. Following the formal comments we will hold a question-and-answer session. Please be advised that this call is being recorded.
 The Company's results were issued by press release yesterday afternoon and are available, together with the MD&amp;A, on the Company's website at www.GluskinSheff.com.
 Before we begin we would like to remind everyone that during this call management may make statements containing forward-looking information relating to the Company's business and the environment in which it operates.
 These statements are based on management's expectations, estimates, forecasts and projections. They are not guarantees of future performance and involve risks and uncertainties that are difficult to control or predict.
 These risks and uncertainties are discussed in the Company's regulatory filings available on our website and on SEDAR. Actual outcomes and results may differ materially from those expressed in these forward-looking statements.
 Further, these forward-looking statements speak only as of the dates on which such statements are made and the Company undertakes no obligation to publicly update any such statement or to reflect new information or the occurrence of future events or circumstances.
 Now I would like to introduce Jeremy Freedman, President and CEO of Gluskin Sheff.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David, and good morning everyone and thank you for joining us today. Joining me from the Company on today's call our Gerald Sheff, Cofounder and Chairman of the Board; Bill Webb, Executive Vice President and Chief Investment Officer; David Morris, our CFO, who you have just heard from; and Brian Ginsler, our Chief Operating Officer.
 2010 was characterized by volatility and risks. There were a number of signs pointing to continued fragility in the global economic recovery. Financial markets responded to this instability with wild swings.
 The S&amp;P 500 Index so no fewer than eight alternating mini bull and bear sessions in calendar 2010, at times jumping as much as 8% to 10%, up and down, from one month to the next.
 Equity markets rallied strongly through the fourth calendar quarter, as the return to risk assets was stronger than we thought warranted by the economic fundamentals. Notwithstanding continued market volatility, as we enter calendar year 2011, we have a positive long-term investment outlook in several areas.
 These include commodities, materials, higher-yielding securities, and the Canadian dollar. And our investment portfolios will be more concentrated in these areas.
 We continue to like the resource sector as a long-term investment. And in order to gain more concentrated exposure, we will be utilizing two recently launched portfolios dedicated to resource-based investments, the GS+A Resource Fund and the GS+A Resource Long/Short Fund.
 We also believe international and emerging markets are an area of continued opportunity over the long haul. Our recently launched GS+A International Fund will allow us to provide greater geographic diversification to our clients' asset mixes, while taking advantage of expected opportunities in this area.
 Quarter-over-quarter total assets under management increased by CAD160 million or 3%, to CAD6 billion, as at December 31, 2010. This increase came from positive investment performance of CAD258 million, offset by net withdrawals of CAD98 million. Average AUM for the quarter was CAD6 billion, as compared to approximately CAD5.7 billion for the quarter ended September 30, 2010, an increase of CAD260 million or 5%.
 Base management fees for the quarter ended December 31, 2010, increased CAD2.2 million or 12% to CAD21 million from CAD18.8 million for the quarter ended December 31, 2009.
 Average AUM increased approximately CAD0.8 billion or 15% over the same period.
 Performance fees for the second quarter were CAD15.8 million, versus CAD44.2 million for the quarter ended December 31, 2009. Performance fees earned in the quarter relate primarily to CAD2.8 billion of AUM with a December 31 performance year-end.
 Total operating expenses for the three months ended December 31, 2010, decreased year-over-year by CAD13.1 million or 43%, to CAD17.6 million from CAD30.7 million.
 The decrease in operating expenses was primarily due to a decrease in salaries and benefits of CAD12.5 million and a decrease in G&amp;A expenses of CAD1 million.
 The decrease in salaries and benefits was primarily related to lower performance fee-related bonuses and the absence of the initial charge for the postretirement obligation that occurred in the same quarter last year.
 The decrease in G&amp;A expenses was due principally to lower performance fee-related subadvisory fees, partially offset by an increase in costs associated with a number of business projects currently in progress.
 We continue to invest in our infrastructure and expect costs associated with these initiatives to continue over the next few years.
 As a measure of the success of our business operations, we monitor what we call base EBITDA, which excludes performance fee revenue and certain nonrecurring and non-cash expenses. Base EBITDA for the quarter ended December 31, 2010, increased approximately CAD0.8 million or 8% to CAD10.5 million from CAD9.7 million for the quarter ended December 31 2009.
 Base EBITDA quarter-over-quarter increased by one CAD117,000 or 1% to the CAD10.5 million I mentioned a moment ago.
 Net income for the three months ended December 31, 2010, was CAD14.1 million, and represented earnings per share basic and diluted of CAD0.48.
 Net income for the three months ended December 31, 2009, was CAD21.6 million and represented EPS basic and diluted of CAD0.74 and CAD0.73, respectively.
 As approved by the Board of Directors and announced yesterday, the second-quarter dividend of CAD0.1375 per common share was declared and is payable on March 18, 2011, to shareholders of record as at February 24, 2011.
 With that, thank you for your time and attention, and we would now be pleased to take your questions.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Paul Holden, CIBC.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wanted to ask you several questions on the net asset flow number. The first time we have seen net redemptions for approximately 2 years now. I am just wondering what client feedback you're hearing that is maybe leading to those flows?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I would say the feedback is that we were very conservatively positioned last year. And while that seemed to be not an unreasonable place to be for the first nine months, the strong recovery in the fourth quarter was disappointing relative to our results.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So it is more of a, say an asset mix situation in terms of your clients' perspective?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just our overall tone of conservatism is something that when the markets are raging, obviously creates some concern.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Second, a related question then, did it come from a number of different accounts, i.e., did it come from a lot of different accounts or maybe was there a few large accounts that took money out?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, there was a combination, and there is also a combination of money coming out from people who have remained clients, but are doing their own asset reallocation. And some who have -- that are client terminations. It is a combination.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. I know it is only one quarter, so you're probably not too concerned about the trend, but is there any specific action you're taking maybe to stem further net redemptions?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, and I would say rather than be concerned about a trend, we are always concerned when our performance is not at the level we expect of ourselves.
 And the actions we are taking, first of all, is to meet with and communicate extensively with our clients about what we are doing and why we are positioned the way we are.
 We are absolute return oriented. It is interesting is the quarter where, as you saw, the gains in the market where approximately 4% on our assets and on an absolute return basis, if you could do 4% a quarter you would never be dissatisfied. But when the market rages the way it does, 4% disappoints some people.
 So we are meeting with clients, talking to clients, explaining to them why we are positioned the way we are. And on the portfolio side I would say we are becoming more concentrated in our best ideas, and putting more emphasis on the securities in which we have the greatest conviction.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. When I look at the fund returns your long-only funds certainly have performed quite well. But when I look at say -- what is it supposed to, I guess, market neutral funds, let's call them, or the alternative investment strategies, returns have been less than compelling, let's say.
 Is there anything in particular you might be changing in terms of strategy or how those alternative investment strategies are currently managed?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I am not really changing the strategy. What happened last year was we did quite as well as you say on the equity side, and we did fine on the long side of our long/short funds. But the things we shorted, which we felt were not good businesses or were highly overvalued, just kept going up.
 So I would say what -- as I said a minute ago, what we are doing in our portfolios, not just the long ones, but on the short side, it is we are backing those ideas, which we have the greatest conviction.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Now I know you've always been geared more towards organic growth, but would there be any possible change in terms of M&amp;A activity?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Really, I have to give the same answer I have always given, which is we have always grown organically. It has been a successful way to grow, and we think a good risk-adjusted way to grow. At the same time we never say never to anything. If something was compelling, we wouldn't say no on principle.
 But at the moment we remain focused on looking after our existing clients and recognizing that is the surest way to a path of success for our clients and our business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 What type of opportunity would you consider compelling, i.e., would it be access to broader distribution or enhancing some kind of investment capability that you may not currently have in-house?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would say it has to run the gamut. It would have to be something that we thought was compelling for our clients, and would add value to our business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Holden,  CIBC - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, fair enough. I will get back in the queue and let other people ask questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra, Industrial Alliance Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So on the subject of performance, I am just going to circle back on that one. I know that you were still holding some cash positions through out 2010, not as high as you had coming out of the financial crisis perhaps. But are you moving towards being fully invested as part of this increased concentration on your best ideas?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Webb,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is Bill Webb here. Yes, we are essentially fully invested in most of the portfolio, the long-only portfolios, and did put money to work both in the third and fourth quarter of the year. So the answer is yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And it seems that, particularly on three of the long-only portfolios that the performance -- the one-year performance seems to be holding up quite well. You are in performance fee territory possibly for July. Obviously there is still six months to go, but are the indications still good in terms of the directionality of the performance of those portfolios as it stands today?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Webb,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, again, we disclose the results on a quarterly basis, as you know, and we will continue with that practice. In terms of performance fees we have always learned that the only time they matter is when you get to the date when they crystallize.
 We have seen -- especially in the kind of environment we are in with huge market volatility, we could drive ourselves nuts if we tried to figure out what they were on a daily or weekly basis. The fact is we just need to manage the money in the right way for our clients and the result is the result.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right, fair enough. Well, then, just in terms of asset allocation mix, could you talk a little bit about these two new portfolios that you have launched and what kind of asset allocation views you have in terms of moving client money around?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Webb,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, it is early days for those portfolios. Obviously, they started at the beginning of January. The resource-only and the resource long/short were in part a reaction to two things.
 One is our long-term belief and view that commodities and materials resources generally are in a secular bull market. And we have invested in these kinds of securities from the day the firm was founded, but a desire to get more concentrated in those areas and to offer more concentration in those areas.
 Secondly, an interest from investors outside of Canada who want to have exposure to Canada, the interest oftentimes is centered on our resources. So we really constructed these portfolios with a view to offering something for foreign investors that would directly and in a concentrated fashion access that area of the Canadian marketplace.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, part of the reason that I asked the question, I realize it is early days, but the speed with which you launched the credit portfolios and the aggressiveness with which you moved client assets into those following the financial crisis was -- obviously will not be replicated here, but do you think that -- is this going to be a very slow move in assets or do you -- or is this going to be part of, again, that increased emphasis on best ideas and increased concentration into these things, and that we would expect to see flows of client assets over the course of the next year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Webb,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would say a bit more the latter than the former. It is certainly not like credit where we thought there was a unique opportunity, and then it turned out even a shorter term opportunity than we thought, where there was a crisis and there was crisis pricing that we felt was quite inefficient.
 This is more of an investment for a secular trend. Having said that, we have a multi-strategy -- our multi-strategy funds and now that we have the resource long/short that will play part of that platform.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, fair enough. Just turning away from that for a second, the tax rates -- the effective tax rates seem to be in line with Q1 but lower than the historical average. Is this something that we can expect to see going forward or maybe this is a question more for David?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Morris,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - CFO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, it is David here. Tough to forecast. It really is just impacted by some of the things we mentioned in the MD&amp;A in terms of the timing of some of the nondeductible items. So it is just difficult to forecast, but we are close to the 29.25%, which is the statutory rate currently.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. So for forecasting purposes, would we be well-served to use 30% or more around the 35% that has been the historical average?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Morris,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - CFO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The actual statutory rates have been coming down quite significantly in the last little while, and continue to go down, and will continue to go down as we go forward. So for forecasting purposes I think the best thing we can do is just use -- follow very close to the statutory rate (multiple speakers) best guess.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fred Westra,  Industrial Alliance Securities - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, fair enough. I will re-queue. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Doug Young, TD Newcrest.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess the first question, just back to the net flows. I guess there is just a few angles I wanted to get some perspective. I know you don't give us gross and redemptions, but can you give us some perspective, was it gross coming down -- or gross sales coming down or was it redemptions going up?
 I know historically when you talk to clients when you're not overly enthusiastic about what is going on out there, you're not out there pitching and selling. Is there still a little bit of that is going on in your conversations?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think there's a couple of things. You identified the right areas. One of the things that happens is when you're not as enthusiastic with the market, certainly the sales cycle is longer.
 Secondly, when you have the kind of quarter we had where the relative performance was obviously weak, you spend a lot more time with your existing clients. And that is just time that is taken away from dealing with prospective clients, so you suffer on that front as well.
 Having said that, like has been the case in the past, we certainly had inflows and we had outflows. Unfortunately in the quarter the outflows were greater than the inflows, but we did have some inflows.
 There definitely becomes an imbalance though when you are spending most of your time talking to existing clients and taking them through your strategies and your thinking and your valuations and your asset mix recommendations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So am I to read that gross sales probably came down as a result of what you just described?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, again, we don't give to that level of granularity. All I am saying is that we do have new clients coming in, and we have had some clients take some money out, and other clients who have gone on to take their money elsewhere.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fair enough, I will leave that one alone. Just doing simple math, so I take the average asset growth year-over-year. I think it is up 14% or roughly around there, so correct me if I'm wrong. Thehn if I look at base EBITDA it is up 8%. And I always think of assets going up by that amount and the leverage within these models. Can you talk about why there is that discrepancy?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Morris,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - CFO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, I'll take that. It is David. A couple of main reasons. One, we are spending and continue to spend on building infrastructure to support the growth of the business going forward.
 And, two, there has been a slight change, I guess, in the average management fee percentage as we moved between different asset classes.
 We had an increase in some of the fixed income asset classes, which have a lower management fee rate, so the average management fee rate came down slightly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It sounds like there is, I guess, more expenditures to come on infrastructure over the next three years. And I guess, is there -- first question, is there a lot of big investments coming? And why over three years, because you're moving buildings, why wouldn't you just do this upfront?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Ginsler,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - COO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is Brian Ginsler here. I think there is a couple of things. Number one, the move obviously plays into some of that cost as well, and there is a certain amount that can be amortized and a certain amount that has to be expensed as we move along.
 In terms of infrastructure spending, I think you are correct. There is a number of years of spending ahead of us, because what we are trying to do is build the business -- build infrastructure for the expected and continued growth that we hope to have.
 So our focus is spending now to get us prepared and able to handle future growth and able to deliver the level of client service that we feel is necessary.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Do you care to quantify or give some perspective of how much this could be?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Not beyond what we have indicated in the MD&amp;A.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Doug Young,  TD Newcrest - Analyst   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alright, that's good for me. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Geoff Kwan, RBC Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Geoff Kwan,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just had a couple of questions. The first one, just in terms of the new fund, my guess is Kai is probably going to be running the international fund. But just was wondering who is the PM on the two resource funds?
 Then the second question I had was you have obviously an increase in the number of fund products that you are offering clients. Do you think that there is a reasonable number of new potential funds that you think would benefit your clients?
 And on the same note, do you think that maybe your clients feel that you maybe have a bit too many products out there, that maybe you need to narrow the product shelf?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will let Bill speak about the managers of the resource models and maybe I will then speak to the second question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Webb,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - EVP, Chief Investment Officer   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, you are correct, Kai Lam is the manager of the international fund. The resource long-only fund is managed by Jeff Hales. And the resource long/short fund is co-managed by Jeff Hales, Matt Ritzel and Reno Giancola, who really works in sort of a risk management capacity with them. So those are the folks on those funds.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In terms of the lineup of funds, our objective isn't to sell product, it is because we have discretion over most of our -- where our client assets go, it is to create portfolios that we think are opportunistic and that have the ability to deliver strong risk-adjusted returns over time. So that is when we start new funds. And frankly at times we also wind up funds, because we don't think that they have the opportunity to deliver those kinds of returns going forward.
 So our lineup evolves where we see opportunity, but it also gets culled when we think a strategy has -- no longer can play that role.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Geoff Kwan,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Now let us stand by for any further questions. There are no further questions at this time. Please continue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeremy Freedman,  Gluskin Sheff &amp; Associates - President, CEO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, in that case, thanks to everyone for joining us on this call today. If anyone has any further questions, please don't hesitate to give us a call. Have a good weekend.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude your conference call for today. We thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect your lines. And have a great day, ladies and gentlemen.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2011 GLUSKIN SHEFF & ASSOCIATES INC Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Toronto</city>
  <companyName>Gluskin Sheff + Associates Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>GS.TO</companyTicker>
  <startDate>11-Feb-11 3:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>200660</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>B15S1Y6</SEDOL>
  <ISIN />
</Event>