<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="5829975" lastUpdate="Thursday, October 22, 2015 at 4:58:58am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="5829975.F" expirationDate="Wednesday, October 21, 2015 at 12:30:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of IPG earnings conference call or presentation 21-Oct-15 12:30pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q3 2015 Interpublic Group of Companies Inc Earnings Call

NEW YORK Oct 22, 2015 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Interpublic Group of Companies Inc earnings conference call or presentation Wednesday, October 21, 2015 at 12:30:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jerry Leshne
      The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - SVP, IR
   *  Michael Roth
      The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO
   *  Frank Mergenthaler
      The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Alexia Quadrani
      JPMorgan - Analyst
   *  John Janedis
      Jefferies LLC - Analyst
   *  David Bank
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Peter Stabler
      Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst
   *  Ben Swinburne
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Dan Salmon
      BMO Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Tim Nolan
      Macquarie Research Equities - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. And welcome to the Interpublic Group third-quarter 2015 earnings conference call. (Operator Instructions) I would now like to introduce Mr. Jerry Leshne senior vice president of investor relations. Sir, you may begin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jerry Leshne,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - SVP, IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Thank you for joining us.
 We have posted our earnings release and our slide presentation on our website Interpublic.com. This morning we are joined by Michael Roth and Frank Mergenthaler. We will begin with prepared remarks to be followed by Q&amp;A. We plan to conclude before market open at 9:30 Eastern.
 During this call we will refer to forward-looking statements about our Company. These are subject to the uncertainties and the cautionary statement that are included in our earnings release and the slide presentation and further detailed in our 10-Q and other filings with the SEC. We will also refer to certain non-GAAP measures. We believe that these measures provide useful supplemental data that while not a substitute for GAAP measures, allow for greater transparency in the review of our financial and operational performance. At this point it is my pleasure to turn things over to Michael Roth.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you Jerry, and thank you for joining us this morning as we review our results for the third quarter and nine months of 2015. I will start out by covering highlights of our performance, Frank will then provide additional details, and I will conclude with an update on our agencies and the tone of our Business to be followed by Q&amp;A.
 We are pleased to report another quarter of strong organic revenue and profit growth. Organic revenue growth in our third-quarter was 7.1%. On top of a very strong comps from a year ago. Net acquisitions had a positive impact of 10 basis points while FX was a negative 5.9%. However FX had very little impact on our operating margin. Total revenue growth was 1.3%.
 We continue to see positive contributions to our topline performance from a broad range of our creative media and marketing services offerings. Across the group additional capabilities were against significant drivers of growth. We also continue to drive strong growth in our largest regional markets with the US, Asia Pac and UK all showing very good advances.
 Organic growth in Lat Am was very strong. From the standpoint of client sectors we saw growth across all client verticals. The best performance came in tech and telecom, financial services, food and beverage, and healthcare. Our operating profit in the quarter was $192 million. An increase of 12% from a year ago.
 Q3 operating margin expanded 100 basis points to 10.3%. We had leverage on both our salaries and related and office and general expenses. Worth noting that below operating profit other expenses in the quarter includes charges totaling $38 million to dispose of certain smaller business units, which were underperforming and which we deemed as non strategic, all of which were outside the US. Most of the expense was non-cash. Frank will have more color in his comments.
 The after-tax expense was $0.09 per diluted share in the quarter and $0.08 for the nine months. Excluding the charge of disposition diluted EPS for the quarter was $0.27, an increase of 29% compared to the prior period. Looking at the first nine months, organic revenue growth was 6.5% on top of 5.9% a year ago. We posted a 17% increase to operating profit and a 34% increase in adjusted diluted EPS. This represents industry-leading organic revenue growth and profit growth. That's an accomplishment which all our people across the company can be proud of.
 Turning back to a bit more detail on the quarter. US organic growth was 7.1% on top of 7.9% a year ago, which is an outstanding result. We had growth at most of our agencies. Notably McCann, Mediabrands, FCB, Deutsch, R/GA, Weber Shandwick, and Golin. International growth was 7.1%. Once again driven by a full range of services.
 By regions we were led by 14.4% growth in Lat Am where we saw increases in most national markets. Asia Pac increased 7.2% organically and was highlighted by our continuing strong trends in India and China. In the UK organic growth was 5.2% on top of last year's 12% growth. We were led by the growth of R/GA and our marketing services specialist at CMG. In continental Europe Q3 organic growth was essentially flat and we continue to stay focused on improving our talent and capabilities in this region.
 The first nine months 6 1/2% organic growth reflected growth in every region of the world in contributions across all major disciplines. Nine months operating margin growth was 100 basis points with leverage on our base payroll, benefits and tax and on office and general expenses. As we said previously, supporting our best in class offerings, as well as cost discipline and margin enhancement continue to be our top priorities and we are successfully executing against those objectives.
 With respect to share repurchase, during Q3 we used $70 million to repurchase 3.6 million shares. Through nine months we've utilized approximately $172 million of share repurchases and we had $271 million remaining on our authorization as of September 30. Since instituting our return of capital programs in 2011, we have returned $2.3 billion to shareholders in dividends and share repurchases, as well as reduced our dilutive share count by 26%. In sum, our performance in the quarter and year to date continues to demonstrate industry leadership in the strong position of our offerings.
 Heading into our important fourth quarter, economic conditions in some areas of the world will present macro headwinds and uncertainties. While those have been incorporated into our outlook, the overall tone of business nonetheless remains solid and we continue to effectively manage expenses.
 Previously we increased our full-year 2015 organic growth target to 4 to 5%. Our strong performance through nine months has us on track to exceed 5%. We also remain well-positioned to achieve 100 basis points of market expansion this year. The high end of our targeted range.
 With that overview, I will turn it to Frank for additional detail on our results and I will join you after his remarks for an update on our operating units, to be followed by Q&amp;A.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frank Mergenthaler,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Michael. Good morning.
 As a reminder I will be referring to the slide presentation that accompanies our webcast. On slide 2 is a summary of our results. Organic growth was 7.1% in the third quarter evenly balance between the US international. In our first nine months organic revenue growth was 6.5%. Q3 operating profit was $192 million, an increase of 12%. For the first nine months operating profit grew 17%. Q3 margin of 10.3% improved 100 basis points and our margin for the nine months also improved 100 basis points.
 We had a below the line charge of $38 million for the disposition of selected non-US business units. Most of the charge is the balance sheet right off of currency translation adjustments built up over the years with the balance representing the net assets of the disposed businesses. This pertains to a handful of business for which revenue was small with non-cash translation adjustments magnified by large affects changes over the years. The impact of this charge from reported diluted EPS was $0.09 for the quarter. Including the charge diluted EPS was $0.27, which compares to Q3 2014 at $0.21, a 29% increase. Q3 fully diluted shares decreased 3% from last year, due to our share repurchase program.
 Turning to slide 3, you will see our P&amp;L for the quarter. I will cover revenue and operating expenses in detail in the slides with follow-ups. I've already covered the disposition-related charges and other expenses.
 Slide 4 has more detail on our revenue growth. Revenue was $1.87 billion in the quarter, an increase of 1.3%. Compared to Q3 in 2014, the impact of the changing currency exchange rates was a negative 5.9%, with the dollar significantly stronger in all regions of the world. Acquisitions added 10 basis points to revenue. The resulting organic revenue increase was 7.1%.
 As you can see on the bottom half of this slide, at our Integrated HT Networks the organic increase was 8%. This was led by our global integrated offerings at McCann and FCB, by Mediabrands, Deutsche, and by R/GA -- IMGA. IMs growth was 7.5% over the first nine months. At our CMG segment Q3 organic growth was 3.7%. We continue to have very strong growth at our PR agencies, notably Weber Shandwick and Golin, which grew at double-digit rates. Organic growth was 2.5% at CMG for the first nine months but was mid-single digit increase excluding the impact of lower pass-through revenues.
 Moving on to Slide 5, revenue by region, in the US, Q3 organic growth was outstanding at 7.1%, with contributions coming from a very broad cross section of agencies, disciplines, and client sectors. For the nine months organic growth was 7%.
 In the UK Q3 organic growth was 5.2% on top of 12.2% last year. We had notably strong performance at R/GA, McCann, Octagon, and Weber Shandwick. For the nine months organic growth was 6.5%. Continental Europe was essentially flat organically in Q3. Our largest markets in the continent were mixed with Spain up organically, Italy and France last, and Germany down.
 In Asia Pac, our largest international region, Q3 organic growth was 7.2%, propelled by strong growth in China and India. Growth for the nine months was 8.4% a performance that speaks to a strength of our positioning across our global integrated agencies, our media business, our digital specialists, and our public relations offerings.
 In Lat Am our organic increase was 14.4% in the quarter. We continue to see very strong performance in most national markets such as Mexico, Argentina, and Colombia, which is consistent with the first half of the year. We also had improved quarter in Brazil although business conditions generally remain challenging there. In the quarter we had leading contributions to growth in the region by McCann, Mediabrands, R/GA, and Huge. Our other markets group, which made up of Canada and the Middle East and Africa grew 13.5% organically in the quarter, due chiefly to strong performance in the Middle East, as well as growth in Canada.
 On slide 6 we chart the longer view of our organic revenue change on a trailing 12-month basis. The most recent data point is 6%.
 Moving on to slide 7, our operating expenses in the third quarter total operating expenses increased 20 basis points from a year ago compared with our reported revenue growth of 1.3%. As a result margin expanded 100 basis points. Underneath that performance our ratio salaries and related expenses to revenue in the quarter was 64.4% this year, an improvement of 50 basis points from a year ago. We had 50 basis points of leverage and our base payroll benefits and tax expense, as well as 20 points of base points on temporary labor. Our accrual for incentives increased by 40 basis points as a percent of revenue driven by our strong operating performance.
 Total head count at quarter end was approximately 48,700, an increase of 3.2% year on year. The increase chiefly reflects organic hiring in support of growth in areas such as digital, creative, healthcare and PR, as well as regionally in the US UK, and Asia Pac.
 Turning to ops and general expenses on the lower half of the slide O&amp;G expense was 25.3 of Q3 revenue compared with 25.8 year ago an improvement of 50 basis points. Our improvement was driven by leverage on expenses for occupancy, travel, office supplies, and telecom and all other O&amp;G expense.
 On slide 8 we show our operating margin history on a trailing 12-month basis. The most recent data point is 11.1%.
 Turning to the current portion of our balance sheet on slide 9 we ended the third quarter with $881 million cash and short term marketable securities. Comparison to December 31 reflects our cash level seasonal and tends to peak at year end.
 On slide 10 we turn to our third-quarter cash flow. Cash provided by operations was $281 million, compared with $176 million a year ago. Working capital was a source of $154 million this year, compared with the use $11 million in Q3 2014. Investing activities used $41 million in the quarter, primarily for CapEx. Financing activities used $151 million, mainly in capital return to shareholders, $70 million for share repurchases, and $48 million for common stock dividends. Our net increase in cash and cash equivalents for the quarter was $26 million.
 On slide 11 we showed debt deleveraging from a peak of $2.35 billion in 2007 to $1.75 billion at the most recent quarter end.
 In summary on slide 12, the quarter and the year to date represents very solid performance in progress toward meeting our financial objectives for the full year. We're seeing growth in areas where we have focused our investment in both people and acquisitions. Our operators are focused on the appropriate cost discipline and margin expansion and our balance sheet is an important area that we continue to deploy for value going forward.
 With that said, let me turn it back to Michael.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you Frank.
 It's worth repeating that we are pleased to continue reporting strong results. In terms of organic revenue growth and margin progress, Q3 continues to make us a leader in our peer group. Contributions came from across the portfolio. In terms of agencies, geography, client categories, all fueled by the outstanding creativity, insights, and digital capabilities that we have throughout Interpublic. Our success is a reflection of the strength of our offerings and our client-centric focus.
 Ultimately it is driven by the caliber of our people. Across the group we continue to see evidence that Interpublic and our agencies are consistently a first choice for the industry's best talent. For some time, talent has been a top strategic priority for us; one that has fueled our return to levels of organic growth that are fully competitive or better. We are proud that our culture has become a differentiator for us and has our long-standing commitment to diversity and inclusion, where we have a strong and established track record as the leader in our space.
 On our call last quarter we drilled down and provided greater focus on the role digital expertise is playing in all of our work we do for our clients from advertising through media and marketing services. We pointed out that unlike others in our space, IPG's digital capabilities have been largely grown organically and are embedded within every one of our disciplines. This commitment to incubating new skills, developing new products and services and investing in new technology has allowed us to stay highly relevant in today's digital world. It gives us confidence that our offerings are forward facing, competitive, and increasingly vital to clients as they seek to navigate the complexity of the media and marketing landscape.
 Operationally it's clear that we continue to be disciplined in terms of cost management. We remain focused on converting at the appropriate levels to deliver 100 basis points of margin improvement for the year. We also remain committed to robust capital return programs that have been driving further value creation for our shareholders. As we look to the fourth quarter, the tone of the business is solid, clients are being measured in their approach, but the year-end period will be key to delivering for all marketers and they are relying on partners that have the tools, insights, and capabilities to connect with consumers across channels and drive desired business outcomes.
 We remain cautious on Europe although our plans did not factor in growth in that region. The Brazilian and Chinese economies have been challenged, although our operations in those regions continue to deliver results.
 The new business pipeline is solid. Year to date we continue to be net new business positive, and in fact near the top of the new business lead tables. The significant number of media pictures continue and it bears noting that we have been performing well to date with a number of headline wins: notably UM's wins of the Coca-Cola media review, J&amp;J's US media buying and planning accounts, as well as CVS and McCormick, which was won in collaboration with R/GA. Those are reflection of the cutting edge offerings we have within Mediabrands. In terms of strategic media thinkers, outstanding digital and data platforms, and the scale and expertise to deliver buying efficiency to some of the world's largest and most demanding clients.
 An additional point that is worth repeating when it comes to emerging media is that we do not take ownership of digital media but resale to clients. So our strong organic growth does not reflect the growth of digital media arbitrage revenue that you are seeing among some of our peers who take principal positions and resell owned inventory to clients at a margin. We continue to believe that our role as an agnostic consultant is key and allows us to provide clients with the recommendations and services that are best for their business.
 We also remain committed to the highest standard of transparency, an area in which we have been a leader for some time. This continues to gain in important as the world of digital media is beset by challenges surrounding viewability and other issues that make it imperative that we serve as wholly objective partners to our clients.
 McCann continues to post strong performance with outstanding creative work on its major multinationals and notable local market wins in the UK, Australia and India. We are seeing great collaboration within world group and this cross selling and integration is helping them win new accounts, as well as increase their share wallet with existing clients. The digital and healthcare units within McCann had strong performance. In the healthcare space it was good to see that McCann Health and FCB Health led us to outstanding performance at the medical marketing and media competition, where we vested the other holding companies in terms of awards won.
 Progress at FCB continues. The agency is consistently appearing on pitch lists with notable recent wins with Lincoln Financial by the New York office, BMO Harris Bank by the Toronto office, new work from Coke at FCB in South Africa and strong momentum at Inferno FCB in London. FCB Health remains a powerhouse in its field in the agency's shopper marketing operation. FCB Red is also a very strong resource.
 At CMG our award-winning public relations Weber Shandwick and Golin continue to gain market share. Beyond digital where both firms have been in the forefront of their discipline. They are also moving into content marketing and upstream to more strategic and integrated opportunities. We are well-positioned here, and we are also seeing good progress from our sports and entertainment and experiential businesses, as well as continuing improvement in the branding sector.
 Focus on Mullen Lowe during the quarter was squarely on merger integration and setting the stage for a successful 2016 and beyond. The agency's senior global leadership recently met to decide on and articulate the network's market position, strategy, and brand identity. This will include both agencies long-standing commitment to creative excellence. Mullen's contemporary hyper bundled approach and Lowe's deep knowledge of dynamic international markets. It's a combination that is working for many leading clients, including Unilever and we look forward to seeing it build positive momentum in the marketplace.
 Our US independence continued to be a source of strength for Interpublic. Deutsche is an example of the benefits of combining big creative ideas with a fully integrated suite of digital capabilities. The marketing agency Hill Holliday and Carmichael Lynch are other agencies that deliver with this model and provide us with a range of options that can meet the needs of the domestic clients.
 In terms of digital, our offerings are consistently outstanding, whether it be our social media capabilities at Weber and Golin, Cadreon and AMP within Mediabrands, or the integrated digital capabilities at all of our brand agencies. MRM is a top-tier digital network and the close collaboration we're seeing before them and McCann is elevating the overall world group offering, just as the integration of Profero and Mediahub are significantly strengthening Mullen Lowe's go to market positioning.
 We are also fortunate to have R/GA, the undisputed leader in digital- and technology-enabled marketing that continue to win business and awards, as well as innovate with programs such as the R/GA accelerators that give us a line of sight into terrific startups with ideas and technology that will play a role in shaping the future of communications and consumer experience. Our current accelerator is taking place in Los Angeles in collaboration with the LA Dodgers and the participating companies span every aspect of connected sport, from athlete training to venue management to new social channels in which consumers can share their passion for sports.
 Huge is another digital specialist that has performed exceptionally well for us. Beyond its industry-leading strategic consulting, design, and UX practices, the agency recently made news when it opened a coffee shop in its Atlanta office to serve as a real-time lab in which we will develop and test digital retail innovations for both current and prospective clients. For us at Interpublic the new business of advertising means that we encourage ambitious change across the entire organization. By providing access to emerging and transformative technologies we develop programs that help us attract talent and create work that puts the user experience first. All in the service of our clients.
 Looking to the balance of this year, we stayed diligent on cost so as to ensure that we can deliver on our margin commitment. There are geographic markets that we will need to monitor, but performance for the first nine months has been very strong and positions us well for a strong close to the full year. As mentioned in my initial remarks, we believe that given our performance to date the appropriate organic revenue growth targets for the new year is in excess of 5% and that we are on track to deliver 100 basis points of operating margin improvement at the end of our initial target for the year -- at the high end for of our initial target.
 Moving forward, we are therefore closer to achieving our previously stated goal of 13%. Combined with our company's financial strength and robust return of capital, which have and will continue to be a source of significant value creation, this will allow us to further enhance shareholder value.
 With that I would like to thank you for your time and continued support and open the call up to questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. We will now begin the question and answer session.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions)
 Alexia Quadrani of JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alexia Quadrani,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
 My first question for Michael: you continue to show such impressive organic revenue growth with some of the highest organic growth this quarter I can remember maybe in several years now, even on difficult comps. Can you provide a bit more color on what's causing this incremental change? Is it the more your agencies are doing from very well? Is it that you've got tailwind from a lot of new business you have won? Is it the overall macroenvironment? Is it client budgets? Any color that can point to what's giving you, even incrementally stronger in organic growth?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you Alexia. All of the above.
 Look, none of this is by accident. We have started on this journey by clearly investing in talent. And I think what you're seeing right now is the fact that the talent that we've embedded within all of our organizations is really shining in terms of what clients are looking for in terms of moving the needle with their business. But creative talent and overall talent needs tools and resources within the organization to make sure we can deliver on that. So we've invested in all of these tools and resources throughout the Company. And finally, we really are a client centric environment so everyone is focusing on the needs of the clients, and therefore we are focusing on what we can bring to the resources within IPG to the client to meet those needs.
 We are seeing success in our open architecture model, where if you look at the business wins, all of our agencies are aware of the fact that if their particular disciplines need other resources from IPG they raise their hand and we bring the additional IPG resources to the table. And frankly we are getting a reputation in the marketplace, appropriately, that we do this very well and we really focus on the needs of the clients versus our own silos. And I think the new business wins that we're seeing, as well as the embedded growth we're seeing in our existing client base, really is indicative of the fact that all of the IPG resources are available to move the needle with our client and we are executing against that.
 But in the end, it takes people and belief by those people that they have a huge resource base behind them. And the other thing which I particularly like is when I participate in a lot of these pitches, what we see in the room are cross disciplines either from within the agencies or outside IPG and it's not uncommon for the client to come up to me and say, you know I didn't even realize which individuals were from which discipline. And that's really what clients are looking for in their resources. So I'm particularly proud of all of our agencies, whether it be our traditional agencies, our digital agencies, our marketing services, PR. I mean across the board we are all doing quite well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alexia Quadrani,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just a follow-up if I can on profitability. I know you don't discuss margins as, say, by region. But maybe you can talk just generally, you've seen a couple of, you know -- a long period now where you've seen a lot more stability in your European operations. Are you seeing maybe better profitability in that area now that you've seen stability for a while, or markets such as Germany which are still weak, really pulling it down for you?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well clearly we're seeing better profitability. That doesn't mean better is where we want to be. I mean it's always been a challenge for profitability in Europe for us. We've taken a lot of actions, we have repositioned assets, we've brought in new management, we've reduced layers of people, and it's a very competitive market. And it's great to see us on the positive side for the nine months. As I said in my remarks, we're not counting on a bigger recovery. But the profitability side of it is moving forward. But it's still not at the levels we want it to be. So we've got more work to do in continental Europe. But we have made great strides towards that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alexia Quadrani,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Janedis of Jefferies LLC
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Janedis,  Jefferies LLC - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Michael, there's been a lot of talk in the market recently about the viability of the agency model in offerings and with all recent pitches have you seen a change in the groups you are competing against? And for the business you've won are there pieces of the business that you would typically work on that [once you] maybe nontraditional players?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, yes, I -- the viability of the model -- it's funny, I gave a talk at IAB and I put up my favorite slide, which is a quote that says the agency business is going to be disintermediated and is basically doomed and then I go to the next slide and it's a quote in 1975.
 So I mean there are always people out there saying that the competitors in other disciplines whether it be Ad-tech or smaller agencies. In the end we have the resources and capabilities that can compete with any resource out there. And frankly when we don't have it, yes, we use outside parties, we work well with them. It's incumbent upon us to know what we do well and what we don't do well. That's what this whole concept of open architecture is all about, John. And that is we're looking at the client first and if we don't have a resource internally, and when I say internally I mean within IPG, it's not uncommon for us to use outside resources to help us.
 And frankly that's what shows clients that we are thinking of them versus ourselves and yet we end up dealing with nontraditional people whether it be on the Ad-tech side. Even in some of the production, we don't like it, but even some of the production facilities that clients request us to use, you know, we have to be in a world now where collaboration works. And the collaboration starts with us, and if it's not within our organization we have to be able to collaborate with other parties our clients are happy with.
 We are able to do all of that and sometimes working with the third parties turns out to be a lot smoother than sometimes working with ourselves, which is a shame on us, but that's the reality of the world out there. The world is changing and our model has to change with us, and I think that's one of the things you're seeing why we're being successful in that we are not wedded to the silo mentality of the past. We have to collaborate. We have to collaborate within IPG, and we have to collaborate outside of IPG with other parties.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Janedis,  Jefferies LLC - Analyst   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay thanks and then just separately as you mentioned you picked up some good wins since your last call and also year-to-date. Can you update us on any potential talent on organic as they roll in. Maybe for either the balance of the year or into next year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well I said we are net new business positive. So by definition if we're net new business positive we are going to move into the year with tailwinds. But we still have the fourth quarter to go. The fourth quarter is our biggest quarter. It's project-based, so we're waiting to see how that comes in. We have a number of reviews still out there. It's unlikely that those reviews will impact 2015, so it will affect 2016 numbers, and we are cautiously optimistic on those reviews that we've had.
 The fact that we've been successful on the media reviews in particular, obviously we're feeling comfortable going into the year finals of some of the media pitches that are out there. But you never know what these pitches but we're very comfortable with how we are positioned in them. So if we are successful with those, or at least some of those, we'll certainly go in to 2016 with tailwinds.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Janedis,  Jefferies LLC - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks so much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Bank of RBC Capital Markets
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Bank,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. First off, Michael, whatever's in the Kool-Aid over there you can feel free to sprinkle it on the rest of the S&amp;P 500 and we will be much happier.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are beginning to feel a little bit like Dan Murphy but -- (laughing)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Bank,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, you're seeing the ball really well right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Exactly, David, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Bank,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But on a more serious note, we are -- I think it is a bit of a follow-up to a couple of questions before, but it's early days lots of headlines but early days on some longer-term changes that I think we as outsiders are trying to understand about how the business is changing you know programmatically, for instance. We look at these things and we see things that appear to be able to be done mechanically more efficiently and we worry that, you know, maybe that takes some value out of the chain that you would be paid for and I think on the flipside -- and we can see headlines about that. What we don't often see headlines about are, you know, what is the traction that you are getting on your skill set in helping clients leverage off these mechanical solutions? Right? Like what is the counterbalance to growing fees on integrating these third-party and your own party products and frankly just helping clients navigate how to use these mechanical solutions. Can you talk about how you're seeing that so far? Is there a financial impact yet? How do you help us understand it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You know I think the key to making a success out of that, there's no question that there's a trend there and we can discuss all sorts of reasons why that trend is there. But our job is to work with our clients. It's interesting I was just talking to our folks on a pitch that we just had this week and there we had a presentation on Cadreon and Programmatic. Obviously, that's a very strong asset of IPG. It's growing tremendously both in the marketplace and competitively. And yet the client is considering taking that inside.
 So as part of the pitch, we present ideas and our people from Cadreon present what we are doing and you see the client sitting there saying, oh my goodness. How come we didn't think of that and how come we didn't think if this. So, yes, we work with our clients who are intending to bring some of it inside. In the end, we act as integrators. Our job, and I've always said this, confusion is good for us, and the reason it's good for us is we get paid to help make sense out of all of this.
 And if clients are looking to us to help them do this, we have to be able to respond. And if it means helping them bring it inside, that's okay. But they are still going to need the current thinking in the investments that we make in these tools that clients just are not a position to make. And frankly the talent that we are able to recruit in that environment is so different than the talent that you can recruit internally on a siloed basis. So, yes, clients are bringing it in. It's not a threat, it's just another tool that clients have that they want us to work with in the overall integrated offering. And we have to be able to do that.
 You know the history of our industry is when clients bring things internally a lot of times it comes back. And the reason for it is the ability to recruit talent, as well as to keep investing in the tools and resources that you need to be current. So, yes, it's a phenomenon there's no question about it and clients are trying to do it internally, but I think they'll find in the long-term that we still have a role to play here in helping them accomplish what they're looking for, but at the same time using the tools and resources that we have that they are not capable of developing.
 So we don't fight it, we actually help them do it. And that's -- you know again that's one piece of the puzzle. I mean again if there's a relationship with the client, it has to be broad and it has to be seen as that we are in a partnership with the client. And we have all of these different resources that we bring to the table. And if the client feels comfortable asking us to help them, we don't view it as them taking business away from us, it's part of what our role is. And we have to build it into our model. But it's a reality, but it's been a reality for years in this industry and it just changes different forms.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Bank,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Stabler from Wells Fargo Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Stabler,  Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Thanks for taking the question.
 Actually I want to follow on yet again on John and David. Questions here, Michael, so with regard to the reviews, we see headlines out there sometimes from large clients suggesting that they are going to use the review process to drive down there aggregate fees, right. Just wondering if you could comment on that?
 The idea that coming out of this process as the dust settles, that the total fee envelope available to all of you is smaller and I guess the other piece of this that doesn't get talked about as much is the situations where the scope of work actually expands. So I am wondering if you could talk a little bit about the first part and then what kind of expansion might you see as you get into these reviews where, who knows, fees could actually go up. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, yes, no, I mean, look, any review that takes place clearly has a view towards what they call efficiencies. Efficiencies obviously means fee reductions and clients for generations have been looking for more for less. So it's something we're very much used to and it puts the burden on us to be more efficient, but yet we have to be able to meet the needs of the clients. And, yes, that presents problems in terms of us maintaining margin. But again, remember this is only one piece of the puzzle.
 When we talk about margins it's aggregate margins in all of the different disciplines and resources. And sure on some basic contract work that we have in scope margins maybe a little bit less than they may have been before. But in the end, it's our opportunity and clients expect it for us to be able to bring in new ideas that help them move the needle and that's what is called -- known as out of scope work and out of scope work is something that typically we get higher margins on. That's the way our business works and clients know that. But first they have to start with a line in the sand.
 So these reviews establish a line in the sand in terms of scope of work and fees that will be available and we have to work within that model. And it's incumbent upon us to make sure that the additional work that we do and clients understand that if it's out of scope they have to pay for it and we typically make better margins on the out of scope work. That's not a secret in our industry and clients know it.
 And the other part of it is this is a value-based environment. And if we can show that we are moving the needle and clients value the type -- the ideas that we are bringing to them and the fact that it's in fact proving that results that we believe it can do, clients have incentive fees with us, there are performance-based contracts that we have on -- particularly on the media side of the business.
 So there are vehicles that we have to develop opportunities for us to enhance margins. And that's the way the business is and so we don't view procurement as a bad word, we don't view as these reviews as necessarily being only with a view towards fee reductions. The other reason these reviews are taking place is because they want to see if they're getting best in class offerings. And frankly if I was a client, I would be asking the same thing.
 So we approach these reviews even when we're incumbent as an opportunity to show clients and future clients what we can bring to the table, what resources we have, and how we can work differently with them to move the needle. You know what's interesting is the incumbents usually start out as, why haven't you brought this to us before?
 So therefore if you look at the history of reviews incumbents generally don't do well. But when you really drill down on it, incumbents have been dealing within a certain playbook both with the client and ourselves. These reviews open up a different playbook. And that means there's got to be change both on the client's side, as well as our side. And I see that's what's happening in a number of these reviews.
 Clients are recognizing that their approach isn't necessarily the right approach, and they're willing to think of a different approach that we can bring to the table. And that means opportunity. Every time we get to work with our clients and show what we can do it presents opportunities for us across the board. So, that's how we approach it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Stabler,  Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks Michael.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne from Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Good morning. I guess I have to be the guy, Michael, that asks about the ANA stuff.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I thought I was going for call without it, Ben.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll take the bullet. But, now that -- it was announced yesterday, generally what we thought was going to happen. From where you sit when you look at who they've hired and everything you know about the process, do you expect any impact on Interpublic Group or, you know, what from your perspective should we be looking for from this process, if anything?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You know it's not a surprise to anybody so I don't know why people all of a sudden are shocked and so on. The ANA has been talking about this. The four A's has been talking about it. Everybody's been talking about it. So the fact that the ANA hired two firms to do it, to help them with it is not a surprise to us at all. Obviously we have dealt with these firms before not so much the [Kroll] but as much as the other one, but we've been talking about transparency. It started with us frankly 10 years ago, maybe it's 11 now, time flies you're having good time, on this whole issue of rebates, and so this is nothing that we are afraid of. We've been very clear on rebate issues for ten years now.
 It's in all of our contracts, we welcome, in fact in all these reviews, we have audit capabilities from our clients to come in and review this, so this isn't new for us. And it's part of the verification and audit that we have within our own systems. Clients are welcome to come in and in fact we do share with them results from that and some of them -- one of the firms that is doing this actually we worked with in the past. So this isn't really nothing new for our industry. Any type of review like this, you know, everyone raises questions of what they're going to find. It's unfortunate that the headlines particularly in Europe have made it look like this is a criminal investigation you know.
 The last I looked ANA doesn't have the ability to subpoena. And if you read these headlines you would think that's what was going on. That's not what's going on, it's a look into the practices within an industry. That's nothing new. This is an industry organization making sure that their constituents are comfortable with what's going on in the practice. And you know we've been dealing with this all along. So from an IPG perspective, we're very comfortable on rebate transparency, we're very comfortable on contractual transparency. We have it in all of our contracts and verification and review is part of our process. There's nothing in any of that that concerns us.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's very helpful. Thank you.
 I just wanted to follow up on the digital buying front, which I know is a part of your business; not all of your business but one that gets a lot of focus. You know what you've done with Cadreon -- can you talk about how much you've been able to get all of your different agencies to leverage that platform when they buy media or do you still have certain pockets of your organization that are doing it on their own? It seems like a pretty complex organizational challenge to have sort of a centralized platform. But I am imagining as you go through these reviews it's just a huge part of the conversation. So maybe you could just talk about it from a management perspective how you guys are set up and how it's working.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, you know, look, the key to this is obviously our multinational clients that go through Mediabrands. They're clearly using Cadreon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And that's part of their business model. We have a number of agencies that do their own buying that have their own capabilities, and that's fine. But frankly from a business management point of view, we always argue, whenever we have the operating reviews of our businesses, and they talk about it, they all think they have a better model. And if their better model is working that's terrific, but it seems that the efficiencies that can be gotten by dealing from with a Mediabrands' platform in terms of current thinking and resources just as compelling and frankly I wish some of our agencies would use it more but that -- certainly the bulk of our media buying is going through that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. And then I just have -- go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There's always opportunities for more, but clearly the bulk of it is going through Cadreon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just have one last one for Frank. Totally different topic. I think you had in the last year about $1.3 billion of NOLs, and I think a lot of that stuff is overseas. As you create more profitability, particularly in Europe, can you access those more rapidly, which, of course increases the value of those NOLs? Just any color on how we think about cash taxes as the business continues to do so well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frank Mergenthaler,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're right, Ben. Most NOLs are in Europe for the most part. So an increased profitability in Europe is helpful in accessing those NOLs. Our cash tax rate this year we're seeing is going to be 27/28%. It was high teens to low 20s for the last three years but we've burned through all of our US NOLs where most -- a lot of our profitability is.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, the --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will weigh in a little bit on that, Frank. I am a tax guy. Some of these --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I apologize for not directing it to the right guy.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frank Mergenthaler,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 He's on a roll, Ben. Keep going.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I am on a roll, Ben. You know, some of these NOLs in these countries are client -- country centric. It's not just Europe. Okay?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The additional challenge is generating profitability within those countries. And obviously we get involved in tax planning in terms of where revenue is being generated. So that's why we have a great tax department who is responsible for making sure that our contracts are reflecting that and we are optimize -- what we call optimizing using our NOLs and we are very focused on doing that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ben Swinburne,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Salmon from BMO Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Salmon,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning everyone.
 Michael, could you talk a little bit about the hiring of Simon Bond. I know he was the new business champion over at BDO. I'm just curious about the role being at the holding company level. Is it largely still focused on new business or is there a little bit more responsibility around coordinating amongst the agencies a little bit thinking of your comments earlier about the success of an open architecture, is it to help facilitate that a little bit as well too?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh absolutely. Look, we already have some very talented people within IPG who work on these multinational open architectural client situations where they are working with the units themselves, whether it be FCB, whether it be McCann, whether it be Lowe, and it's their responsibility to work with the people within these agencies to make sure that the needs of the clients are being met with all of the resources of IPG. We were fortunate to have an opportunity to recruit Simon to our organization and clearly his responsibility will be both on the new business side, but also on these open architecture pitches.
 More and more these RFPs are coming into the holding company. They're coming directly to me actually, and sometimes -- which is why I have to look at my emails every day. But it really comes in to the holding company and they are saying, you tell us which is the best way you want to approach this RFP. So someone like Simon with his vast experience in new business and client focus and frankly his knowledge of the consulting industry and the relationships he has is a tremendous asset for us and frankly Simon's already been involved with a number of our agencies' pitches that are going on right now. And he's a resource, you know, and we're from the home office and we are here to help.
 And some of our agencies have already tapped into Simon to help him in terms of their pitch. He's fantastic in terms of new business pitches and he has actually gone in and helped these agencies and frankly we had a couple of wins that he helped in terms of the presentations. So he's -- the fact that we were able to recruit Simon is an indication to me that this whole notion of open architecture is one that is resonating in the industry and our reputation for being a holding company that collaborates with all of the agencies within the holding company is real, and I think his presence along with the other individuals within IPG, whether it be Peter or Terry. They all work very closely with our agencies. And they know that they are there to be helpful to our agencies. The pitches themselves are coming in different forms and we have to be able to respond to the needs of the clients.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Salmon,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Did Simon ask you to raise that question?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Nolan from Macquarie.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Nolan,  Macquarie Research Equities - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Thanks for taking the question.
 Taking a very high level view IPG has come a long, long, long way since you both have been there. And it seems to me, if I may be so bold, you are probably in what I would say the eighth inning of your career, maybe in the top of the ninth. Correct me if you think that's too optimistic. You do have some margin to recover yet.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Nolan,  Macquarie Research Equities - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You've see still some relatively high salary and service numbers. You mentioned Europe requiring some work to get back to more better profitability. I just wonder with all of this put together what do you think are the last steps that need to be taken to really get you to that 13% target? Or to just -- how do you think about really getting through that final hurdle if that's the right way to think about it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we're constantly thinking about how to get to that hurdle because that's obviously a main objective for all of us. We are well on our way and you're right. Call it the eighth, ninth inning whatever you want. We are making great progress and it's clearly within our sights to accomplish that. So we're feeling pretty positive about that.
 Look, we're a variable cost model. Our biggest variable cost is SRS. It's not a secret we said what we have to do is focus on that and you can focus on that by generating revenue, which is what we've been doing. And keeping an eye on those cost pressures and the SRS. So we've done a great job on O&amp;G and that's showing the improvement even in the third quarter. We see an improvement there.
 We have seen leverage. We have seen at least 50 basis points and if you work through the pass-throughs, it's really 80 basis points this quarter in terms of leverage on SRS. So we're very focused on it and we just have to continue to do that and we see that there's still opportunity to do it and that's how we are going to get there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frank Mergenthaler,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim, it's probably more agency specific now than it is IPG specific. As we look to the last inning or inning and a half, it's getting those certain agencies that aren't where they need profitability wise to cross the goal line.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And look let's face it we use incentives within our -- our agency goals are focused on margin improvement and they know that the best way to get margin improvement is to keep an eye on their SRS ratio. So it's both monitored, as Frank said, from the agencies, as well as from our reviews at the holding company. So you know this isn't rocket science, this business, and we're very comfortable in our ability to manage that. I think we've proven that you know we know how to manage that.
 You know we can do this and I have said this before, we can get there tomorrow, but you know part of this is making sure we have the talent and resources to generate growth. So on a longer-term basis, had we not had the talent and resources that we had within all of our different agencies, we wouldn't be delivering the results that you're seeing right now.
 So if we starve the pipeline of people and got our SRS ratios in line quicker, yes we may achieve our goal, but our long-term viability would be adversely affected. I kind of like the way we're doing it now. If you're looking at 80 to 100 basis point margin improvement you know at clips along the way you know we're going to get there. We just -- we are not going to get there tomorrow and it would be silly for us to shoot ourselves in the foot and do something dramatic that would get us there.
 Just look at the write off that we are having. We are focusing on unprofitable businesses that are in geographic locations that aren't necessary that are a drag on our P&amp;L. And so this time the $38 million is 4 to 5 locations in areas that we don't have to be. They were dilutive and we either sold them or closed them. And that's how we get there. We're constantly looking at those types of opportunities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Nolan,  Macquarie Research Equities - Analyst   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wasn't at all suggesting you should accelerate the process and get to 13% tomorrow. It was more to say 100 basis points margin improvement this year is great. If the market holds and you do well and you have new account wins, maybe that's a similar target for next year, and then you're getting there already. I would just wonder and I think you've answered, you've done a lot of work with the individual agencies over the years. Is it really just a matter of like finding some last bits to clear out, winning some business, having the scale, and just letting the operating leverage takeover. Is that the way to think of it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I mean, that's it. It's like everything else its execution and with the changes we've made across all of the networks in both people and structure; we put Mullen and Lowe together this past year. You know, I am very comfortable with our leadership across the board. We brought Henry in to run Mediabrands. Alex to run Lowe and Mullen, and obviously Harris and Carter are doing great jobs. So I'm very comfortable with our leadership and am very confident that we will get to objectives.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Nolan,  Macquarie Research Equities - Analyst   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great job. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We do not have further questions on queue. Speakers you may proceed.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Roth,  The Interpublic Group of Companies, Inc. - Chairman &amp;  CEO   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I thank you all for participating. I look forward to our next call, which will report our year-end results. Have great holidays. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This concludes today's conference. You may disconnect at this time.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q3 2015 Interpublic Group of Companies Inc Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>NEW YORK</city>
  <companyName>Interpublic Group of Companies Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>IPG</companyTicker>
  <startDate>21-Oct-15 12:30pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>87867</companyId>
  <CUSIP>460690100</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2466321</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US4606901001</ISIN>
</Event>