<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="4865076" lastUpdate="Thursday, July 19, 2012 at 10:06:56pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="4865076.F" expirationDate="Thursday, July 19, 2012 at 3:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of JCI^I16 earnings conference call or presentation 19-Jul-12 3:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q3 2012 Johnson Controls Earnings Conference Call

MILWAUKEE Jul 19, 2012 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Johnson Controls Inc earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, July 19, 2012 at 3:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Glen Ponczak
      Johnson Controls, Inc. - Director, IR
   *  Steve Roell
      Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO
   *  Bruce McDonald
      Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Chris Ceraso
      Credit Suisse - Analyst
   *  Brian Johnson
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Ravi Shanker
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Peter Nesvold
      Jefferies &amp; Company - Analyst
   *  Pat Nolan
      Deutsche Bank - Analyst
   *  Rich Kwas
      Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst
   *  Daunte Tresta
      Lazard Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Joseph Stack
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Welcome and thank you for standing by. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode.
 During the question-and-answer session (Operator Instructions). Today's conference is being recorded. Should you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.
 Now I will turn the meeting over to Vice Presidents Glen Ponczak. Sir, you may begin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Director, IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Pat. Good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us.
 Before we begin the call today I would like to remind you that Johnson Controls will make forward-looking statements in this presentation pertaining to its financial results for fiscal 2012 and beyond that are based on preliminary data and are subject to risks and uncertainties. All statements other than statements of historical fact are statements that are or could be deemed forward-looking statements, including terms such as outlook, expectations, estimates, and forecasts.
 For those statements the Company cautions that numerous important factors, such as automotive vehicle production levels, (technical difficulty) schedules, energy and commodity prices, the strength of the US or other economies, currency exchange rates, cancellation of or changes to commercial contracts, changes in timing or levels of investments in commercial buildings, as well as other factors discussed in Item 1A of Part 1 of the Company's most recent Form 10-K filing, which was filed November 22, 2011, could affect the Company's actual results and could cause actual consolidated results to differ materially from those expressed in any forward-looking statement made by or on behalf of the Company.
 In a few moments I will turn it over to Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Steve Roell, who will give us an overview of the quarter and some of the market conditions. After that Bruce McDonald, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial officer, will do a more in-depth review of the business results and provide an overview of the financial performance in the quarter. That will be followed by questions and answers, and we will end at the top of the hour.
 With that I will turn it over to Steve.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Glen. Good morning and thank you for joining us on the call.
 This morning in our third fiscal quarter results we reported that earnings were up 15%, record levels for the period. I just want to start by expressing my appreciation to the JCI employees that listen to this broadcast for their contributions to our results. But I also want to quickly acknowledge that we fell short of the guidance that we provided on the call just three months ago, and we will go through some of the details that led to that.
 But during the quarter there were many times where we were confident in our ability to achieve that 20% growth that we had projected, but ultimately the slowdown in the European market and the escalation of lead costs in our Power Solutions business were just too much to overcome. And I guess I would just as a comment here tell you that the shortfall from the guidance we provided to you we could easily explain just simply by the Power Solutions business shortfall in lead. And I will explain to you what that is in just a second.
 If we look at the numbers in terms of the results, sales of $10.6 billion were slightly higher than last year. If we adjust for foreign exchange, our growth was 7% year over year. As the slide indicates that impact from -- the impact of pure dollars was about $515 million just due to FX.
 Our segment income increased 14% to $615 million. That yielded net income of $466 million, a 15% increase. These are all non-GAAP numbers. We think these are the more accurate numbers to look at. EPS $0.64 per share. You can see how that compared to the $0.56 a year ago.
 Now let me turn to the market conditions that are impacting our business and how they are likely to affect our upcoming quarter.
 In general, I guess I would make the statement that we have seen demand slow across several of our industries and geographic markets. Clearly, the one exception has been the North American auto market where production was up 27% in the third quarter. But I think even that good news was tempered by the most recent outlook for the current quarter, our fourth fiscal quarter, where production growth is expected to slow to about 4%.
 The European market, auto market in the quarter continued to soften with industry sales declining 5% and that pressure, as you can imagine, is expected to continue.
 Turning to the building side, non-residential building margins are not recovering at the rate that we had originally anticipated and we have had to align our strategy and cost structure accordingly. I think we have talked about that throughout the fiscal year. I think Dave and his team have done a great job of doing that as evidenced by their improvement this quarter.
 But just turning back to the industry, domestic growth in the first nine months for us has really been concentrated in state, local, and federal government sectors, as well as the commercial buildings, airports, and life science. The institutional sector of education and healthcare, where we have a very strong presence, has declined.
 I know some of you that follow the building market are probably familiar with the Dodge Report. It has projected that the institutional market will contract 10% in calendar 2012. Again, those of you that also follow that sector recognize that the Architectural Billings Index has stagnated the last three months after being up five months prior to that.
 International building markets; we continue to see good growth in Asia and the Middle East. Western Europe remains depressed, particularly in Southern Europe, and I think you all understand what is happening there.
 I want to go back now and explain to you what we saw in the Power Solutions business relative to lead. We normally don't talk about lead; we haven't had to talk about junk batteries, again, for a long time. We saw something that was very uncharacteristic, we haven't experienced in some time, and that is just the lack of retail activity in the aftermarket where we are dependent upon collecting what we call junk batteries or cores.
 Now we need those cores and junk to be able to recycle those to produce new batteries and provide those to our [tollers] and also to supply our smelters. That demand, or I should say the lack at retail, which has been really uncharacteristic across the board in North America, has resulted in a shortage of cores. We haven't seen that before. And as a result, we had to go through and actually pay up to get the cores we needed to meet our tolling arrangements as well as to start up our smelter operations.
 I am going to tell you that year over year that impact is roughly $40 million, so if you put a dollar or a percent share on that that will explain almost the entire shortfall that we didn't expect coming into the period.
 It is a timing issue. We know the cores will come. We know that as soon as retail picks back up we will see that in the fall and in winter, so we expect that not to continue, extend beyond the current quarter. We are seeing it continue in the month of July and that is part of our concern about the fourth-quarter forecast.
 But I wanted to just highlight that that issue of buying cores at the prices we had to pay was a $40 million decline in earnings year over year in that segment. And that really was not expected, again, in our forecast when we provided you the guidance back in April.
 There certainly are a number of our businesses that are performing exceptionally well. Most notably, were the five business categories that comprise our Building Efficiency segment, where each of them achieved double-digit earning increases. In total that segment, as you saw, was up -- income was up 28%. We believe we are gaining share by virtue of the backlog growth that we saw in the orders that we had this quarter.
 I am mostly encouraged by the bidding activity. We have talked oftentimes about our pipeline and I continue to see that pipeline improving, which may be contrary than what you would expect. And I even see it improving in some of these institutional sectors that we monitor.
 I also expect Building Efficiency to show margin improvement again in the fourth quarter. We have guided that all year that we said it would be the second half. I think you saw it happen in a big way in Q3.
 Contrary to what you are hearing from some other markets and industries regarding China, I would have to tell you that China is performing -- our markets there are performing very consistent with what we expect (technical difficulty) as we got coming into the fiscal year (inaudible) around Building Efficiency and Automotive Experience. Bruce will highlight some of the increases we had, but at this point in time we see the China market performing and holding up well for us.
 In the near term, higher temperatures are driving HVAC service demand. That did not happen in June; we were hoping to see some of that in July and August. We are seeing the shortening battery life certainly from the higher temps which will bode well for us in the upcoming year, and certainly is supporting our growth in the residential air-conditioning markets, which again Bruce will highlight for you.
 In recognition of some of the market conditions, we opted to take a $52 million restructuring charge in Q3, primarily to reduce our staffing in Europe in Building Efficiency and Automotive. We are currently planning to take further action in Q4. Again, a lot of that, or a high proportion of it, is tied to what we see in the European market softening and the view that that market is going to remain soft in the midterm.
 The uncertainty we faced has basically caused us in Q4 to lower our earnings guidance to the zero to 5% growth. The factors that prompted us to change our projections come from the previous guidance are as follows.
 First would be the weaker battery demand early in the quarter and the higher lead cost. I mentioned to you that what we saw in Q3 we have seen continue in the month of July. We are seeing increasing weakness in our European businesses. It is difficult to get improvement in the automotive metals business in Q4 because of the shutdown period and lower production levels.
 In general, I think we are just to the point where we are seeing things like commercial negotiations extend longer in automotive. So there is just a number of factors. We looked at those and said it is time for us just to go back and lets be a little more conservative. If they come fine, but we are having difficulty forecasting the timing of some of these issues.
 So we thought it best just to lower the guidance and we will see, but I do want to come back and also highlight our midterm and long-term views. The next slide really covers that and I want to just go through that real quickly with you.
 The things we have talked about in the past that drive our stock and drive our performance are still intact. We have a strong position in SLI batteries. We have the ability to drive the higher margins. We talked about the vertical integration investments we are making. Again, those are all on track and we believe that they will bode well for us in 2013 and 2014.
 The investments we are making in EGN battery technology to support our customer demand for start-stop vehicles continues to gain momentum. We are well positioned and market leaders in the emerging markets in all three of our businesses. Higher automotive margins [would be our] (inaudible) metal strategy. We believe that that is still a core strategy and key to us as we drive to a core product portfolio and standardization.
 Finally, building efficiency with its market share gains through our ability to help our customers improve energy efficiency and reduce greenhouse gas footprints. So those are, again, the factors we have talked to you about that are at the core of Johnson Controls and our long-term strategy and value, and we believe those are all intact. We just have to deal with some of the headwinds in the near term.
 So with that I am going to have Bruce go through and highlight some of the third quarter by business results.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks, Steve. Good morning. As you will note in our press release, we did have a couple of non-operational items this share and last year. Let me just talk on those.
 So for this here they netted to a charge of about $0.03; as Steve indicated in his comments, some $52 million of restructuring charges. And we also had some non-recurring tax benefits of $22 million, which reflect valuation allowance releases in certain foreign jurisdictions associated with improved levels of profitability.
 In the year-ago quarter you will recall we had a $0.04 charge associated with the acquisition of KEIPER, and so as I really talk through the three business segments here I am going to exclude these items from my comments.
 So starting off with Building Efficiency, I would say overall superb quarter here, especially when we look at the state of the major markets that they participate in. Sales were down 2%. If you back out foreign exchange, we are actually up about 1%.
 We saw good revenue growth in both GWS, which was up 7%, and Asia, up 7%. Again, those numbers are without foreign exchange. Although this was largely offset with softness in Latin America, Europe, and the Middle East.
 In aggregate, if you look at our North American businesses, I mean I am talking about our systems and services business that focus on the non-residential markets, we were down about 2% in the quarter.
 Residential was a bright spot for us. That is one of our higher margin businesses and you can see on our slide we have talked about the fact that our revenue was up 24%. On a unit shipments basis we are up about 20%.
 I guess what I would note, if you look at the mix within our residential business, what you are seeing is the sales of the lower efficiency-type products are doing exceptionally well. If you look at the higher end, the energy efficiency furnaces and air conditioners, those volumes are comparable to year-ago levels. So really seeing, I guess, a trading down phenomenon in the residential space. But nonetheless, it is good to see the volume start to finally improve after several years of sluggish demand there.
 Look at the segment income, up 28% at $264 million. If you look at our margins here, we are up about 160 basis points to 6.9%. I know Steve mentioned in his comments all five of the business segments within Building Efficiency reported double-digit margin improvements with [GWS] and North America kind of leading the way here, up 86% and 49%, respectively.
 To really look at what the drivers were there we saw better labor utilization of our service workforce, we started to see the benefits of some of the technology investments that we have made in our North American service business, and also several of the restructuring initiatives that we have taken over the last few quarters paid dividends for us in the third quarter here.
 Turning to Power Solutions, we had a tough quarter, as Steve mentioned in his remarks, really reflecting the weak demand outlook, particularly here in North America. We looked at our point-of-sale data from our customers and we are seeing our sales to our customers are down 2% or 3%. What we are seeing at point-of-sale, unfortunately, here is volumes being down 8% to 10%, particularly in May and June and as we start into July here.
 So we have got a little bit of an inventory buildup in the channel, the aftermarket retail channels here in North America. And that combined with the lead are two factors that are going to carry over here in the fourth quarter, so we are hoping that the inventory bulge kind of blows through here in the fourth quarter. The lead issue is a one quarter phenomenon, so we hope we get back into Q1 of 2013 more in balance here.
 Look at the revenues, down 2% -- or sorry, up 2%, excluding foreign currency. Unit shipments had a good performance in the OE side. North America really leading the way, but in aggregate up 4%. Aftermarket up just 2%.
 Looking at the segment income, down 9%. There is where we really saw the impact of the spent cores in terms of the impact on our results. It is kind that exasperated here for us as we start up the launch of our South Carolina smelter in this quarter.
 I guess I would just remind folks that in Power Solutions we are on LIFO basis, so we have to -- if you think about the startup of the facility, we have to buy roughly 1 million units at the current prevailing market rates, which are extremely high. Unfortunately, when we book keep that we put them into inventory at our long-ago historic cost, and that really drives a charge in the quarter.
 As Steve said, if you look at the second and third quarter here, the impact is about $0.05 a share just from this lead issue.
 Turning to Automotive Experience, we did deliver a solid quarter here, although I would acknowledge it was below our expectations really due to the deteriorations that we are starting to see in the European market and the weaker euro.
 Look at our sales increases by territory, we saw sales up overall 7%; 13% if you sort of back out foreign currency. And there is where you really see the impact of our backlog flowing through the revenue line.
 If you look at it geographically, in North America we were up 31% against 27% industry increase. If you recall that number seems very high. If you really look behind detail what you see is the Japanese customers really bouncing back from the depressed levels associated with the tsunami last year.
 Europe, if we take out currency, we were flat versus a 5% lower industry production level. And in Asia we were a 24%. As Steve said in his comments, we were pleased to see our results in China do well for us.
 For Automotive if you look at our sales, which are primarily through non-consolidated joint ventures, we were up 24% to $1.2 billion. And you kind of need to compare that against the passenger car volumes, which in the quarter were up about 13%. So, again, good strong outperformance in all three of our geographic territories versus the first to market.
 Turning to segment income, we are up about 18% to $202 million. We did benefit from higher volumes in North America and Asia, though this was partially offset by Europe where we swung back into a loss position in the quarter.
 If you look at the issues that we are facing in Europe, we did start to see some of the impacts of lower volumes. If you listened in to our earlier calls, we had largely been insulated from that because most of the deterioration tended to be in the French and Italian markets where we would say we have been underexposed. Now we are seeing a more broad-based reduction in production and that is starting to impact us [like] the rest of the sector here.
 We also would acknowledge that (technical difficulty) in our European numbers and roll-up South America, largely because that market is dominated by European OEs. And that business has turned from a profitable position in the year-ago period to a lossmaking position. That swing for us on a quarterly basis was worth $0.02 or $0.03 and so that is a market we are going to need to focus on right-sizing.
 We would acknowledge that we are have a little bit -- we are trailing behind in terms of the operational improvements, the pace of them [because of our metals] and interiors business in Europe. Nonetheless, if you look at our margins we did manage to expand margins in the quarter by 110 basis points. You can see on the slide here I have kind of indicated what the return on sales was by geography.
 Turning over to slide 11 and focusing on the income statement here, as we sort of referred to sales were up 2%. If you back out the impact of the euro, which has gone from $1.44 last year to $1.28 this year, our top -line improvement would have been a very respectable 7%.
 You can see our gross profit, a little bit of fresh versus last year, down 50 basis points. Here we are really seeing the benefit of higher revenues and our cost reduction initiatives, but it is offset by our business mix. And by that I mean Automotive being a bigger piece of the pie this year versus last year. Auto has a lower gross margin than our other two businesses; that is a bit of a headwind here.
 This is where we also see the impact of the lead input costs flowing through and some of the launch difficulties that we are having in Europe.
 SG&amp;A we were pleased to see a 90 basis point reduction in our SG&amp;A expenses, down to 9.4% of revenue. This decrease really represents the focus that we have had on right-sizing our cost structure in light of the fair market realities. If you really look at the SG&amp;A expenses by business unit, really Building Efficiency is where we have seen the most traction and we have gotten the benefit of the recent restructuring initiatives.
 I also point out that we did go out this year with a plan to increase SG&amp;A spending in some of our -- to support some of our key growth initiatives. And that would be areas like innovation, our emerging market infrastructure, and new product development. Those initiatives we are protecting and we are dialing some of those back, but if you look at those types of things we are spending more money on a year-over-year basis than we did in the prior year.
 In terms of equity income, a strong increase of 25% to $70 million. This is really due to two things. One, the fact that we have consolidated our hybrid joint venture; that is a business that was losses in the prior year. That is now fully consolidated; it's now going to flow through this line.
 The other factor here would be improvements in profitability in our automotive joint ventures. So if you look at our segment margins here it is $615 million -- our segment income, sorry. Saw a nice segment margin improvement of 60 basis points to 5.8% versus the 5.2% last year.
 Turning to slide 12, if you look at financing charges up about $16 million, very comparable to the year-over-year increases we have been seeing the other few quarters of this year. A higher level of interest expense really associated with higher borrowings to finance the 2011 acquisitions that we made and higher levels of capital expenditures.
 In the quarter you can see our underlying tax rate was about 16% versus about 18.5% last year. That reduction really is attributed to the fact that we have a revised mix of where our income is flowing on a geographic basis, so we generally -- you could sort of take away here we are making more money in lower tax jurisdictions and less money in the higher tax jurisdictions. Most notably the US where we are taking the hit on the battery and the lead side.
 The income attributable to non-controlling shareholders. I am asked this has a bigger year-over-year charge. What I would point out here is in the quarter we did purchase substantially all of our minority partners in (inaudible) for $120 million. That is going to bring us an annual benefit of $20 million on a run rate basis, so we got about $5 million improvement here in the quarter (inaudible).
 Then lastly in terms of our diluted earnings per share came in at the $0.64, which is an improvement of 14% versus last year.
 [Then maybe] just make a few comments now on the balance sheet. We are pleased to see our cash provided from operations of $619 million. It was a 70% improvement over last year.
 You can see CapEx came in at 22% higher at $447 million. If you look at the CapEx number for the Company, we continue to believe our full-year number is going to be around $1.7 billion. That would imply a pretty significant reduction here as we go into the fourth quarter.
 Our outlook for the fourth quarter is about $300 million. So the difference, the headwind that we have had all throughout the year of CapEx being way up versus prior-year levels is going to float around here in the fourth quarter and it is going to be somewhere between $150 million and $160 million year-over-year decline. So that is going to be a source of cash for us as we go into the fourth quarter here.
 In some of the earlier notes I did see some comments about the year-to-date cash outflow position that we have taken. And I guess I would just remind folks that if you do look at our year-to-date numbers we have about a $400 million outflow associated with discretionary funding of our pension plans and that shows up as a use of working capital. So, yes, it is a cash burn but on one hand we are really just taking part of our money that we would otherwise use to reduce debt and better funding our pension plans.
 At the end of the quarter our net debt to total capital (inaudible) was consistent with where we were at the end of the second quarter, 34%. We still have a strong balance sheet and we do expect to see some further deleveraging here in the fourth quarter, which should position us pretty well as we go into 2013.
 A few comments on the pension and our pension retiree medical plans. We continue to improve the non-funded position. We expect to end the year in the 90%-plus funded rate, and that is really as a result of pretty good asset performance this year but also the $400 million of discretionary funding that I talked about earlier.
 Over the course of the last year we have also taken a look at adopting mark-to-market, a pension accounting methodology. This is a methodology that I am sure many of you are familiar with one the call here, but a number of large companies have adopted this change. And we believe, when you really look at the fundamentals here, it is a simpler and more straightforward methodology that improves financial transparency.
 So we are going to make this change in the fourth quarter and we will book a year-to-date retrospective charge in prior-period numbers. So we end up, from an accounting perspective, restating prior-year numbers so that we show the impact of the catch up in the first reported period. Then we will show all comparable periods on a like-for-like basis.
 If you are kind of trying to model out what impact of that would be on 2013, we will see a reduction of our pension expense associated with some of the amortization of prior-year losses. However, if you look at the lower discount rate that we are going to be facing in 2013 combined with a reduction that we are going to take in our discount rate as we -- a reduction in our expected planned return on assets rate that we are going to take as we derisk our pension plan, those are largely going to offset the impact and we don't expect to be material.
 If you are really -- I guess really just putting this in perspective, for the last few years we have kind of been on a path to insulate our financial results from the volatility of pensions and pension accounting. Some of the things that we have done we have invested about $1.5 billion in discretionary pension contributions. We have closed and frozen the majority of our global defined benefit plans, and we have adopted a number of more conservative investment strategies to derisk our investment returns.
 And so really you need to look at this accounting change in light of all that and just another step in that process. The other thing I will just point out for our employees that might be listening on the call is this is just an accounting change. It has absolutely no impact on our funded levels or the benefit levels that we pay to our current and future retirees.
 Lastly, I would like to just talk a little bit more about some of the changes, some of our restructuring initiatives. We did take some small charges here in the third quarter and we expect to do more in the fourth quarter.
 If you really look at the focus of those, it is going to be on properly aligning our headcount to the market realities that we currently face. We are going to continue with divesting some smaller non-core assets, and we have had a number of those flow-through on a year-to-date basis. We do expect to make some footprint changes in certain geographies. And we are going to do some consolidation and that will be both in smaller manufacturing activities but also in some of our back-office functions.
 We do expect to continue to invest in our key strategic growth initiatives. We are hopeful that these actions, combined with some of the growth initiatives that Steve has talked about in his section, are going to enable us to deliver a solid, improved profitability into 2013, even in light of the market environments that we sort of currently face.
 Than lastly, just on an informational item, we are going to host our analyst meeting in New York again, although we are going to change the timing here from what has typically been in the October time frame to December and more January. And really the key thing here is in pushing it back to this time, we are going to be a lot closer aligned to when some of our peers report, but we also are kind of in a real unique situation where there is a lot of uncertainty around fiscal and monetary policy particularly in the US but also in Europe. It's very difficult for us to forecast the economic climate we are in when we've got GDP growth that could swing 4, 4.5 percentage points based on the outcome of some of the legislative changes that we're facing here. So that is really what is driving us to push our timing back to the December/January timeframe.
 So with that, Glen, we'll open up it for questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Director, IR   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Pat, we are ready to take questions.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) Chris Ceraso, Credit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Good morning. A few items; I guess first on a battery business. Maybe we can talk about why you don't think these pressures continue past Q4. Can you have bought up all the core that you need, or you are just expecting there will be more cores available and, therefore, the price comes down?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is the latter. There will be more cores. In fact, we expect there to be a flood of cores; that would be the normal situation. It is just a function that we have to go into production almost this early to be able to meet demand.
 We level our production [and in the summer] we are actually at almost full production here from July through the end of the year just to be able to meet the (inaudible) requirement in the aftermarket. We think it will be -- even though, like Bruce described, there is probably a little bit of a pent-up inventory at the aftermarket (inaudible). And so we expect that because of the hot weather and what it is doing to the chemistry in the batteries, which it destroys them.
 Maybe even those of you that are on the phone that don't know that industry, the shortest lives of batteries are in the high-heat districts, like Vegas and Phoenix. And so the hot heat we are seeing throughout the Midwest and East and the South is, in fact, weakening the batteries and shortening the battery life. We expect there to be, therefore, a flood of cores by the fourth quarter. It shouldn't continue beyond that. This is just very unusual, Chris.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is somewhat contingent then on an increase in replacement demand, but you think with the heat that that should happen?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Or just the normal seasonal pattern will do it too, okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Then also on the batteries, there was -- the weakness in volume overall outside of any kind of weather issues, is any of that attributable to price hikes that have been taken in that market?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I don't think so. I don't consider it at all.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is pretty consistent most -- if you look at the competitors who have reported similar numbers there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. I have a few questions on the pension. The guidance for Q4 does not include the change to your pension accounting, right? That is just a pure change based on the fundamentals?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is correct.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nor does it incur -- nor does our guidance include any restructuring.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Restructuring, yes. Just operational.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We really haven't sized that yet, Chris.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then along the lines of derisking and changing the pension around, have you thought about offering buyouts or shifting to third-party annuities like we have seen from some of the OEMs?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are looking at offering buyouts to [deferred assets], but this is probably something that we are maybe a year away from.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Just lastly on Europe auto, can you maybe sketch out what the path is to improvement here? You had done these acquisitions and those were supposed to help the margins in Europe, and that hasn't happened. Has that been because the volume is low?
 Are you feeling now that you have got more vertical integration you are even more susceptible to volume? Maybe just help us understand what exactly is happening in Europe and how and when it gets better.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is fair, Chris. Let me try to -- this is a question I expected from probably most people on the call, so I want to take a minute to answer this question appropriately.
 First of all, let me dispel something. The performance that we have from the KEIPER transaction is just exactly what we expected. It is contributing the way we thought, so it is not the KEIPER.
 The issues that we are having are pretty well concentrated in two businesses as we have described. It is the metal operation prior to the acquisition and the business that we were awarded under the old product schemes. (inaudible)
 Let's talk about metals, which is the one where we expected the biggest improvement and haven't been able to get there. We have six different operating, I will call them work streams, that we are focused on where we have identified and have mapped, I'll call it that to use your comment, Chris, probably hundreds of millions of dollars in the next 18 months. They have to deal with improvements in operations; they have to do with purchasing; they have to do with commercial negotiations.
 Let me just go into some of what they are in detail and then I will come back and tell you why timing is an issue for us. There is some things we can get our hands on right away. There is some purchasing opportunities that we have around steel tubes, around motors that we can get our hands on in relatively quick timeframe, meaning over the next 12 months.
 There are commercial claim processes; there are change processes that we will get over the long term and the medium term. There are some things that we know we are going to benefit from in 2013 such as lower launch costs, and we are going to be shedding containment costs. That is probably a $50 million year-over-year improvement that we can see today just based on the activity that we have.
 There are some things that are probably over the medium term, and these you will understand as I walk them through with you. They would include things like how we design for manufacturing; how we standardize our product lines; how we deploy best practices and best processes. As an example, Hammerstein has an outstanding process that they use for both marrying their tracks and how they stamp rails, and we are deploying that across our product lines.
 Footprint optimization, what we can do to improve our machine utilization or label productivity. Those are all mapped in what we call a tracker. We have -- I am not going to give out a number, but there are hundreds of millions of dollars we attract.
 What we are trying to do now is refine what we can get to in the near term quarter by quarter in fiscal 2013. These are all mapped and expected to be able to happen by mid-2014. So what I am trying to do is provide some refinement so I can come back and give guidance to our shareholders what that rate of improvement is in the next six months, the next year, and then quarter-by-quarter guidance. That is what I guess I would kind of tell you.
 So it is a blend of near-term things that we know we can get our hands on. There are some things we need to do to improve the long-term position of the business and standardize our product lines, improve our machine utilization. That is all taking place.
 And so it is not the new acquisitions. It is the business that we were awarded back in 2009 and 2010 that we are trying to improve, and making sure that we have the foundation in place and the fundamentals in place to ensure that improvement continues into 2014 through 2016.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, that is helpful, Steve. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Chris.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson, Barclays.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So just drilling down a little bit more into the European auto experience, it sounds like the improvement program is in metals; it is not in Hammerstein or Recaro, so it is an existing metals business. To what extent, though -- I guess a couple questions. A) is interior still a drag there? We have seen Visteon unable to sell its business due to pressures in the European interiors market.
 And then, secondly, while you are reducing costs the OEMs are themselves running into profit pressures. What is your confidence in being able to hold onto these cost reductions in light of pricing pressures in seating? And how are you thinking about that as part of the improvement plan?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Let me take a shot and I will let Bruce come in also. I guess if you go back to the interiors, we still have plants that are a drag. We have product lines that are a drag and we are actually looking at exiting some product categories, Brian.
 I think that the market conditions haven't changed. Interiors is a sector which has got overcapacity and I think most players in that marketplace, whether it be Visteon or some of our other competitors, it is not a new phenomenon. The industry has been struggling for some time.
 I believe that we have got Bill Jackson focused on the business and that is what he is focusing on right now. And we believe that we will get some improvement because of that in terms of how we approach the OEs as a stand-alone business. That is number one.
 In terms of your comment about the OEs, you are absolutely right, there is some additional pressure and it is spotty in select OEs. We have turned back business where we weren't able to meet the cost reduction request that we were given.
 We continue to have a strong book of business, but I do think that our job is to protect that. We have made an investment and it is our job to protect the investment and the margins that we acquired. And so from my perspective the only way to do that is to be somewhat resistant on price reductions request and if that shrinks our business, so be it. I am managing that business for returns right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just kind of within the quarter, given production was only down 5%, it looks like your incremental margins were -- detrimental margins were very high, ex currency. So I see the improvement path, but what was sort of the step back vis-a-vis on a year-over-year or a sequential basis in the business? Was it just volume or were there other things that popped up?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Remember too, Brian, in that European number there is also the South American swing into a loss (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, so it is really the South, so that is part of that? Is that an improvement plan there or is that just waiting for a better macro real?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, there is an improvement plan we have to put in place. Bruce referenced that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If you look the South America situation, in many ways -- I mean that is obviously a lot smaller for us. I mean just the size of South America piece within our business now only like $500 million to $600 million on an annual basis. But if I look at kind of the market fundamentals it's very tough.
 You have got -- markets have softened, currencies have significantly weakened, and the auto industry there is, I will say, more susceptible to imported components which puts a lot of pressure. Labor inflation is extremely high and some of the government policies, particularly in Argentina, are tough and so I think we are looking at what we can do to improve the situation down there.
 But we are in a pretty tough market right now and that is not likely going to change in 2013. Now there is some things that we can do to improve our current position, but our outlook for 2013 is we will have a loss there. It will be smaller; we are going to take some actions but we have got to write that out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Brian.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker, Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Good morning, everyone. Steve, if I can ask you why -- if you can give a little more color on why you delayed the analyst day. And is there any particular milestones or data you are looking for that will help you form your outlook for 2013, or is it more of just giving your restructuring and your operations a little more time to improve?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I think it is the former. I think really we are just trying to get a better sense for what kind of environment we are going to be operating in. The other thing we could have done is walked in and said listen on these assumptions this is what we think. We just think that we will have a better chance to refine those assumptions.
 I think in general the investment community will have a better chance to also be focused on 2013. I truthfully think that we are concerned that oftentimes we go out and really -- I say people -- there hasn't really been a strong focus on 2014 at that point in time because there is very few companies that have gone and really talked about it.
 So we just feel that we are better equipped to give you guidance for Q1 in the fall, talk about maybe some of the things we are seeing and the assumptions that we are beginning to focus on through 2013, and then come back and give you better -- we just think we can provide better information. We certainly know last year that that was the case. And last year things were a lot more stable than they are today, but clearly the last few months would have been significant for us in terms of understanding what environment we were in.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think if you looked at the numbers right now between the (inaudible) board and the major banks, including your firm, I think what people have right now is GDP growth in North America next year of somewhere in the 1.5% to 2%. I think it's a pretty tight cluster there. And those numbers are coming down and on that basis I think we would feel pretty good at providing what we think is going to happen in our business.
 But if you then look at the -- between the sequestration related spending cuts and the expiration of the Bush tax cuts, which are big items, and quantify those, those adds up to somewhere between 4% and 4.5% of GDP. So now that takes your 1.5%, could possibly minus 3%, and that is a very different economic picture here in North America. It's unlikely we are going to know the answer to that between now and when our normal analyst day would have been, which is early October. We just elected to push it back here a couple months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Understood. Just looking at the BE in the quarter your margins were much better than we expected. Can you help quantify how much of that was some of the SG&amp;A and cost in shares that you had and how much of that was driven by just the improvement in resi?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would say if you kind of look at residential, and last year within our Building Efficiency numbers we had a large -- we had a one-time benefit in residential and we had a one-time hit from the Latin America business that is largely offset. But if I strip that out then what you would see in the residential is we did see a nice pop up in profitability, but the fact that the mix moved to a lower margin product our profitability was a little changed from an ROS point of view. So that really didn't drive it.
 The big area for us was in service. North America service we actually saw a nice improvement in our profitability there. Start to think about last year it was kind of cool, especially in the early start of the cooling season. Really saw the benefit in margins there which was labor utilization and processing improvements that we saw that came of our IT investments in that business. That was the sort of biggest driver.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But, Ravi, I think the fact that all of our segments were up in BE would just explain, because it really was broad based.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Finally, Bruce, you pointed out that the FCF should be viewed ex the pension contribution. Can you just help us with what cash flow will look like in the fourth quarter?
 You have had some pretty big cash generating fourth quarters in the past. Is it going to be something similar or do we expect something similar?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, no. We expect to see a very strong Q4. We aren't making any -- we are sort of done from a discretionary pension point of view so we won't have anything there. As I said in my comments, our capital expenditure is going to be in the $300 million range. That is a big reduction versus the run rate that we have had for the last three quarters, and it is a big improvement versus what we had in the fourth quarter of last year.
 We do have some -- expect our working capital levels are going to improve by a couple hundred million, and we have a few sort of smaller, non-core assets and properties that we are selling. So we do expect pretty strong improvement here in the fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Nesvold, Jefferies.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Nesvold,  Jefferies &amp; Company - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. So I just want to talk about the Power Solutions business for a minute. This is not an area where I am an expert, but we have heard some channel perspective that believes that JCI's move towards vertical integration is actually helping to drive up lead prices. That a lot of the third-party smelters that you would have historically sold to are kind of out in the market trying to secure lead and, therefore, pushing that up.
 Do you think that is accurate? Is that part of what is happening here? And if that is true, why would it reverse out so quickly?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, that is not what is happening and I think it is more a factor that the activity at retail, as I described, I think is the bigger issue. The fact that they are just -- we have looked across four or five different aftermarket customers and (inaudible), of course, coming back that is what is driving up the prices. We haven't ramped up enough at this stage in our own internal smelting to really drive that up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Nesvold,  Jefferies &amp; Company - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. I will keep it to that one.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Peter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Nesvold,  Jefferies &amp; Company - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rod Lache, Deutsche Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat Nolan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is Pat Nolan on for Rod. Can we just go back to Europe for a second? I know you talked about the metals business, but you also highlighted the new business launches from 2009 and 2010.
 Prior to this quarter you were expecting that the most difficult launches were largely behind you and we were going to see the containment costs start to taper off. Is that not what occurred in the quarter? Can you help us frame what was the run rate of containment costs in the quarter versus where they had been running? Are the launches basically getting -- are the launches tracking worse than you expected?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I don't think launches are tracking any worse than what we expected. I think some of the containment costs we had on the prior launches where we would have expected to shed we probably haven't shed those costs as quickly, Pat. But there is nothing that we can point to in the new launches.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat Nolan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you give us any kind of framing of where your containment costs are tracking in the quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't have it handy. I mean we can follow-up with you, Pat, on that. Like Steve says, it wasn't a down -- it wasn't a variance versus what we thought. I mean like I said at the last call, we have three or four problematic launches.
 Those are following through as we expected they were, mainly in the Europe side of our business versus the North America. You kind of saw in our North America numbers -- we were kind of depressed last quarter and the quarter before because launches there those snap back, our profits they snap back there nicely.
 Maybe one other comment I would add on Europe, though, we haven't talked about it is -- not a big issue for us but it is something that we were worried about -- the sort of distresses that we see in our supply base. We do have some headwinds associated with that and that is the area that if things deteriorate more there that is going to become a bigger and bigger headwind for the industry, not just Johnson Controls.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat, just on the comment -- not to what you just said, Bruce -- but I do think that one thing that we have really done well in the last six months is get our hands around our launches in terms of our launch teams. I think we have staffed them adequately, I think we have got tremendous oversight, and they aren't as complex. I mean, to be honest with you, there were some extremely complex launches and product configurations.
 So I feel better about what we use to describe, but to your point, Pat, I would hope to see some higher -- some better and faster improvements in our ability to reduce our containment costs. Our quality is good. We are getting high marks from our customers on our quality; it is just a function we have got to shed some costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat Nolan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Prior to this quarter you were expecting the European margins to get above 3% in Q4. Can you just give us an update on that? That seems like a pretty big bridge from the negative 1.5% you did this quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that is fair, that is fair. I think if you look at part of the reason why -- we are not getting the 3%. Part of the reason why I think I am more cautious and I went back and tried to maybe actually quantify this. So if we look at some of the delta in Q4 I would attribute as much as $0.03 or $0.04 to just our thoughts regarding commercial planning resolutions in this timeframe.
 One of the earlier questions, I think it was from Brian, had to do with OE resistance and I don't think it is resistance as much as they are just slow-walking claims and things of that nature. In the past we would have -- holdings had a very strong fourth quarter in terms of claim resolution. I think we have just had baked into our forecast, but that is not going to happen this year. It could happen, but we have assumed that it does not, and that is our biggest delta in terms of our margin assumptions for Q4.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat Nolan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just lastly on the lead impact, the $40 million you saw in Q3, is the inventory bigger -- billed in Q4 bigger, so that $40 million could be a bigger number?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, it is going to be, I would say, in the $30 million to $40 million range.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And it could be less, because we think this thing should start to improve by September. By October, November, December it's real obvious that it's going. In fact, to some extent we are surprised that we are still seeing it in July.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pat Nolan,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks very much, guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas, Wells Fargo Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A broader question on Europe. IHS came out with their forecast the other day for calendar year to be down 6. I know there is a lot of skepticism out there regarding that number. It sounds like you are a little skeptical on that. I know you are on a different fiscal year-end.
 But, Steve, what are your thoughts here? Do you think there is a lot of downside risk to that forecast?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think (inaudible), Rich. We have sort of been trying to revise our forecast as we get information from the marketplace, so we are trying to watch our major exposure. We are broad-based with the German customers along with Opal and Ford. As Bruce mentioned, we don't have a lot of exposure to the French.
 But I think we are looking at the mix trying to understand what is taking place. We are trying to guess what is happening. The fact that UK and Germany is holding up at that; they are still growing. We are still trying to figure out if that is going to continue.
 But my sense is that I am more worried about the level of decline that could happen in the south. I think France is the one I am most concerned about. I think Spain we have already probably -- we are down already, but I think Italy and France would be the two markets I am most concerned about. I don't think I want to comment yet in terms of whether I agree with the minus 6.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, all right. Then on the Building Efficiency side, so very good margin performance this quarter it sounds like. Should we expect similar rate of improvement year over year for the fourth quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At this point in time -- best guess I can give you at this point in time is that they are going to improve at least 100 basis points of margin in Q4.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then just looking out, I know that we are going to be a few months away from getting an outlook for 2013, but, Steve, the sustainability of this margin improvement how comfortable are you with that? Or is that kind of in flux right now as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are you talking about within Building Efficiency?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, within Building Efficiency.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think that it is where we are [glad] to get another handle on. I think we have a very good handle on our cost structure as we go into 2013. The thing that is going to be important for us --and I am only going to give you leading indicators.
 We would hope to come out of this quarter with our backlog up 6%, 7%, 8%, if not more. That is the key, Rich. That is what I need to see and probably the category that we need to see it in is in what we call the solutions business performance contracting. Something that has lagged the last four or five months for us.
 The data that we have from our field is saying that they expect that to recover in Q4. That is the one we are watching; that will be the key. Whether we are up 4% or whether we are up 8%, 9%, that then will dictate whether we get the margin right next year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich, maybe just a little more there. I would just keep in mind, when we went into this year what we talked about for Building Efficiency is about 50 basis points of margin expansion. If you look at where we were in Q1 and Q2, we were flattish or down slightly and we talked about the fact that we were fronting some of our investments in panoptics and things like that.
 So we are pretty comfortable with our outlook here for the fourth quarter that we will get that 50 basis points and maybe another 10 or 20. But the path for improvement for Building Efficiency, because so many of our investments are in SG&amp;A, that glide path we are not backing away from. So we are not going to be up 100, 120 basis points next year. It is going to be that 50 to 60 basis points. That is our trend line.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, understood. Then last one for me. On FX, are you assuming current conversion rates in guidance for fourth quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, we use [122] here for the fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. All right, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Rich.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [Daunte Tresta], Lazard Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daunte Tresta,  Lazard Capital Markets - Analyst   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Good morning, guys. First question is on the Building Efficiency side. So this is a very impressive improvement on the CWS side, was there anything one-time in the quarter here or what kind of lead to that 86% improvement in the operating margin there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I know there isn't anything of a non-recurring nature. I would -- [it is making an improvement] but I was still (inaudible) about that. If you look at the absolute margin (inaudible) it's still below where we would like to see, so it has bounced back strongly but it's still not in that 2.5% to 3% range that we expect.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess I would just make a statement in general, though, about Building Efficiency. There really were no unusual items this quarter. This was one of the cleanest quarter -- the quality of that earnings is very, very strong.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daunte Tresta,  Lazard Capital Markets - Analyst   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. One quick follow-up then guys. When we think about your Power Solutions, clearly lead price is sort of what it is and you guys are saying it's going to go away, hopefully, by one quarter. Now as we think 12 months out -- so with this incremental benefit from lower prices, how do you think about how that business grows when the aftermarket comes back?
 And where did the margin go? Because all the drag is sort of now going to be behind you guys after a quarter. How should we think about that business 12 months out?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me start and then, Bruce, you jump in.
 I guess two-fold. Let me explain volumes first. Whenever we have seen the type of January through March period where we had depressed volumes due to weather, typically it has continued slightly depressed, again in the quarter that we are in today, and then it pops in the fourth quarter. That is going to be interesting to see if that happens.
 But regardless, this is going to normalize and it always has. So I hate to talk about weather constraints, but we do expect a very, very strong fiscal 2013 start in terms of volumes. That is number one.
 Number two are the margins. We have guided higher margins partially because of some things we have done. We have invested in vertical integration; that is a big one for us. We also have, we believe, some improvements that we will have from some costs that we incurred last year in China that will be year over year.
 So we think it's 2013 we expect the margins to improve in Power primarily because of higher volumes, better utilization, vertical integration, and an avoidance of the Chinese year-over-year softness that we incurred last year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daunte Tresta,  Lazard Capital Markets - Analyst   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, that's great. Thanks a lot, guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We got time for one more.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [Joseph Stack], RBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joseph Stack,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks a lot, guys. Just to quickly follow up on Power Solutions, and I'm glad you mentioned China. I know that I think the plant partially reopened, so just trying to think a little bit of the margin trajectory in the fourth quarter from the third quarter and the different headwinds. Clearly, the lead issue is still -- lead is still an issue.
 Shouldn't the pricing come up a little bit and then also some more cost savings from China? So do those totally offset or is it still a net negative headwind for (inaudible)?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess we will see the being negative headwind, but when you look at a year-over-year delta -- so we do expect to see some margin expansion here in the fourth quarter in Power. I wouldn't say that China would be a big part of that, but the biggest issue is going to be the pricing.
 We did announce pricing here in the current quarter, some of it went in in May, some of it went in June. So if you just look at the benefit that we get in the fourth quarter where we will get -- we will have it implemented across the board, so we get the whole benefit here in the fourth quarter. That is going to enable us to offset some headwinds that you are referring and we will get back to that margin expansion into the fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joseph Stack,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then just to see, the $40 million headwind this quarter I mean is the majority of that because we are ramping up South Carolina? Like had you already been ramped up?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, none of it was.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That South Carolina ramp up really is a Q4 issue not (multiple speakers). And so if you think about that $40 million we talked about in Q3, in Q4 we said $30 million to $40 million. You probably could think about a third of that is going to be when we ramp up this new facility and two-thirds of it will be the high-cost cores.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joseph Stack,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you talk about what your, I guess, internally sourced lead goes from to once that facility is fully ramped up?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, these cycling centers are roughly (inaudible) work. We have a capacity of about 50 million a year at current lead levels, so that is kind of the delta that we will get from South Carolina.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But then I think we have all our smelters, so what is our internally (multiple speakers) is there. That is probably from what it was (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Director, IR   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are going to have to cut it off there, Steve. Final comments?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls, Inc. - Chairman, President &amp; CEO   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just a couple quick ones. First of all, we apologize for the fourth-quarter results that we are projecting here. We thought we had conservatism built into them, but believe me our people have not given up. We will do everything we can to deliver results in the fourth quarter.
 We are focused on fiscal 2013 where we feel our fundamentals are good. We are just trying to understand the macro environment that we are operating in.
 Don't read any more into the delay in the analyst day than that we wanted to provide you with the best information we possibly can. We will do what we can in the call at the end of Q4 to sort of tell you what we see in the environment, how we are thinking, and give you maybe some of the assumptions that we are thinking about on a preliminary basis. So we will try to give you at least the stage setting for what we see.
 Again, thank you very much for the call. Again, feeling very good about our long-term fundamentals. We are just frustrated by the near-term as you are and we apologize for that. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for your participation on today's conference call. You may disconnect at this time.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q3 2012 Johnson Controls Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>MILWAUKEE</city>
  <companyName>Johnson Controls Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>JCI^I16</companyTicker>
  <startDate>19-Jul-12 3:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>96304</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL />
  <ISIN />
</Event>