<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="3026809" lastUpdate="Friday, April 23, 2010 at 10:19:30pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="3026809.F" expirationDate="Friday, April 23, 2010 at 3:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of JCI^I16 earnings conference call or presentation 23-Apr-10 3:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2010 Johnson Controls Earnings Conference Call

MILWAUKEE Apr 23, 2010 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Johnson Controls Inc earnings conference call or presentation Friday, April 23, 2010 at 3:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Glen Ponczak
      Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR
   *  Steve Roell
      Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO
   *  Bruce McDonald
      Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Rod Lache
      Deutsche Bank - Analyst
   *  John Murphy
      Bank of America/Merrill Lynch - Analyst
   *  David Leiker
      Robert Baird - Analyst
   *  Brett Hoselton
      KeyBanc - Analyst
   *  Himanshu Patel
      JPMorgan - Analyst
   *  Rich Kwas
      Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst
   *  Colin Langan
      UBS - Analyst
   *  Chris Ceraso
      Credit Suisse - Analyst
   *  Brian Johnson
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Ravi Shankar
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Itay Michaeli
      - Analyst
   *  Kent Newcomb
      Wells Fargo Advisory - Analyst
   *  Tim Deneuer
      [Wolf Trend] - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time. With that, it is my pleasure to turn over today's call to Mr. Glen Ponczak. You may begin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us and happy Friday. Before we begin, I would like to remind you of our forward-looking statement.
  Johnson Controls will make forward-looking statements in this presentation pertaining to its financial results for fiscal 2010 and beyond that are based on preliminary data and are subject to risks and uncertainties. All statements other than statements of historical fact are statements that are or could be deemed forward-looking statements and include terms such as outlook, expectations, estimates or forecasts. For those statements the Company cautions that numerous important factors such as automotive vehicle production levels; mix and schedules; financial distress of key customers; energy prices; the strength of US or other economies; currency exchange rates; cancellation of or changes to commercial contracts; liquidity; changes in the levels or timing of investments in commercial buildings; the ability to execute on restructuring actions according to anticipated timelines and costs; as well as other factors discussed in Item 1A of Part 1 of the Company's most recent Form 10-K filing, which was filed on November 24, 2009 that affect the Company's actual results and could cause its actual consolidated results to differ materially from those expressed in any forward-looking statement made by or on behalf of the Company.
  I am joined this morning by Steve Roell, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Johnson Controls, who will provide an overview of our second-quarter 2010, and he will be followed by Bruce McDonald, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, who will give a more in-depth look of business results, as well as a financial review. And that will be then followed by questions and answers.
  And with that, I will turn it over to Steve.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Glen. Well, good morning and thank you for joining us.
  I guess I'm going to start by just highlighting the two primary themes in our earnings release. Certainly the fact that we're benefiting from the recovery of the North American and European auto industry is a major driver of our results in the quarter. And I think the other theme is that we're starting to see signs that are surfacing with the non-residential market. The building market is beginning to recover as well, and we will highlight some of those indicators for you.
  In terms of the second quarter itself, both Power Solutions and Automotive Experience benefited from the strong automotive production levels in North America and Europe, and we will talk a little bit later about the fact that we now are convinced that those trends will continue into the second half of the year.
  Emerging markets demand continues to be good for all of our businesses. If you look at the Building Efficiency side, China we continue to benefit both from an order and a sales standpoint. South America is strong for us, and in the Middle East, while sales were negative in the quarter, down slightly from a year ago, the orders in the pipeline of activity in the Middle East is starting to pick up for us significantly.
  And coming into this fiscal year, one of the key elements of our projections was that we would convert on the higher automotive volumes in both automotive and power, and we continue to perform very well against that metric. The conversion has been strong, at the high end of the ranges that we originally projected.
  We look across our businesses and believe that we're gaining share, whether that be in the automotive group -- and you will see our sales growth -- compared to the industry build. We see gains obviously in the Power Solutions business, and we believe we're taking share in the equipment side and security and solutions side clearly in our Building Efficiency.
  We ended the quarter with a strong balance sheet. During the quarter we did get positive outlook revisions from both S&amp;P and Moody's, and our cash flows remain strong. And, as a result of that, as we note here, we will be accelerating some of our investments in growth. That is primarily in the Power Solutions business when we talk about capital, but we will be investing also in increased sales forces in our Building Efficiency growth.
  In terms of the absolute numbers for the second quarter, our sales of $8.3 billion were up 32% from a year ago. We had segment income of $427 million. Our net income of $292 million was a record for any second quarter. So we wanted to highlight that. We did not highlight that in our press release, but it did beat the 2008 fiscal year second quarter, which was a record for that period of time. Our EPS of $0.43 compares, of course, to a loss last year of $0.16. We did call out the one item, the $0.03 charge. I think most of you are probably familiar with this by now. We had an $18 million charge from a tax standpoint related to the Medicare subsidy law change that took place, and so that is the one single item in the quarter we call out relative to our earnings per share.
  I should also note Bruce in the past has talked about we expect in the second-half we will have roughly a $50 million to $100 million benefit in tax benefits. We still expect that to happen. We want to make sure that you understand that that is not included in our earnings per share guidance for the fiscal year.
  Turning to Power Solutions, just a couple of quick items for you. Our vertical integration strategies are on track. The Mexican lead recycle facility is now scheduled to start up in October of 2010. What you see and those of you that are looking at the PowerPoint, the illustration on the far right is an actual image from that site, and we also received the final permit we need to start construction in South Carolina with another lead recycling facility.
  When both of those plants are complete, our in-house recycling capacity will represent about 50% of our needs. And, as we have highlighted in the past, we expect about a 200 to 250 basis point margin improvement as a result of those investments.
  We are expanding our investments in China in Power Solutions from a capacity standpoint. For the last 12 months, we have been supplying China's demand through exporting from various facilities throughout the rest of the world. That capacity, the need now is equal to that, so we are going to build another plant, and we already have volume essentially that we are selling in China that represents that additional plant's capacity. We now project that we will require a plant per year for the foreseeable future just to keep up with the demand in China.
  In terms of the quarter, one of the things we highlighted was the fact that our aftermarket unit growth was up 9% in North America. We just wanted to make sure that you understand that did not include the additional win from Wal-Mart that we announced in February. That volume will start at best in June and probably in our fourth fiscal quarter. So we just wanted to highlight that that 9% growth was really a reflection of just the market and the share we have taken up to this point. It does not include additional Wal-Mart business.
  And then finally, in terms of hybrid business, a couple of highlights for you. Our lithium ion battery assembly production launch for the Ford transit will begin in September of 2010. That vehicle was named as Truck of the Year.
  In addition, we would highlight that the Mercedes S-Class hybrid, which you probably have seen some of the ads, is selling exceptionally well, in fact 3 times out of the original expectation by the OE.
  Turning to Automotive Experience, seeing strong growth across all geographic regions. Bruce is going to highlight some of the industry assumptions that we have, what we saw. But we are very pleased with the build.
  China -- our China expansion continues. We now have 23 joint ventures with over 40 manufacturing plants. We expect to add an additional 10 plants, manufacturing plants. Some are components, some are just in time, by the end of this fiscal year.
  Our sales for 2010 in China are now expected to be $3 billion of mostly non-consolidated. That compares to $1.9 billion in 2009.
  Now we have highlighted the fact that we have had a very heavy launch of load in our automotive industry business. We had roughly 60 launches in the first quarter. We had 39 additional launches in the quarter just ended. The majority of those, or I shouldn't say the majority, more than half were really in Europe, and then we highlighted some of the launches themselves. The seating for the Ford Fiesta and the Opel [Mareba], the interior systems work was really the door, the five series door panels for BMW. Electronics pertains to the VW Polo cluster, and we had some hands-free phone launches for Honda.
  So a good launch load. It is good to thing to have that kind of business. We feel very good about it. We feel we are gaining share. And just to highlight for you, while we do not announce our new backlog until October at our annual management meeting, we can tell you that and signal to you that we expect an increase in our backlog as we look at the years 2011 through 2013. We expect an increase in our backlog when we report to you in that October timeframe.
  Turning to Building Efficiency, as I mentioned, there are signs of recovery. Our orders were up 5% in the quarter. It is the first time, in fact, that our orders have been up since the fourth quarter of our fiscal 2008. The strength primarily was in the rest of the world. As I mentioned, we are seeing good growth in the international markets, but also in North America where both our system and services orders were up 5%.
  I wanted to highlight the fact that when we look at the vertical markets in North America, we've talked about the fact that we have not seen a lot of demand from ARRA. Yet despite that, we were seeing education demand strong. That continued in the quarter. We continue to have strong bookings in both K-12 and higher ed. We see extremely strong bookings in the government vertical markets, the federal, state and local. I did want to highlight that our bookings in ARRA in the quarter were $143 million, which actually is more than would have been booked in fiscal year '09 and Q1 combined. So we did see some activity picked up, but I would tell you that we are seeing the growth in education with or without that ARRA stimulus.
  Finally, I wanted just to mention the fact that the expanding market leadership, we are seeing, as I mentioned, earlier gains. We tracked that from the standpoint of some of our equipment shipments. We can look at some of the industry data that gives us an indication that our North American equipment unit share is growing year over year. And one of the ones I would point out is our residential heating furnace market share, which was 13.4% through February 2010 compared to 6.5% in February of '09. We have that data at least.
  Finally, I guess I wanted to talk about the outlook that was contained within our press release. We have revised our automotive production levels in both North America and Europe. We are now looking at production levels for our fiscal year, and I will mention our fiscal year -- 10.9 million and in Europe 16.7 million units. And then given the fact of how well we have demonstrated our ability to convert on that high end, we felt it was appropriate to revise our guidance higher. That, combined with the Building Efficiency showing signs of improvement, gives us some confidence that as the year plays out our second half will continue to improve. We expect that our third fiscal year quarter to show sales growth beginning of that timeframe.
  Just to comment on that EPS guidance, our previous guidance was $1.70 to $1.75 per share for our fiscal year ended in September. We revise that now to a $1.90 to $1.95. And I think all the assumptions that support that EPS guidance are contained in the press release that we provided to you.
  So with that, I'm now going to flip it over to Bruce and let Bruce go into more detail on the second quarter by business and some of the financial detail.
  Bruce?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks, Steve. So just flipping to slide 10 on Automotive Experience, we are really pleased with our auto results for the quarter here. I really think it shows the progress we have made, the financial momentum that we had as a result of completing the restructuring, most of the restructuring initiatives, in Europe and North America.
  So if you will look at sales, which back out the impact of currency, they are up 66%. That really reflects both sales gains and flow of our backlog, the launch of new business, but by and large, a big chunk of that is higher OE production levels.
  In North America you can see our sales were up about 85%, and that compares versus that production increase of about 72%. So there is the evidence of the share gain. Similarly in Europe, we backed out foreign currency, and our sales were up 51% versus an estimated improvement in new vehicle registrations of about 9%.
  Then lastly, in China we are seeing and continue to see the very strong growth that we saw last quarter. Sales, which I will remind everybody, come mainly through consolidated joint ventures improved by 91% to $741 million. The industry sales in China were up about 78%. So in all three regions, substantial outperformance versus the industry.
  In terms of our segment income of $189 million, that compares to a large loss of $269 million last year, and we are seeing really good conversion rate on the incremental volumes. And that's really just again due to the restructuring initiatives.
  The topline growth that we see in China really helps our margins because it flows through as higher equity income, and we saw that both in our Chinese joint ventures but also some of our non-consolidated joint ventures in North America and Europe.
  Looking at our margins by geography, you can see in the upper part of the chart here in North America at 6.7%, Europe at 2.4%, and Asia 6.7%. I think these type of numbers demonstrate the improvements that our business is making and underpin our confidence that we can get our margins in that 6% to 7% range as the volumes pick up here.
  In terms of our European profitability, we talked last quarter about our numbers being negatively impacted by some launch difficulties, distressed suppliers and things like that of $40 million to $50 million. This quarter those costs dropped by about 50%. So they were in about the $20 million to $25 million range in the quarter, and our guys were making good progress reducing those. So we expect those to tail off over the next couple of quarters here, and you'll start to see our European margins trend higher.
  Flipping over to Building Efficiency, sales were $3 billion, which was level of last year, but if you take out the impact of currency, it is down 4%. And, as Steve mentioned earlier, our order activity picked up. So we are starting to see things looking better here.
  If you look at the businesses that do not flow through our backlog -- so that is Global Workplace Solutions and our North American residential business -- sales in these two segments were up 14% and 42% respectively, and that is excluding any impact of foreign currency again.
  In North America we saw revenues were down about 10%, but we were pleased to see orders pick up 5% in this region. And then lastly, in Europe and Latin America, those markets continue to remain somewhat soft, and we saw double-digit declines in our revenue position.
  Looking at segment income of $104 million, we are up 16% year over year. That really reflects primarily the turnaround in our residential business and the good control of our costs.
  I would point out that our numbers here -- we have the bullet point here, we talk about our nonrecurring charges being sort of comparable to last year in the quarter. If you recall last year, we took about $25 million of expenses that really related to some of the reorganization we were doing in our North American residential business and our SKU and inventory rationalization actions.
  In this quarter we have comparable charges, nonrecurring type charges of about $25 million that relate to both inventory adjustments, and some -- a couple of larger customer bankruptcies that impacted us by, like I said, an aggregate of about $25 million. And, as Steve indicated before, we continue to invest in some of our key growth initiatives like energy, our infrastructure and emerging markets in particular.
  Looking forward we are confident that we are going to see Building Efficiency sales start to turn positive on a year-over-year basis here and further margin expansion beginning here in the third quarter.
  And then lastly, in terms of the backlog, you can see in the quarter we are at $4.4 billion. On a year-over-year basis, that is a 6% decline, again taking out foreign currency. And I think the key takeaway here is the sequential improvement versus the down 10% that we were at the end of the first quarter. So we are seeing strong momentum in our pipeline, and our backlog we anticipate will turn positive on a year-over-year basis by the end of the third quarter here.
  Next, moving on to Power Solutions, we had an exceptionally strong quarter with sales up 30%. If we back out the impact of lead, which was about $100 million, our unit volumes you can see were up 14% with aftermarket up 9% and the OE side of our business up 44%.
  As Steve indicated earlier, these numbers -- just reminding everyone -- do not include the impact of the Wal-Mart business, which launches in our fourth quarter.
  In terms of China, Steve talked about the capacity expansion that we are looking to make in that market. Our volumes were up 38%, and as Steve indicated, we are filling that demand with shipments from North America and Europe.
  I guess I probably should point out that if you think about our growth in our business, it is really coming from our development of the aftermarket side of that business. So our growth strategy is building up the aftermarket side of Power Solutions to take advantage of the longer-term trends and more stable trends that we see in that side of our business. Hence, our confidence that we can put the production capacity in place that Steve mentioned earlier.
  That capacity expansion in China, combined with the timing of us getting the South Carolina smelters, is the driver behind the uptick in our CapEx guidance that I'm going to talk about later on.
  In terms of segment income for Power Solutions, $134 million. The main drivers here would be higher volumes. We had some lead issues that lingered on in 2009, and our business performance is very strong. We are basically selling this higher level of volume with three fewer plants than we had a year ago, so we are getting excellent conversion pull-through from our manufacturing operations.
  And then I would also point out that negatively impacting our segment income is the investment that we are making in the hybrid business. As Steve talked about, the money that we are spending to facilitize here in Holland, Michigan and the launch of our BMW lithium ion production in France in the quarter here.
  So maybe now I will turn over to the financial section on slide 14. As I talk about our numbers, I am going to talk about them excluding the one-time items. And then, as Steve mentioned earlier, the only item that we are calling out for this quarter is the $18 million tax charge that we took associated with the Medicare Part D subsidy elimination.
  So before I get into the specific details, I think the key takeaways from our financial performance are as follows. First would be our topline growth. We are benefiting from both automotive and battery, those markets improving on the OE side, as well as market share gains in all three of our businesses. And here is where you are really seeing the continuity that we had in terms of commitment to our growth initiatives. We funded those through our tough times last year, and we're now starting to see the benefit of those pay off.
  Be that the growth that we are seeing in China in all three of our businesses. Some of the market share gains that Steve talked about in the North American residential turnaround. You know, those types of things. We are also seeing the significant benefit of our restructuring actions, and you are seeing that in both spend and gross margins and also better SG&amp;A control. And then the strong conversion rate on the incremental volume is really flowing through well.
  So looking at our topline, Steve mentioned where sales were up at $8.3 billion was a 32% growth. Again, backing out foreign exchange, the underlying increase is 27%. Obviously that was driven primarily by the recovery in the OE side of our business in battery and automotive, but all three of our businesses contributed here in terms of market share gain.
  Building Efficiency, while we have bottomed out, we are still down 4% in the quarter. In terms of gross profits at 14.7%, you can see about 390 basis points of improvement versus last year. And here is where we are really seeing the benefit of restructuring initiatives and better capacity utilization across our manufacturing operations.
  In terms of SG&amp;A expense, you will see $847 million. We are up about 5% year over year. If we back out the impact of foreign currency, it is up 2%. So I think the takeaway here is we have 27% constant currency increase in sales, and we have a 2% increase in our SG&amp;A costs. And if you look at where that 2% came, it is in higher engineering increases and incentive compensation accruals, which were increased versus last year.
  You can see again on the equity income line we have a significant improvement versus last year of $51 million. If you think about that, the two main buckets would be $20 million would be in China, and the other $20 million would be North American and Europe nonconsolidated joint ventures in our auto business.
  Flipping to slide, 15, maybe just draw your attention to a couple of line items here on financing charges of $43 million, a little bit lower than last year really reflecting lower borrowing rates and borrowing levels.
  Lastly, on an underlying basis, our tax rate was 18%, which is consistent with the guidance that we gave you last quarter. And then income from attributable noncontrolling interest, or what we used to call minority interest, was an expense this year of $23 million versus income of $12 million last year. And that really is just attributable to the fact that our consolidated automotive joint ventures are profitable this year whereas last year in the quarter they were losing money. And if you look at the deluded earnings per share at $0.43, you can see the magnitude of the turnaround from the $0.16 loss that we had last year. And
 then lastly, I will just comment a little bit further on our guidance for this year. So, as Steve indicated, we are up in our guidance range by $0.20. So our new range is $1.70 -- sorry, $1.90 to $1.95.
  In terms of our topline, you can see we are ticking up our sales growth from 16% to 18% at $33.5 billion. Here we are seeing the benefit of the higher production levels in North America and Europe, although that is somewhat offset by our Euro assumption. You can see taking the euro down from $1.45 to $1.35 negatively impacts our topline by about $700 million. And I think even though we have not changed our Building Efficiency sales guidance of up 5%, we just wanted to make sure that folks understand that we are committed to that number, and we feel very confident with that, especially on the basis of what we are seeing in terms of our orders and backlog activity here.
  In terms of our earnings at $1.90 to $1.95, here you are really seeing the impact of the conversion on the incremental revenue growth. We are seeing good focus and good continued focus on keeping our costs down. So, as the revenue grows, we are keeping our expenses in check here. And then the impact of the Euro assumption on earnings is about $0.05 a share. And that flows through primarily in our automotive European operations. That is where most of that $0.05 hits us because that's our biggest European business.
  In terms of margins, we have changed our guidance here and taken our overall segment margins up to plus 330 basis points. The ranges, as you can see by Business Automotive, were going to be in the 3.1% to 3.3% range, which is up from 2% to 2.2% previously. In power our range is 12.6% to 12.8%, and that is up from an 11.8% to 12% previously. And BE we feel our range does not need to be updated here. We are sticking with the 5.6% to 5.8%.
  Capital expenditures, we are upticking about $50 million in our range here, and that's all due to Power Solutions. And then from a free cash flow point of view, we are going to be up about $100 million. So we've got a slightly higher level of earnings and a little bit offset by the increased CapEx guidance.
  So with that, I will turn it back to Glen, and we will open things up for questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are ready for questions. If I could ask everybody on the phone, please, if you got multiple questions, if you just ask one question and then hang up and get back in the queue, and that way we can be fair to everybody who would like to ask a question. And with that, we will take questions now.
 
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Rod Lache, Deutsche Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rod Lache,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 First of all, on Power Solutions the comment on China growing the size of Europe over the next five years. Europe is about 30% of that business. It looks like you could be doing maybe $300 million per year of growth from that, and you have got 5 million or 6 million units coming from Wal-Mart. It sounds like that business could be looking at 10% organic growth in 2011 and beyond. I was hoping you can comment on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is Bruce here. I think one thing needs to be -- we feel very optimistic about our growth prospects in China. But I would caution you that that is a unit comment. So when we talk about we think the level of -- our unit forecast, let's say, in a five-year timeframe from China would grow from something like an 8 million or 9 million level that we're running at now to about a 30 million level within five years. So that puts the magnitude of the unit sales in context. If you look, though, at the dollar amount, generally speaking I would say that there is quite a bit richer mix in Europe from a dollar point of view with EGM batteries and more extended life type batteries. So the dollar is not going to be equal, but the units are. But nonetheless, it is significant growth.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Murphy, Bank of America/Merrill Lynch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Murphy,  Bank of America/Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just wanted to ask about the backlog. You made some very interesting comments on the automotive side and automotive interiors. You said there were -- the backlog was increasing, and I know you cannot mention the exact number. But I was just wondering why you think you are seeing that backlog increase? Is that because you think volume forecasts are higher, or are there new wins, or you're actually getting a higher percentage of wins on the business that you are bidding on, and if there any change in this relationship with the automakers as you ramp up this backlog?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess the two things I would point out if you think about the backlog we provided to you for the 2010 through 2012 timeframe, probably the biggest changes I guess I would highlight, one is the fact that that backlog 10 through 12 was almost void of North American new business. And now we are seeing some new programs and some chairs there in North America.
  And secondly, I guess the other one is we would expect to see more interior growth in the interior systems that what we had in the backlog in the prior time. So that is what you should hear from us when we come out in 11 through 13.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John, maybe just to add a bit, when we talked about our backlog last year dropping from the $4 billion plus range to the $2.5 billion that we disclosed, a big chunk of that was cancellations and deferrals. And as we have seen the fortunes of our customers improve, new business activity or that product development cycle is speeding up. So there is more business opportunity than, let's say, there has been in the past.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Murphy,  Bank of America/Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it is fair to say that the logjam has been broken in North America, and it is not necessarily a shift in your market share on the bidding process?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would not say -- we would take some share, but it is a combination of all that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think by definition our backlog is incremental business, so by definition it is share growth.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Leiker, Robert Baird.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Leiker,  Robert Baird - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let's talk about China here a little bit, your operations over there, and as these have grown in scale across all the businesses, can you give some context how you manage that and how you make your investment decisions? I think almost all of your operations there are joint ventures, and do you have any intentions of getting majority ownership of wholly-owned operations?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David, just to remind the audience that is listening, most of our joint ventures are with our customers. It's a little bit unique situation. So when we are growing with SAIC affiliates, we are really growing with SAIC or with FAW affiliates as with FAW.
  I think we continue to gain share with them. We are the primary supplier to both of those large OEs. And then also obviously we have penetrated and I signed a group when I was over with Geely. I hope that is going to pan out to something in the future. We have a relationship with Chery, with [GASC].
  To your broader point, I don't believe that we are going to -- it is not our intention right now to try to take bigger ownerships in those joint ventures. We think the model works well for us. It has provided good growth opportunity. We managed those plants. We trained those managers. We run moral surveys and development plans around all of those management teams. And so despite the fact that it is fractured and fragmented by JVs, we are able to get some scale and some consistency across the whole breadth of all those different JV relationships.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Leiker,  Robert Baird - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are you getting dividends out of those operations or are you reinvesting that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are generally reinvesting, but yes, we do get dividends. Because it's not a like for like, David. I guess the other thing maybe I would add is, if you look at our Power Solutions and Building Efficiency business, those operations are 100% owned or we have a couple where we own 80%. But those businesses were really growing primarily through organic growth investments. And if you look at all three of our businesses, we have a significant presence there, managing our growth strategy in those regions. And we talk about that as being key areas where we have been in testing over the last three or four years.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think as an example that would be, if we were to take you to our technology center in [Chan Chun], you would see it is one of the best ones we have in the world.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brett Hoselton, KeyBanc.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brett Hoselton,  KeyBanc - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wanted to talk about your automotive margins for a second. First of all, what are the primary drivers for your increase in automotive margins? Is it simply the reflection of the improvement here in the second quarter, or are you looking for additional significant improvements going forward as it sounds like you might be in Europe?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, it -- well, there are several factors. Clearly volume is the biggest one. We have talked about on incremental volume we are looking for our business to pull through somewhere between 15% and 20%. I am talking here as the industry recovers.
  The profitability of the business that we are launching out of our backlog, again we have talked about that being higher than the business that it is replacing in aggregate. And then with respect to Asia, we certainly have a tail wind in the fact that our equity income is really benefiting our income, and it does not obviously affect our sales. So that is accretive to our margins. So those are the main factors.
  You also made a comment about Europe. We have a good improvement versus Q1, but we still have you can think about a point or so of penalty that we are dealing with associated with some of the launch difficulties and supplier shortages and things like that that I spoke about earlier. So we are definitely anticipating that the European side of things improves further as we go through the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The only thing I would add, Bruce, is I think Europe's margins are being impacted only by the launches, which are good, by the way. It's not like maybe the first quarter where we had more -- we had a couple of launches that we had to fight through. I know it is a typical process associated with launches, the magnitude of them. And, as I said earlier, we have our engineering costs. So our engineering costs were up also in the quarter primarily in Europe as they support these launches.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brett Hoselton,  KeyBanc - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And as you look -- and I apologize as this is a follow-on call -- but as you look at the European margins of 2.4% and you pick up, let's say, 100 bps with the launch costs and distressed supplier costs going away here, how do you then see yourselves going from 3.4%, let's say, up into that 6% to 7% range?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, again I would say we have talked about that being really a question of volume. We have said that I think if you go back in time we have had a target of 6% in automotive. When we did the magnitude of the restructuring here that we did in the downturn, we said, look, we think we can get that 6% to be closer to 7% and that we also felt that our ability to get to that level, we did not need production to be back in that 15 million, 16 million units in North America, let's say, but rather down in that 13 million, 13.5 million range. So that is part of where we need to get to to get to those levels.
  It is really a question of making sure that we launch our new programs in line with the targets that we have, making sure that our commodity costs don't eat into our margins, and we have talked about the fact that 90% of our business is -- we have got full or partial indexing, and then making sure that as the industry recovers we get that 15% to 20% profit pull-through. It is as simple as that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Himanshu Patel, JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Himanshu Patel,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wanted to get a little bit more into the power division. Two questions on that. One is, the two lead recycling plants once they come on stream, how does that affect your earning sensitivity to future lead prices?
  And then the second quarter on power was, you mentioned there was a 200, 250 bps gain from the lead plants coming on stream. How much additional margin expansion would you see from some of the elevated lithium investments you have right now normalizing, or I guess some revenue coming on stream to match that if we are just trying to think out three years from now to figure out a normalized battery division margin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me start. I am going to go back to the investment in the vertical integration in the 200 to 250 basis point improvement. That is assuming that (inaudible) of today's state. The way to think about it would be, if lead goes up, then clearly we would benefit even more from probably the tolling ranges we would have. So it gets even -- it has an even higher margin impact if you believe lead is going to skew higher.
  I mean when we did these transactions, these investments, we looked for a two-year payback is what we are currently projecting on both of them. Just to give you some idea how lucrative it is. Secondly, what it does do to us, it does add a fixed cost element to us to the extent that, in fact, lead went the other way. But we feel good about what those economics are even with a lead pullback.
  In terms of the -- Bruce, you have something you want to add to that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the lithium piece, I think that is a function of really how much -- how successful we are commercially in terms of the support structure we have to put in place. So I'm not in a position to give you a longer-term projection of margins on that, other than what I described to you on the vertical integration fees. That is the best I can do.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would say probably in the next two to three years, what is happening within hybrid is probably not going to be a significant driver of our margins here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think that is fair.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Himanshu Patel,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If I could sneak in one last one. The balance sheet has come a long way. Your equity value has moved up. How are you thinking, Steve, now on acquisitions?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we are fairly looking at what is out there and what we could do that would help benefit our business. We have prioritized and met with our management regarding some of the opportunities that we would look to. Some we believe are actionable; some are not.
  So I guess I would just describe it this way. Clearly our acquisitions are focused on technology, platforms that we can grow from. I would look at all three businesses. I think longer-term, as I have mentioned to you, I believe that BE will still have the lion's share of our M&amp;A activity. But it does not mean that we are going to exclude opportunities in the other two businesses. That is for sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And I would say we did make a small acquisition in this quarter. You can see that from our cash flow. That is a business that provides us with some enhanced capability to do performance contracting, so the lighting and lighting controls side of our business. And we have other I would say small type acquisitions that are in the pipeline. You should expect to see start to flow through here in the next few quarters.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas, Wells Fargo Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich, what is your one question?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I have got about six right here. My one question is on services, just in Building Efficiency. As you look, that business has been down. What was the year-over-year change for that business, that piece of the business this quarter, and what are you seeing right now on that front? Has that started to pick up at all?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For the quarter revenues were down 7% in services, and our order impact -- this is just North America, by the way -- and orders were up 3%. I guess, Steve, do you want to comment on some of the quoting activity?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich, the thing we have been highlighting the whole time is the fact we had not seen a lot of the smaller work, project type work, and just the last 2 weeks we have seen a slight pickup in terms of that. When we look at our pipeline, our pipeline now and what we call prime, or that project type work, is the best it has been in two and a half years. But it's all happened relatively recently. So we are encouraged by that. We are also seeing a lot of activity in terms of what we call PSA schedule service work, and the bidding activity there is the strongest it has been in two years. So we are starting to see some recovery, and that is what we are really pointing to on the service side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just lastly, L&amp;M what are you seeing there? Any pickup there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Not really at this stage. Not really. We're just getting -- we don't have -- usually weather is the driver. This time of year we think what we are doing our service people are primarily doing that scheduled work in the March/April timeframe. The L&amp;M is usually associated with spikes in the weather. There is one where you typically see it or just our ability to penetrate more accounts. Right now at this time of year we are focused pretty much on providing that preventative maintenance work on the PSAs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You might say a little bit as well once the air-conditioning season comes full on and people start turning all this stuff on after being off all winter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Kwas,  Wells Fargo Securities - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. It makes sense. Okay. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Colin Langan, UBS.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Colin Langan,  UBS - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you talk a little bit about Building Efficiency? You are down on average I think 1% in the first half, but your guidance you still think you can do the 5%. That means second half is going to be around 11% in the second half. Can you comment on the pace of that in Q3, Q4, and then what are the main drivers and how dependent are you on the recovery of servicing that 5%?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I mean maybe just one clarification in terms of your math there when you said down 1%, then we need to be up 11%. Keep in mind, our business is very seasonal. More of our revenue flows in the second half. It is not quite as bad as you are suggesting there. But nonetheless, it does need to pick up. I think you need to -- what gives us confidence is, if you look at the businesses that are not flowing through our backlog -- so that's the residential business and the Global Workplace Solutions -- those businesses are up, as I said earlier, double-digit, strong double digits. 40% in the case of our UPG business. So we feel confident that those trends are going to continue and in the case of GWS accelerate.
  If you look at the other businesses that now flow through our backlog, I mean there we take comfort from the quoting activity we have. So the fact that we start to see orders picking up, I mean that is what happens before it turns into revenue. So I think we feel pretty good about that. I would say maybe the only de-rail that is out there for us would be if we have an exceptionally either late start to the cooling season or a very, very cool summer. But those are 1% or 2% deltas. They are not going to change the sign here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think what else I would tell you is we are seeing good pickup in demand from an equipment standpoint, and that is a good forerunner. Secondly, I guess I think the emerging markets are really just trying to pick up when we see some of the order and pipeline activity. The only margin I guess I would tell you that we still don't see recovery happening at is Western Europe. That is the one market that at this stage we are not counting on any growth in the second half.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Colin Langan,  UBS - Analyst   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So in your 5%, the servicing side is not a big portion of that growth, or I mean it's based on mostly business that you're already have planned in the pipeline?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Particularly the Solutions business. If you include that element, that is really where we have got good growth in our backlog, too.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso, Credit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A couple of questions on Europe. First, the revenue there was stronger than we thought it would be. Is there anything in particular that you can point to, a change in mix or a new program that came on? And then just as a point of clarification on your 16.7 build expectation for the year, on your numbers what was that in '09 so I get the percent change right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think that number -- we will have to get back to you. I think it was in the low 15s if I'm not mistaken.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will send you a note on that. I don't remember that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then I'm assuming you meant European automotive for the second part of your question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A couple of things. We are seeing the OE production continues to be better than we were expecting, and paradoxically we are even seeing most of the strengths in the A and B segments. So think about some of the stimulus programs that were in place last year that are not there this year. We never would have thought we would see the growth in the smaller segment.
  I think the other point that is very significant for us here in Europe is a lot of -- we are very well positioned with the cadence of our launches. If you look at where we have strong content, our customers are gaining share in the market. The product is being very well received.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Ceraso,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Anything in particular you can flag in vehicles?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I can tell you where the demand came from. The stronger demand came from Volkswagen in our backlog, Volkswagen, PSA and Daimler. And I think if you go back, we have had this large launch load, and I think part of it is the business we have launched in the last 12 months benefiting from the higher volume.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Like 20, more than 20 of those launches were in Europe this quarter. So I mean we just had a lot of new volume coming out as a result of the new program.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson, Barclays Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I want to talk a bit strategically about the lithium ion battery business. Given how fast that market is going with product announcements since we met with you -- since you had your big meeting in New York. Can you give us a couple of sense of how do you look at the global potential there? You seem very well positioned in Holland, Michigan with Ford. A couple of sub-questions. Is Ford rolling out faster than you think, and should we think about outside there?
  Secondly, on the European side, European OEMs we've got Daimler, Renault teaming up on electric vehicles. Daimler buying a German battery company, BMW doing some ventures. Are you still comfortable that you can grow the European side of the lithium ion battery business, or are the automakers there doing an in-house-based approach?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think if you want me to take a shot at it (multiple speakers) I think it is sort of all of the above. I think it is the sort of difficult characteristics of a nascent industry in that nobody quite knows maybe what the business model is, and so people are taking a taste of it this way and a taste of it that way. And so you are seeing even within OEs, going different routes with different sort of vehicles and different levels of electrification, and I don't know that that is going to settle out anytime soon. So it is hard to give a prediction of what it will look like in three years. I think we are all figuring it out as we go along.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You know, as Glen mentioned, this is still a very immature industry, and my frustration continues to be the fact that there are so many different players, there are so many different chemistries, there are so many different types of packaging and cell configurations, it is going to take a while. But it is just characteristic of a very immature industry. I think we are going to have to watch it evolve here.
  But right now basically we have very few of those consortiums that have been formed. You don't have really standards being formed. I think you have to look over your shoulder a little bit at some of the improvements being made in the combustion engines and some of the mileage efficiency people are talking about. I don't think at this stage if I were looking at strategically trying to size this business that I would change a whole lot from what we have done in the past. I think it still represents probably at the end of this decade maybe 10%, 15% of the market.
  I don't think gasoline prices or government subsidies are going to make a whole lot of difference based on what I know today. It would change medically if you doubled the gas prices here in the US, and it changes the ballgame.
  We still have a hard time seeing how EVs themselves are economically feasible to the consumer. We have done some work in terms of where we think the gasoline prices have to be to make that economic story to work, and it is a ways from where we are today.
  So, anyway, I'm still optimistic. We are going play hard in this segment of our business. We think we have some competitive advantage in relationships, but it's just going to be one of those things where the story is going to change as we play out here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Johnson,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And are the European OEMs who are doing in-house or aligning with each other, are you still in the running with that for future business there, or is it -- as good as it is? Okay. But those are not final decisions that this is 100% in-house sourced?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. Some forms, as Glen mentioned, may take different forms and we may partner in a different way with them, but no, those opportunities do not exist.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shankar, Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shankar,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you talk about any competitive environment in the auto business? You said you're gaining share, and the auto margins that are being fairly good as well now. Can you give a sense of is the pressure you face in that business, if there is any on the pricing side either from your customers or from competitors?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't think a lot has changed from a competitive environment standpoint. We have good competitors. We compete with Lear obviously and Magnum for us here, the ones we would call out. But I don't think a great deal has changed in terms of how we all behave at this stage. So I don't sense there is much difference in terms of pricing pressure. It is probably what it always has been. That is my sense.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shankar,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And from the customer side? I mean in the past, obviously you have seen as supplier margins start getting up, there is obviously a risk of price down. Do you see that being an issue?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think it is probably fair to say that, as volumes continue to increase, There is going to be and there is starting to be a bit more pressure on productivity givebacks. But I think with what the industry has been through, I think there is going to be a lot more discipline to make sure that productivity givebacks to our customers are matched with cost downs within our operations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that is a good point. What Bruce just said is significant, and that is I would tell you that there is just a different change right now. When we deal with some of the OEs where there would have been just unexpected, let's say, historically 2.5%, 3% price down, I think there is a lot more cooperative effort trying to figure out how to make that happen. So when Bruce made that comment about costs -- underlying will be that cost word, that is usually in conjunction with the OE in terms of identifying opportunities. That is what really has changed.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Itay Michaeli.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Itay Michaeli,  - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just a follow-up to that question. Are you seeing the same cooperative effort in some of the new backlog discussions you referenced in North America? If so, would you expect new business to really come in at more profitable rates going forward?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I would. I mean I think for us we are going to be very disciplined in terms of the financial characteristics of business that we book. But I think when you are quoting new business, I don't think that side of the equation has changed. The business model is generally speaking our customer has a target price, usually an aggressive target, and they make a sourcing decision based on somebody's ability to hit that target and their confidence on the technology and quality and the ability to hit the program milestones on time.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Itay Michaeli,  - Analyst   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is helpful. And then maybe one quick one. Can you maybe talk about the outlook for North America's auto margins in the second half of the year? It looked very good and Q2. Maybe what you're embedding into the full-year auto margin guidance for North America?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we are looking at -- I mean if you are looking at our guidance, we are sort of thinking that production is slightly lower in the second half than the first half, okay. And that is obviously due to some of the planned shutdowns that happen every year in Europe and North America in July and August.
  We we are continuing to increase our investment in quoting new business. So, as I say, our fortunes are improving in automotive. We have asked -- our business is going to spend more money looking to grow our backlog further. So that is kind of an investment that we need to make for longer-term growth.
  But I think we are pretty confident. I mean we gave you a range for the full year. I think we are pretty comfortable with that range.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [Kent Newcomb], Wells Fargo Advisory.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kent Newcomb,  Wells Fargo Advisory - Analyst   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Could you share with us any thoughts from the board perhaps on the dividend policy? You have now gone about 10 quarters at the same rate. And with business clearly improving, can we expect some movement here anytime soon?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We will revisit that as we normally do in our November timeframe, and that is when the board meets. That is when we discuss the outlook -- compare our outlook for the new fiscal year.
  If you look at our data right now, our payout ratio is about 27%, and we're pretty proud of the fact that we held our dividend when many cut them. So I understand the tone of your comment, but I think we work very hard to maintain our dividend throughout a very tough year with a very high payout ratio last year.
  So what you should expect from us is a revisit and September announcement in that November timeframe regarding our outlook.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [Tim Deneuer], [Wolf Trend].
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tim Deneuer,  [Wolf Trend] - Analyst   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm wondering if you could provide a little more color on the two Visteon plants, which bankruptcy court recently approved your purchase of? Has that been completed, and can you give a little color on what components are built there, and how you had planned to operate them a bit more profitably?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, so, first of all, they have not yet been completed. I think our target completion date is the end of April, but I could be mistaken. But it's definitely in this current quarter. I don't really want to get into a lot of the details about what we are going -- how we are going to operate those plants versus how they were operated before. But we are confident that they will be accretive to our earnings in the next quarter. So they are not something that we think we are going to lose money on.
  In terms of what they are, they are interior components. And if you think about putting a couple of extra plants into our network here, we think we have some -- the footprint that we have got with these two operations, we have some good potential to launch new business in those operations where we may be would have otherwise had to spend capital in the future. So we have some good synergies buying those, and we think we can operate those very profitably.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We probably have time for one more call.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rod Lache, Deutsche Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rod Lache,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There has not been a lot of talk yet about raw materials on this call, but obviously they have been -- aside from lead -- obviously they have been rising. I was just hoping you can give us some feel for what you're seeing relative to the automotive experience in Building Efficiency businesses as a meaningful headwind at this point. And also, just on the Power Solutions based on where spot prices are currently, can you just give us some feel for your revenue expectations for this year adjusted for spot lead prices?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me start. On the raw materials side, I'm going to start with steel and just tell you a couple of things.
  First of all, from the standpoint of how we locked things in, we are locked in with contracts for the remainder of our fiscal year, let's start with that. And they are consistent with the plan and the guidance we have been providing you.
  Now having said that, we also recognize that steel is going to go up -- as a result of our contracts, is going to go up significantly when we end those contracts, and there will be a hike. I will come back and talk to you about what we have on the other side of the equation with the OEs, but let me complete one more.
  We also see an increase in resin prices, as you would imagine. So we again have that protected through contracts. Now let me go through and explain to you what we did on the other side.
  In some cases there is one large OE here in the US where we are on their steel and resin buying, let's just start with that. So we have no exposure from the standpoint of our contract exposure. And, as Bruce has indicated, if you look across our board at the Asian OEs, the European OEs, those are fairly and very confident about our recovery of those. Timing by a month or two could be an issue, but we feel confident about a high recovery rate on that contractually and just the agreements we have with those firms. So that is the other side of it.
  We would acknowledge that we have been worried about raw materials prices for some time. So just a comment to you, it is something we started worrying about probably two years ago when we came out of this side of the recovery. From a copper standpoint, our policy has been that we have six months of our forward work is hedged.
  Bruce, do you want to talk a little more about that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, it is going to be -- I mean copper, like Steve said, we do hedge six months out. So we will have a little bit of a headwind here in the second half of the year associated with copper, but not a meaningful amount. And if copper continues to run up, then at least in the Building Efficiency side of the business, historically there has been a good pattern of the industry passing that on through higher prices. I guess we would expect that would continue. But that would be more of an 2011 issue than a 2010 issue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then in terms of Power Solutions and our assumption regarding lead, Bruce? I know we've have had a packet of about 2200, right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes and it has been pretty consistent for a change.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that is $2200 a metric ton for those in the audience, and it has been plus or minus the number for probably the last four or five months?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce McDonald,  Johnson Controls - EVP &amp; CFO   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Roell,  Johnson Controls - Chairman &amp; CEO   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it really has stabilized. We are not seeing the upward pressure on lead at this stage.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glen Ponczak,  Johnson Controls - Executive Director, IR   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, thanks, everybody, for all of your good questions. It is Glen here. I'm available for the balance of the day for any follow-up. Have a good weekend.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for participating today. You may disconnect at this time.
 
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2010 Johnson Controls Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>MILWAUKEE</city>
  <companyName>Johnson Controls Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>JCI^I16</companyTicker>
  <startDate>23-Apr-10 3:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>96304</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL />
  <ISIN />
</Event>