<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="4932218" lastUpdate="Thursday, November 8, 2012 at 1:34:16am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="4932218.F" expirationDate="Wednesday, November 7, 2012 at 3:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of KEY.TO earnings conference call or presentation 7-Nov-12 3:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q3 2012 Keyera Corp Earnings Conference Call

CALGARY Nov 8, 2012 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Keyera Corp earnings conference call or presentation Wednesday, November 7, 2012 at 3:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  John Cobb
      Keyera Corporation - VP, Investor Relations
   *  Jim Bertram
      Keyera Corporation - CEO
   *  David Smith
      Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Carl Kirst
      BMO Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Rob Hope
      TD Securities - Analyst
   *  Robert Kwan
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Robert Catellier
      Macquarie Capital - Analyst
   *  Matthew Akman
      Scotiabank - Analyst
   *  Steven Paget
      FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. My name is Kyle and I'll be your conference operator today. At this time, I'd like to welcome everyone to the Keyera Corporation third quarter results conference call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent background noise. After the speaker's remarks, there will be a question and answer session. (Operator Instructions) Thank you. Mr. Cobb, you may begin your conference.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Cobb,  Keyera Corporation - VP, Investor Relations   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Kyle, and good morning. It's my pleasure to welcome you to Keyera's 2012 third quarter results conference call. With me are Jim Bertram, Chief Executive Officer, and David Smith, President and Chief Operating Officer, and interim CFO. In a moment, David and Jim will discuss our business, as well as provide additional information on our financial results. At the conclusion of the formal remarks, we'll open the call for questions.
 Before we begin, however, I would like to remind listeners that some of the comments and answers that we will be providing today speak to future events. These forward-looking statements are given as of today's date and reflect events or outcomes that management currently expects to occur based on their beliefs about the relevant material factors, our understanding of the business, and the environment in which we operate.
 Because forward-looking statements address future events and conditions, they necessarily involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially. Some of these risks and uncertainties include fluctuations in the supply, demand, and pricing for natural gas, NGLs, and iso-octane, the activities of producers, other industries and other industry players, our operating and other costs; the weather, governmental and regulatory action, and other risks as they are more fully set out in our publicly filed disclosure documents available on SEDAR and on our website.
 We encourage you read to review the MD&amp;A, which can be found in our 2012 third quarter report and our annual information form, both of which are available on our website and on SEDAR.
 With that, I will turn it over to Jim Bertram, Chief Executive Officer. Go ahead, Jim.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, John, and good morning everyone and thank you for joining us here this morning on the call. With me this morning in addition to David and John are Steven Kroeker as well as Eileen Marikar. I'd like to acknowledge Steven Kroeker in particular who is Keyera's new Chief Financial Officer. So Save will retain that title for another hour or so. Steven has been a key member of our executive team for over six years. Among his many contributions, he's been instrumental in identifying non-deductible successfully executing our strategic acquisitions at the right price, enabling us to grow our cash flow and add value for our shareholders. This experience together with his background in capital markets set about nicely for this new opportunity. Steven has been a big part of the Keyera team, and we're glad to have him, and wish him well in his new role.
 The third quarter was a very busy time in Keyera's operational and business development areas. Operationally, we undertook three maintenance turnarounds and completed repairs, modifications, and remediation work at three gas plant. On the business development front, we were successful in attracting new business opportunities in all three business segments. Demand for services remains strong this quarter in both the gathering and processing, and NGL infrastructure areas. And we are excited about the new opportunities we see ahead for us.
 On a sad note, in September we lost the Chairman of our Board, Peter Lougheed, who passed away after a short illness. Peter had been our Chairman since we went public in 2003. Much has been written about Peter's contribution for the problems of Alberta and to Canada. Peter brought that same passion and commitment to Keyera. He often said how proud he was to be involved with our Company. All of us at Keyera feel proud and very privileged to have had the honor to work with him. He will be missed.
 Yesterday, we announced the appointment of Bob Catell as Keyera's Chairman of the Board of Directors. Bob has been a director of Keyera since 2003 and in his role as Chairman and CEO of Keyspan Corporation, was instrumental in the creation of Keyera in 1998. Bob brings a wealth of leadership experience in the energy sector and we look forward to continuing to work with him in his new position. The continuity achieved with Bob stepping into this role, together with the depth of talent of our other directors will provide a solid foundation as Keyera looks to fill the vacancy that we now have on the Board.
 Keyera's financial results in the third quarter were led by continued growth in the NGL infrastructure. Overall, EBITDA for the third quarter was CAD72 million, lower than the CAD77 million posted in the third quarter of last year. Although one-time repairs and remediation expense affected the financial results in the gathering and processing business, we continue to see producer activity driving our growth at several of our facilities, and the marketing segment continues to perform well despite weak propane fundamentals.
 On the strength of our cash flow growth and the outlook for the coming year, we are pleased to announce a 6% in the dividend per share to CAD0.18 per share, per month. In the gathering and processing business, gross total throughput in the third quarter averaged just under 1.2 billion cubic feet per day, about the same as the third quarter of last year and only slightly lower than the second quarter of 2012. Continued solid performance at the Rimbey and Minnehik Buck Lake gas plants was offset by lower throughput in the quarter at the Strachan and Edson plants, where plant repairs resulted in lower throughput in the quarter at those facilities. Repairs at these facilities were completed in the quarter and both plants were operating at their previous levels.
 We are encouraged by producer activity around the Simonette plants. Late in the quarter, we began receiving new gas production from South and East of the Simonette plants, with two newly completed producer-owned gathering pipelines. Indications from the producers are that these volumes, coming from the Montney and Duvernay drilling in the area will increase over the fourth quarter. We continue to pursue an expansion of these facilities, including the addition of deep cut NGL extraction and continue to discuss commercial terms with producers in the area.
 At the Caribou Gas Plant, our producer owned pipeline was completed in the third quarter and gas began flowing through the plant from lands southwest of the plant late in the quarter. The producer suggests that production will increase in the area over the next 12 months as the Montney zone continues to be developed.
 In West Central Alberta, producers continued to drill a number of zones, including the Glauconite, Cardium, and Duvernay horizons. Two producers in the process of building pipelines to tie in new production to the Minnehik Buck Lake and Strachan gas plants. Keyera has entered into agreements with producers to purchase the pipelines when they are completed over the next nine months or so. Throughout remains steady at Rimbey, driven by deliveries to the Carlos pipeline. We have been approached by producers in the Williston Green area, west of the Rimbey gas plant, who are interested in a new gathering pipeline through Rimbey from that area. This is an area that saw significant land sale activity over the past two years where a number of Duvernay wells have been drilled.
 Altogether, there are eight new producer initiated gathering pipelines completed or under construction in 2012 that will deliver gas through Keyera plants. In September, we announced that we are proceeding with a project to enhance NGL recoveries at the Rimbey gas plant. This CAD210 million project will involve the installation of a 400 million cubic feet per day turbo expander. Upon completion, the turbo expander will enable us to extract up to 20,000 barrels per day of ethane from the raw gas delivered to the plant, as well as incremental propane, butane, and condensate. Based on the current schedule, the project is expected to be completed in 2014.
 In support of this project, we have entered into long-term agreements relating to the processing raw gas plant and the sale of ethane. In addition, providing incremental cash flow for Keyera, the project may allow us to further expand the NGL extraction capacity significantly at the Rimbey Plant in the future with only modest capital investments.
 During the quarter, we were successful in acquiring additional ownership in the Brazeau North and Pembina North gas plants to bring our ownership to 100%. We also acquired an additional 17% of the Minnehik Buck Lake Gas Plant, bringing our ownership in that plant to 80%.
 In September, we shut down the Cranberry pipeline, which delivers condensate from the Chinchaga Gas Plant due to our lease from the pipeline. Approximately CAD2 million was spent on soil removal and remediation work in September and we expect another CAD2 million to CAD3 million could be spent between now and next summer to complete the work.
 Maintenance turnarounds were completed successfully at the Gilby and Nordegg River gas plants in the third quarter. This work was completed on time and on budget, enables us to provide long-term efficient and reliable services to our producer customers. This completes the scheduled maintenance turnarounds for this year.
 With that, I'd like to turn it over to David to review our liquids business unit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Jim. The liquids business unit delivered strong results again in the third quarter. In the NGL infrastructure segment, we continue to benefit from the growth in NGL supplies from liquids rich drilling in Western Canada, and from increasing production of bitumen from the oil sands. This drove strong demand for services in all areas of the business, which, with the addition of Alberta EnviroFuels earlier this year, resulted in record results in the NGL infrastructure segment again this quarter.
 As a result of the increase, NGL supply volumes or NGL fractionators are now operating at capacity and we are seeing increased storage demand as well. With fractionation capacity becoming tighter in Alberta, we are working with our producer customers to find ways for them to secure access to capacity all along our NGL value chain. An example of this is the project we announced in September at our fractionation storage facility in Fort Saskatchewan. We are embarking on construction of a 30,000 barrel per day de-ethanizer that will allow us to process C2-plus NGL mix delivered to the facility. To underpin the economics, we have contracted a majority of the capacity to a deep basin producer. The producer will get long-term access to the NGL fractionation, storage, and delivery chain for their C2-plus mix, at a time when capacity at these facilities is growing tighter.
 In return, Keyera receives a long-term fee for service cash flow stream and the opportunity to access additional NGL products. This project is anticipated to cost about CAD110 million and is scheduled to be on stream in 2014.
 Demand for diluent logistics services, as a result of increasing bitumen production, is also benefiting our business. On July 1, our diluent services agreement with Imperial Oil for their Kearl Project began generating fee for service cash flows. These cash flows will increase when the Kearl project begins operation, which Imperial has indicated will be early in the new year.
 To meet new demand for services from other customers, we have a number of facility expansion initiatives underway. The development of our 12th storage cavern at KFS remains on schedule to go into operation next year. We completed the well bore for our 13th cavern in September and are moving into the washing phase of development for that cavern. In support of this additional capacity, we began constructing a new brine pond on the site, which we currently estimate completing in late 2013.
 Imports of diluent into Alberta via rail continued to increase this year, and in order to meet the increased demand for rail outgoing services, we are moving to a 24-hour a day, 7 day a week operation at ADT beginning in December. In the third quarter, we began construction on the South Cheecham rail and truck terminal, which we announced in June. This is the latest initiative in our strategy of expanding our service offering to the oil sands sector. The initial phase of the terminal will enable bitumen producers to deliver diluent via rail to oil sands developments in the Athabasca region and it will also allow customers to load diluted bitumen onto rail cars for delivery to upgraders across North America.
 In September, we announced an agreement to acquire a rail and truck terminal from Exxon Mobil, located in Hull, Texas near Mont Belvieu. Our plan is to use the terminal to handle the receipt and delivery of propane, butane, and NGL mix. The terminal has pipeline connections to Exxon Mobil's storage, fractionation, and refinery facilities in the area and can deliver products into the Mont Belvieu market. We have completed our due diligence work and expect to close the acquisition later this month. We need to do some work to refurbish the facility before we can return the terminal to service, and this work is expected to be completed in 2013. Total cost of the purchase and refurbishment work is anticipated to be in the range of CAD10 million to CAD15 million. We believe that the facility could assist with the movement of propane volumes by rail from Western Canada to access markets in the Mont Belvieu area.
 Alberta EnviroFuels, our iso-octane producing facility at Edmonton, contributed to our results again in the third quarter, despite being offline in September and part of October for its scheduled maintenance turnaround. We are very pleased with how smoothly the turnaround went. Alberta EnviroFuels is a very large and complex facility and significant work was required to complete all of the inspections and repairs that were needed at the facility. The CAD17 million cost of the turnaround was actually slightly lower than what we had anticipated when we acquired the facility. However, in addition to the turnaround work, we also replaced catalysts and completed several other maintenance projects that were outside of the turnaround scope. These added another CAD8 million of maintenance capital costs to the total cost of the turnaround.
 Alberta EnviroFuels returned to full production on October 18th. The success of the turnaround was due to the extensive planning and hard work by the entire team at the facility and I'd like to thank them for their contribution to our success.
 As with other facilities in our NGL infrastructure segment, Alberta EnviroFuels provides services to Keyera's marketing segment and charges the marketing segment an internal transfer fee for producing the iso-octane. This fee revenue is included in the NGL infrastructure segment as are the operating costs associated with the facility. The margin generated from the sale of the iso-octane net of the butane feedstock cost is included in our marketing segment financial results.
 Modifications are well underway on our rail loading facility at the Edmonton terminal to enable us to load iso-octane onto rail cars. The Edmonton terminal is already pipeline connected to AEF the final work on the rack itself is expected to be completed this month. We are working with customers across North America who are interested in purchasing iso-octane for delivery by rail. We are encouraged by the interest we have been seeing from our customers, and are optimistic that this new delivery method will help us increase the utilization levels at AEF during 2013.
 In our marketing segment, physical sales of butane and condensate were strong in the third quarter and our crude oil midstream business also delivered good results. Offsetting this were weak results in our propane business, lower sales of iso-octane due to the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels, and realized losses from financial contracts related to butane and condensate particularly.
 Overall, sales volumes in the third quarter were about 83,000 barrels per day, 21% higher than in the third quarter of 2011. Third quarter demand for propane was weak, as is often the case at this time of the year. The continued oversupply of propane on the continent continued to put downward pressure on propane prices throughout the quarter. However, the propane forward physical and financial contracts, put in place to protect the value of our propane inventory, has been effective. And as a result, we anticipate stronger results from propane going forward.
 Butane margins and volumes remained steady in the quarter, other than at the Alberta EnviroFuels facility, where the turnaround in September resulted in reduced consumption of butane feedstock in the quarter. Diluent demand continued to be strong throughout the quarter and we imported increased volumes of condensate by rail using our rail offloading, storage, and pipeline connections at Alberta diluent terminal. And again, this quarter, our crude oil midstream activities posted strong results.
 As part of our risk management program we have entered into financial contracts related to certain future purchase arrangements for butane and condensate. While our propane hedging strategy is intended to protect the value of our propane in inventory, our butane and condensate hedging strategy is intended to both protect the product inventory when these products are held in storage, but also to align the pricing terms of future physical supply with our sales arrangements to reduce the basis risk.
 In the third quarter, we incurred approximately a CAD14 million realized loss from the settlement of these contracts, the majority of which related to butane held in inventory. Partly because of the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels -- sorry, partly because the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels reduced butane feedstock demand in September, the gain that would have been realized from the physical sale of butane was not captured in the third quarter. Furthermore, the unrealized gain from the higher value of the butane inventory is not reflected in Keyera's financial results until the butane is consumed at Alberta EnviroFuels. This creates a timing mismatch that we expect will be corrected in the fourth quarter when the physical butane is removed from inventory.
 And now with that, I'll turn briefly to the financial results. Net earnings in the third quarter were CAD14 million, or CAD0.18 per share, compared to CAD39 million, or CAD0.54 per share, in the same quarter last year. The lower earnings were largely due to non-cash items, primarily impairment charges of both CAD30 million or about CAD0.38 per share related to the Chinchaga and Nevis gas lines.
 As Jim mentioned, EBITDA was CAD72 million, slightly lower than the CAD77 million recorded in the third quarter of 2011. Distributable cash flow was CAD19 million, or CAD0.24 per share, compared to CAD51 million, or CAD 0.71 per share last year. The lower distributable cash flow was largely due to almost CAD30 million or CAD0.38 per share of maintenance capital expenditures incurred in the third quarter. This number is unusually high due to the size and scope of the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels. Dividends to shareholders in the quarter were CAD39 million, or CAD0.51 per share.
 Our gathering and processing business experienced continued strong demand for services, although repair and remediation costs reduced results in the quarter. Operating margin was about CAD36 million and included the effect of about CAD6 million of unusual items, both higher costs and lower revenues. This compares to about CAD37 million recorded in the third quarter of last year.
 The NGL infrastructure segment set another record for the third quarter, posting an operating margin of CAD30 million, 77% higher than the same period last year. As I mentioned earlier, income from Alberta EnviroFuels and continued strong demand for fractionation and storage, and diluent logistics contributed to these record results.
 In the third quarter, the Marketing business delivered operating margin of CAD16 million, compared to CAD32 million in the third quarter of last year, which was a particularly good quarter. Butane and condensate performed very well, as did our crude oil midstream business. However, offsetting this in the third quarter of this year was weaker propane results and lower iso-octane volumes due to the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels.
 NGL inventory at the end of the third quarter was CAD196 million, CAD27 million higher than at the end of the third quarter last year. This difference was largely due to higher butane inventory, partly as a result of the turnaround at Alberta EnviroFuels in the third quarter.
 Keyera incurred approximately CAD400,000 of cash taxes in the third quarter, about the same as in the same period last year. These taxes primarily related to one of Keyera's subsidiaries. Keyera continues to forecast current income taxes for 2012 and for 2013 in the range of 1% to 3% of annual cash flow before deducting maintenance capital and taxes. These forecasts are based on Keyera's estimates of future cash flow and the timing of future growth projects, and are subject to change.
 As discussed, maintenance turnarounds were completed at the Gilby and Nordegg River gas plants, and at the Alberta EnviroFuels facility in the third quarter. In addition, repairs and modifications to the sulfur plants at the Nevis and Strachan gas plants, as well as other maintenance projects undertaken in the quarter resulted in unusually maintenance capital expenditures of almost CAD30 million in the quarter.
 Finally, we have included our third quarter supplementary information on our website concurrent with the release of our 2012 third quarter results. This information includes both operating and financial data for each segment of our business. You can reference our 2012 third quarter report for details on how to access the supplementary data.
 Jim, that concludes my remarks. Back to you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, David. I'd like to conclude with a few comments about what I see for Keyera going forward. The last couple months we've been focused on developing our budget for 2013, and with that developing a better sense of what opportunities are available to us in 2014 and beyond. The results of this work demonstrates to us that the future looks very bright, despite the challenges we see from major structural changes in the NGL and natural gas business, driven by technological advances and the continued focus on liquids-rich drilling.
 We remain encouraged by the producer activity around our plants and the new business opportunities that may evolve from that. Continued growth in the oil sands developments continues to present new opportunities for us, whether in Fort Saskatchewan, ADT, or Cheecham. While it's too early to know what benefits we may see from [Hull], we know that having access into the Mont Belvieu marketplace is beneficial for our marketing business and we're excited to develop new business in the area. Producers need real access to new markets and this could be the start of that.
 Yesterday, we announced that we anticipate a growth capital program for 2013, excluding acquisitions, of between CAD250 million and CAD300 million, the largest in our history. More than two-thirds of this forecast is allocated to projects that are already underway that will deliver cash flow for our customers in the future. With the level of industry activity, current projects underway, and other opportunities under consideration, we anticipate that our growth capital investments for the next several years will be significantly higher than the recent expenditure levels.
 With the continued strength of our business and our view of the future, we announced yesterday an increase in our dividend. Effective with our November dividend, payable on December 17th this year, our dividend will increase by 5.9% to CAD0.18 per share per month or CAD2.16 per share per year. This our tenth dividend increase since going public in 2003 and third since converting to a corporation almost two years ago.
 Our 7.5% compound annual growth rate in dividends per share since inception demonstrates that Keyera has many of the characteristics necessary to weather the current economic climate and continue to grow our business. We have our customers, service mindset, facilities in strategic locations, a conservative balance sheet, and a very strong focus on execution.
 John, that concludes my comments and we can open up the lines for questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Cobb,  Keyera Corporation - VP, Investor Relations   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Jim. Please go ahead, Kyle.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) Your first question comes from the line of Carl Kirst from BMO Capital Markets. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Carl Kirst,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Good morning everybody. Maybe if I could start on the liquids side. So maybe a question for Dave, but I don't think you can quantitatively answer this, but maybe just sort of color. When we look at the lower propane margins and the challenge recognizing there's some seasonality here in the third quarter, I think when we were coming out of last winter, entering into 2012 there was a feeling that margins were going to get challenged both because we had sort of crappy propane market, but also as we switched to using purity products that that in and of itself might structurally limit perhaps some of the margin.
 And so, as you look at the propane opportunities today or the propane challenges, how much of it is just sort of the state of the market, which hopefully will improve with a normal winter, exports, et cetera, and how much of it is just sort of structural by, hey, this is just in effect to give up we had to do by going to purity propane hedges?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I think there's sort of two parts to your question, Carl. One is what's going on in the North American supply and demand fundamentals and then the second one relates more specifically to our hedging strategy. So maybe I'll start with the first one. Propane, to me, right now as we start the winter looks a lot like the natural gas in North America. We have -- throughout North America, we have a lot of propane in storage. Strong winter demand will help certainly to kind of put things back to normal. But the reality is that we have production of propane, supply of propane throughout North America that's increased a fair bit over the last two or three years, and relative to demand still results in an oversupply situation.
 And so, structurally the way that that gets addressed as we look forward is through additional propane exports offshore. And we see investments in the US, particularly in additional terminal capacity to make that happen. So we're cautiously optimistic if you look out one or two years, but we still are in a situation currently where we have excess inventory and continued oversupply.
 Having said that, from our point of view it's certainly a challenge for the industry in Western Canada to deal with that oversupply situation, but it's not something that concerns us, particularly from our business. As you point out, we've adopted a somewhat different hedging strategy and I would also mention a somewhat different supply and sales strategy with our propane movements as we head into this winter. We probably have a little bit more modest profit opportunity as you point out, but a fair bit less in terms of potential margin variability from propane as we look forward.
 We had about CAD13 million of unrealized gains on our propane hedges, both physical and financial as we head into the fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Carl Kirst,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Would the Exxon terminal near Mont Belvieu I would assume an understanding basis between Conway and Belvieu is kind of floated around a lot in the third quarter, but presumably as that comes on you've got access to that. That should be something that structurally should help your propane margins, should it not?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We're cautiously optimistic that that in fact will be a big benefit. We expect that the Belvieu market will be the higher value market and so propane barrels will want to try and get in there. We think that the Hull terminal will allow us to access that in material volumes. It's just a little bit difficult to be able to say too much about that right now as we still work through what we need to do.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Carl Kirst,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Understood. And then last question, if I could, just in sticking with marketing and looking at the butane plus. That part of the business will presumably continue to be hedged with crude oil, as you guys have stated in the past. Are there any correlation disconnections up or down that we should be aware of as far as impacting your business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There's always a certain amount of basis differential that becomes difficult for us to completely hedge away as a result of infrastructure constraints among the various NGL hubs. Having said that, Carl, we feel pretty confident with respect to the pricing arrangements we have on the supply and sale side, as well as the hedging arrangements that we have in place to correlate with that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Carl Kirst,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks so much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question comes from the line of Rob Hope with TD Securities. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rob Hope,  TD Securities - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Maybe just to continue on the propane theme, maybe you could frame how you're thinking about the Alberta propane market post Cogent being taken out of service? Do you see an opportunity to move more volumes down to Belvieu on rail car? And do you expect that you could have a pickup in marketing margins there assuming that the basis differential between Alberta widens?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We're certainly spending a lot of time thinking about that, Rob, and talking with the producers and with the potential customers at the other end of the value chain. Certainly, we feel like we're very well positioned with our rail loading capabilities and our storage capabilities at Edmonton to be able to help to alleviate the constraints that the Cogent reversal might create in the propane market. That's still more than a year away. So we're still trying to understand what the implications are and what the appropriate solutions are.
 Having said all that, I do -- I am optimistic that because of the positioning of our infrastructure that we should be able to grow the business in meeting those needs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rob Hope,  TD Securities - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And maybe just one further point to that. When Cogent returns with diluent service, would that potentially take away volumes from South Cheecham South as well as Edmonton?
 Potentially, yes. We were asked the same question, of course, a couple years ago when Southern Lights was just starting up. There's certainly demand, continued growth and demand for condensate in the oil sands in Western Canada, which is why you've seen the development of Southern Lights and the proposed reversal of the Cogent pipeline. We believe that there will be more than enough demand for the barrels that we'll move on those pipelines, along with imports of condensate by rail.
 Keep in mind that one of the advantages that we have with rail is the flexibility to source supplies that aren't pipeline connected. And so we're quite optimistic that we will continue to see substantial volumes both at Edmonton and at South Cheecham.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rob Hope,  TD Securities - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question comes from the line of Robert Kwan from RBC Capital Markets. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Kwan,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just wondering if you can expand on the KFS fractionator expansion opportunities. And Jim, you mentioned something around the DF expansion, creating a potential for modest capital investment to further expand the facility. Was that separate from the T3-plus fractionator expansion? Or is there something else that you're looking at in terms of de-bottlenecking?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I think just right now we're looking at the expansion that we talked about in the press release. Clearly, I talked about structural changes. We believe there will continue to be pressure on fractionation capacity in Alberta. Certainly, it's tight today. So we along with others I'm sure believe that you're going to have to have further fractionation by expansion at Fort Saskatchewan. It's the logical place to do it in Alberta given its proximity to the pipes and to the marketplace for diluent, for butane, for the movement of propane out of here.
 So we haven't announced anything, but we certainly continue to look for ways to expand our frac capacity. Because I believe over the next year the industry is going to require it very, very quickly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Kwan,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just on the comment around the modest capital investment to expand capacity, is that related to the C3-plus, like the 30,000 barrel a day expansion? Or is that something smaller?
 Robert, I think that was referencing Rimbey. I think what we believe there, once we have the turbo up and running, we still have access to a very, very efficient lean oil system at Rimbey that we can utilize if volumes in the area turn out to be more than 400 million a day. And there's certainly some scenarios where that could happen.
 So that was one of the I guess add-ons that we get at Rimbey is today we have a very efficient lean oil system, but we're going to load in to make it better with the turbo, but still have access to that lean oil system for minimal capital investments if it's required.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Kwan,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Jim. And just with respect to the stepped up CapEx that you're seeing over the next several years relative to the history, can you just talk about the funding strategy, particularly just balancing the timing of the need for funds versus the conservatism of accessing the capital markets while the markets are receptive?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I think we believe what we see on our plate today is staged out quite evenly over 2013. We certainly do believe we'll have increased cash flows from the projects that we've been putting in place over the last couple of years, start-up of Kearl. And I think the full year run of the iso-octane business I think that, all of that, plus a drip, we certainly believe these initiatives we have in front of us today are funded and we don't see a reason to go back to the market.
 But we'll continue to address that and we certainly anticipate over time other opportunities will, whether acquisitions or further organic growth projects come into play, we can address them. But we're pretty comfortable with it right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Kwan,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question comes from the line of Robert Catellier from Macquarie. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Catellier,  Macquarie Capital - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was wondering if you could address some of the changes in the landscape, particularly around Simonette? On the one hand, you have Alliance pipeline coming out with some new service offerings and then you have one of the producers in the area being acquired by a major that's a big customer of yours. How do you see that -- those two dynamics impacting your business, particularly around Simonette?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I think, Robert, Simonette is an evolving story and I think evolving exciting story because of the geology in the area. I think since we've owned Simonette, not much more than two years ago, we've seen the Montney play evolve to the south and in and around the plant. And I think today the Montney play to the northwest is exciting, maybe more exciting than any of the other stuff given its liquid rich nature and some of the recent drilling successes there.
 And then to the east, south, the Duvernay play and all along you've got the cretaceous stacking. So the geology is what's driving all of this and for Exxon to come in and make a position, as well as two or three other majors tells me that there's some serious long-term resource in this area. So I think from our perspective we're trying to be sort of -- be calculated and understand the ultimate size of a gas plant and what's required by our customers in that area.
 So I appreciate Alliance can be and will be a competitor in there, but I just come back to the size of the prize in Simonette, Rest Haven area is enormous and I think we and producers will have to continually work to sort out what's the right sized gas plant. And there will be numerous gas plants in this area is my belief is it's that perspective. And it'll just take a while to sort out, but the economics appear attractive because it's very liquids rich and appears quite prolific. And you're dealing with a number of very prospective geological zones here.
 So it's exciting but complex and I think we just want to be guarded and careful about how we go forward on this, because these are going to be big capital expenditures.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Catellier,  Macquarie Capital - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, is there anything you're hearing back on Alliance specifically that colors how you might go after it? Or is it still a question of just waiting to see how things evolve in the area?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My view on Alliance versus Keyera or other producers, or midstreamers in the area is that I really believe that the Montney and the Duvernay plays in those areas are all about condensate. And so I think that producers are going to want access to their condensate and their butanes. That's what creating and riving the value of the play for now. I believe that condensate and butane have market share in Alberta, not in the US. So I think that producers are going to certainly strive to access those barrels.
 And then how deep you go in terms of your fractionators, whether you take ethane or propane, those will move around and certainly today they're not as attractive. But again, people develop these resources for the long-term. And I believe that propane will continue to have premium value over gas and ethane as well. So I think that -- I believe over the long-term NGLs left in Alberta make the most economic sense for producers. And ultimately, that will drive their economics to probably gas plants up and down the deep basin and NGLs streamed into the Edmonton, Fort Saskatchewan region.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Catellier,  Macquarie Capital - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Typically on the capital spending front, you've been reluctant to build facilities on spec. However, it looks like there's seemingly a wave of fractionator demand coming down the pipeline. By now you know about Pembina's aspirations to expand their system, their NGL system in particular, which term insurance seems obvious that there's a need for additional fractionation capacity. What's your appetite for perhaps building a fractionator that's partially underpinned with long-term commercial agreements and may be taking some of the volume on, some of the capacity on spec?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think that we've, whether it's fractionators, or pipelines, or that, we've always been prepared to take some risk and I think it's pretty obvious, too, that the industry does need more frac capacity. And it'll be a combination of producer commitments as well as some comfort level that there's more frac capacity required that will drive us or others.
 I think we look at it, we tend to look at it a little differently. We come back to fractionation capacity that will be required to service the NGLs coming out of our gas plants. And clearly as we go forward in what I call structural changes, Keyera is going to make sure that they have the ability to fractionate the NGL mix that comes out of the Keyera gas plants. We certainly don't want to be in a position where our customers can't access fractionation if they're going to process gas through our plants.
 So that's starting to change a little bit of our thinking around strategy, but clearly our integrated business model we think is the right one in this world. A non-deductible we're just focused on trying to understand what's going to come out of our gas plants over the next three to five years and making sure we have the right frac and ability to handle those products downstream from a market perspective as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Catellier,  Macquarie Capital - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My last question has to do with kind of the landscape again, this time on Enbridge. After talking about it for a while, they finally made another investment in the midstream sector, this time some gathering compression from [Ancana]. How do you see their involvement altering the landscape in your franchise areas, if at all?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think Enbridge is a good company and they make lots of investments in pipelines and have made investments in these types of assets. So competition is good. We've always welcomed it. I think it keeps us -- make everybody work harder for the customer. So I don't have any real issues with Enbridge. As I said before, there is a tremendous amount of capital required to build out the infrastructure in Alberta and Western Canada over the next ten years to meet -- stay ahead of the liquids rich resource drilling that is just starting to occur. This is a resource that I think has decades of development. And at the same time, there's a tremendous amount of capital required for infrastructure to continue to stay in front of the oil sands development from a diluent solvent handling. So there's lots of room for competitors in this space.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Catellier,  Macquarie Capital - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question comes from the line of Matthew Akman from Scotiabank. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Akman,  Scotiabank - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much. On the AEF maintenance, it looks like you guys might have done a little bit more than anticipated. I'm not sure about that going in. I'm just wondering given this is the first time you've really had a chance to do a thorough look through the plant, what did you find? Is the major maintenance over? Do you have to carry some to next year? And what were your learnings of the activities?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew, I think our, as we sit now with the turnaround completed I think we're very pleased. I'll fully admit that we were a little anxious when we bought the facility because we knew that the turnaround in September was coming up and the Alberta EnviroFuels facility is quite different in its nature than the gas plants and fractionation facilities that we're used to. But I give full credit to the team at Alberta EnviroFuels because they planned the turnaround carefully and I think they understood what the uncertainties were going in. We had some issues with a unit called the all-flex reactor that ended up costing us more money and costing us a little bit of time than what was anticipated. But even with that at the end of the day, although the schedule was a little bit longer than what we had anticipated, what we had planned, the cost for the turnaround itself was pretty much bang on to what we had budgeted and we're very pleased to have the plan back up and running.
 In terms of what we found, I think the plant is extremely well maintained. The people take a great pride of ownership there. I think if you were to wander around it you'd come to the same conclusion very quickly and we're quite optimistic that it will be able to run smoothly over the next four years. And I'll tell you that the team there is very anxious for us to be able to find new markets by rail for iso-octane because they would love nothing more than to be able to operate that plant at 100% utilization.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Akman,  Scotiabank - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's great. So it sounds like no more major turnarounds that could slip into next year on that plant?
 No, we would fully anticipate that the next turnaround will be four years from now. Having said that, there are some maintenance capital type projects at AEF because of the nature of the facility that are ongoing, things like vessel maintenance, and catalyst purchase, and things like that, that are probably a little bit higher than what you'd see in a gas line, for instance. But I don't think we've found anything that would change the outlook that we talked about when we first bought the facility.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Akman,  Scotiabank - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. And I just wanted to touch quickly on the G&amp;P segment. I think Jim you mentioned that a couple producers [got] into Simonette and began delivering some gas. Is that going to be meaningful increase in volume as far as Simonette goes? Or can you put some more quantification around that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Bertram,  Keyera Corporation - CEO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would say one of the pipes that tie in, there was a 12-inch I think 60 kilometer pipeline right to the east, through the heart of some pretty prospective land purchases over the last couple years. So (inaudible) it ramps up and how many producers ultimately come into it will be dependent. But to put some perspective around it, our 12-inch Carlos pipeline we anticipate 130 million, 140 million a day can come through that. So it certainly has the size.
 The second line to the south again into a pretty interesting Montney area by one of the traditional players in that area, tied into a 12-inch line that we own. So again, we anticipate some pretty significant volumes. This, as I said before, this area geologically has tremendous potential and so I fully expect these pipes over time to have a lot of gas come through them.
 We know that the 150 million a day gas line that we've got today is going to get filled with existing production in the area. We know we absolutely have to expand a facility in the area or somebody has to expand a facility in the area based on the geology. So there's a tremendous amount of potential and it's just trying to understand what's the right way to go about it, what's the right type of facility for the extraction of the NGLs. Some of the issues that I think we in the industry have to get through first.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Akman,  Scotiabank - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, guys. I'll leave it there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) Your next question comes from the line of Steven Paget from FirstEnergy. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Paget,  FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning and thank you. It looks like we're seeing Alberta become a more balanced butane market versus the butane long market that it used to be. Can you [cure] a benefit from possible butane imports and/or do you see any problems for AEF in possibly getting the butane it needs?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven, I think that we have seen an evolution in butane supply and demand in Western Canada over the last few years. We at our facilities have been seasonally importing butane by rail to meet [defaults]. Butane is an interesting commodity because you'll be exporting it by rail at certain times of the year and importing it by rail at other times of the year. Your question is an interesting one as we look forward because we do anticipate increasing production of NGLs, including butane, in Western Canada. And certainly, we've seen increasing production of butane throughout North America over the course of the last two or three years, which has resulted in some softness in the butane price relative to WTI.
 So I think from the point of view of AEF that's a good thing and the other sort of demand -- the other question market as we look out at the demand looking forward is the possibility of using more butane as a solvent in in situ development of bitumen production, the oil sands.
 So those are some of the factors that we look at. I think our outlook is likely that butane will be somewhat softer than what it's been when you look at it relative to crude oil, but not significantly so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Paget,  FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David. My second question is, could there be a move to create a new delivery system, a new pipeline to get propane out of the province since Cogent may be taken out of service? Or will rail grow in importance here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's our view that rail will grow in importance. One of the reason why the Cogent pipeline is being reversed is, quite honestly, because the owner and operator of that pipeline wasn't seeing sufficient propane volume on that pipeline to make it worthwhile to continue to keep it in that service. And so I think given that, I don't think you'll see a propane pipeline built for export purposes. The advantage of rail is that it's far more flexible in terms of meeting the seasonal demand patterns and meeting the varying geographic demand patterns. And so that's what we would anticipate you'll see to address that issue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Paget,  FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David. Does Keyera have enough rail cars to meet the demand for Keyera's propane or any sort of rail service that you might have? Or are you looking to add more to the fleet?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven, that's a very good question. I think access to rail cars is going to be a constraint for those parties that want to move more hydrocarbons by rail, whether it's propane, or butane, or condensate, or crude oil, or [dill bed]. And certainly, the manufacturers of rail cars right now are seeing a little bit of a banner time.
 We have the advantage of having an existing fleet of railcars. So we can add to that fleet. We can renew leases in a manner that allows us to kind of manage that growth in demand for railcar capacity I think more effectively than somebody who is starting from scratch. And what we try to do with our fleet is maintain as much flexibility as we can so that we can use it for propane, or butane, or condensate, and of course maintain the flexibility in our rail terminal capacity as well to be able to load and offload those cars as demand patterns evolve.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Paget,  FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the demand for your rail services and ability to provide them right now are roughly in balance then?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Smith,  Keyera Corporation - President &amp; COO, interim CFO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right now, yes, and we're adding a fair number of cars to the fleet over the course of the next 12 to 18 months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Paget,  FirstEnergy Capital - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David. Those were my questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There are no further questions at this time.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Cobb,  Keyera Corporation - VP, Investor Relations   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Kyle. Well, this completes our third quarter results conference call. If you have any further questions, please contact us. Our contact information is in yesterday's release. So thank you for listening and have a good day.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This does conclude today's conference call. You may now disconnect.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q3 2012 Keyera Corp Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>CALGARY</city>
  <companyName>Keyera Corp</companyName>
  <companyTicker>KEY.TO</companyTicker>
  <startDate>7-Nov-12 3:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>142580</companyId>
  <CUSIP>493271100</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>B3SGMV5</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>CA4932711001</ISIN>
</Event>