<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="11542792" lastUpdate="Monday, July 23, 2018 at 11:17:53am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="11542792.F" expirationDate="Friday, July 20, 2018 at 12:45:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of KSU earnings conference call or presentation 20-Jul-18 12:45pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2018 Kansas City Southern Earnings Call

KANSAS CITY Jul 23, 2018 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Kansas City Southern earnings conference call or presentation Friday, July 20, 2018 at 12:45:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Brian D. Hancock
      Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO
   *  Jeffrey M. Songer
      Kansas City Southern - COO &amp; Executive VP
   *  José Guillermo Zozaya Delano
      Kansas City Southern - President, GM &amp; Executive Representative of Kansas City Southern de México Sa de C.v.
   *  Michael W. Upchurch
      Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP
   *  Patrick J. Ottensmeyer
      Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Allison M. Landry
      Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Director
   *  Brian Patrick Ossenbeck
      JP Morgan Chase &amp; Co, Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst
   *  Christian F. Wetherbee
      Citigroup Inc, Research Division - VP
   *  Jason H. Seidl
      Cowen and Company, LLC, Research Division - MD and Senior Research Analyst
   *  Justin Trennon Long
      Stephens Inc., Research Division - MD
   *  Kenneth Scott Hoexter
      BofA Merrill Lynch, Research Division - MD and Co-Head of the Industrials
   *  Matthew Edward Reustle
      Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst
   *  Ravi Shanker
      Morgan Stanley, Research Division - Executive Director
   *  Scott H. Group
      Wolfe Research, LLC - MD &amp; Senior Transportation Analyst
   *  Thomas Richard Wadewitz
      UBS Investment Bank, Research Division - MD and Senior Analyst 

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Greetings, and welcome to the Kansas City Southern Second Quarter 2018 Earnings Call. (Operator Instructions) As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.
 This presentation includes statements concerning potential future events involving the company, which could materially differ from events that actually occur. The differences could be caused by a number of factors, including those factors identified in the Risk Factors section of the company's Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2017, filed with the SEC. The company is not obligated to update any forward-looking statements in this presentation to reflect future events or developments. All reconciliations to GAAP can be found on the KCS website, www.kcsouthern.com.
 It is now my pleasure to introduce your host, Pat Ottensmeyer, President and Chief Executive Officer for Kansas City Southern. Mr. Ottensmeyer, you may begin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you very much, and good morning, everyone. And welcome to the KCS second quarter earning's call.
 I'll start my comments with just a brief introduction on Slide 4, but you all know the cast and the lineup for our calls, no changes, so I won't spend any time introducing us.
 Slide 5, just a couple of quick comments about the results. We had record quarterly revenues for the second quarter of 2018, revenue was up by 4% from the previous year.
 Volume is up only 1%, which was a bit of a disappointment, and I'll talk about that in a couple of minutes. Operating ratio is 64.0%, which was 50 basis points higher than last year. Mike Upchurch will review this in greater detail in a few minutes, but volume weakness, higher casualty and fuel expense and PTC related costs, including depreciation, were some of the major contributors to the higher operating ratio.
 We also produced record quarterly earnings per share. There was some tax items included in that number, but -- that Mike will review in a few minutes as well, but I'd still say, solid earnings per share growth for the quarter.
 Before I turn the discussion over to the team, I'd like to make 1 additional comment on our volume growth and full year outlook. Given our actual volume growth for the quarter and year-to-date, through 6 months, we are revising our guidance, which had previously been mid-single-digit, down a bit.
 While it's certainly no means out of the question that we could still achieve mid-single-digit volume growth for the full year, at this point, there is [certainly] greater risk and higher probability that we'll come in below that guidance. So our current expectation is a full year volume growth will be in the range of 3% to 4%, which is kind of right at the edge of high or low to mid-single-digit growth.
 I think for the past few weeks, Mike Upchurch and the Investor Relations team have been guiding to the lower end of our previous guidance range. So hopefully, this doesn't come as a surprise to most of you on the call.
 As Brian Hancock will show you in a few minutes, there is a lot of strength in many of our most important long-term growth areas, and one of the major areas of disappointment was crude oil, which was largely a timing issue. And again, Brian will talk more about that in a few minutes.
 So with that introduction, I will turn the presentation over to Jeff Songer.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeffrey M. Songer,  Kansas City Southern - COO &amp; Executive VP   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Pat, and good morning.
 Starting with a review of operating metrics for the quarter on Slide 7. Velocity of 27.5 miles per hour improved versus prior year, while dwelling increased, driven primarily by our Northern Mexico terminals. Congestion faced in Q1 and early Q2 has eased in the Houston area, and we have been working hard to clear the cross-border traffic that backed up to Northern Mexico during that time. This congestion is largely behind us, and dwell should continue to moderate through the rest of Q3.
 Other highlights for the quarter include the announcement that we will purchase 50 new high-horsepower locomotives with delivery starting in Q1 2019. This provides a great opportunity for us to modernize our fleet with more efficient, more reliable and lower-cost-to-maintain units, and positions us to handle more line of road trains, specifically in the refined products area.
 Offsetting this purchase is the disposition of approximately 30 older switching and low-horsepower units. Additionally, we look to reduce the leased units that we have had online over the past several months. Overall, our active fleet will remain largely unchanged with the acquisition of these new units.
 PTC work continues on schedule, and we project to be fully equipped on our network by the 2018 deadline. Approximately 60% of our subdivisions are in PTC revenue service, that's up from 40% as reported at the end of Q1. We continued to experience only minor impacts to our operations as we moved territories in PTC.
 Turning to Slide 8. Our cross-border volume outlook is strong, as Brian will outline in more detail. We continue to work on operational improvements at the border to ensure we have capacity to achieve planned growth. In addition to the joint U.S.-Mexico customs facility, which began operation last summer, we have now started our international crude operation. This operation will improve fluidity, safety and security at the border, and will provide public benefit by reducing the amount of blocked crossings in Laredo.
 Future technology enhancements such as (inaudible) [speed] scanning of trains and data processing improvements are other opportunities to improve fluidity at the bridge.
 Turning to Slide 9. This map shows 2017 foreign direct investment in Mexico. Despite ongoing trade negotiations, foreign direct investment in Mexico is growing. Prior capacity investments we have discussed such as Sanchez, San Luis Potosi and on joint KCS-UP trackage rights in Texas as well as future projects such as upgrades to the main line between Monterrey and Matamoros, and at the ports of Veracruz and Tampico, all aligned with foreign investments into Mexico and related cross-border opportunities.
 As indicated on the map, the highest concentration of foreign investment is in the northern and central regions that we serve. Brian will go into additional details around specific customer projects in these areas, specifically related to the refined products, plastics and automotive industries.
 I will now turn the presentation over to Brian.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Jeff, and good morning. I'll start my comments on page 11, where you can see second quarter year-over-year revenue was up 4% and volumes were up 1% despite headwinds from the closer and large utility customer facility in Texas.
 Both volume and revenue increased for 5 of our 6 business units. Additionally, in the second quarter, we achieved record franchise cross-border carloads and revenue benefiting from the growth in key areas such as refined products, plastics, automotive and cross-border intermodal.
 During the quarter, our revenue per unit grew 3% despite mixed pressure from the loss of a long-haul utility coal business and unfavorable FX impact. Positive core pricing was in line with the first quarter pricing of about 3%, and our outlook on pricing remains very positive, as 2Q renewals were up in the mid-single-digit range.
 The Chemical &amp; Petroleum business unit revenue growth of 14% was primarily driven by plastics and petroleum. Plastics revenue was -- revenue growth of 24% was driven by favorable domestic and cross-border volumes and very strong demand in Mexico. Petroleum revenue grew 14%, driven by strength in southbound unit train and manifest refined products related to Mexico Energy Reform.
 In Q2, Mexican Energy Reform carloads and revenue grew 84% and 57% respectively, and we included an update on this important and growing business segment in the appendix of our earnings slide.
 Our strong performance in refined products was partially offset by lower heavy fuel oil volumes at the Tula facility in Mexico, and the refinery continues to experience production challenges. Revenue from our Industrial &amp; Consumer business unit grew 3% in Q2.
 This business unit benefited from strong paper and appliance revenues due to the tightening truck capacity and increased brown paper demand, partially offset by lower metals' revenue, as length of haul was negatively impacted by a shift in customer sourcing trends.
 Agriculture &amp; Minerals revenue was up 1% year-over-year. Growth in grain and ores and minerals was partially offset by food products due to a plant expansion project at one of our customer's facilities that required a temporary shutdown.
 We're encouraged that the congestion that impacted this segment during the first quarter has improved, as evidenced by better performance at the end of the second and early third quarters.
 Similar to last quarter, Energy's revenue decline of 20% was driven by a previously announced closure of a power generation facility in Texas and by frac sand sourcing changes.
 These declines were partially offset by higher volume and pricing in our crude oil business, driven by increased production in Canada, with decreased pipeline capacity.
 Intermodal revenue increased 3%, with mixed performance by lane. Both U.S. domestic and cross-border business posted solid performance, as we continue to benefit from truck conversion. This growth was partially offset by a 15% year-over-year decline in Lázaro intermodal.
 As we continue experiencing pricing pressures driven by a weaker Mexican peso, we are actively pursuing strategies to regain this market share without suffering the long-term negative effects of an unsustainable pricing concessions.
 Revenue from our Automotive business was up 17% over prior year, with improvements in both volume and revenue per unit. Increases were driven by carryover inventories, increased plant production and growth in vehicles imported into Mexico through the port of Lázaro Cárdenas.
 We continue working with our customers to address inventory congestion by providing unique service solutions that address some of the temporary congestion and equipment issues being seen throughout the rail industry.
 On Slide 12, we provide an outlook for the second half of 2018 for each of the business segments. As Pat mentioned, our full year volume outlook may be below mid-single digits. We still expect a sequential volume increase in the second half of 2018, as growth from key businesses accelerate and we benefit from easier comps due to hurricane impacts during the second half of 2017.
 Starting with Chemical &amp; Petroleum. Mexico Energy Reform continues to be a significant focus in 2018. Volume growth from refined products accelerates in the second half of 2018 as additional storage capacity comes online. Additionally, we expect plastics to grow in the second half of 2018 as new petrochemical capacity begins production.
 We also expect to see continuing solid growth in the intermodal cross-border in U.S. domestic lanes, as we benefit from conversion of a freight currently moving by truck.
 Lázaro Cárdenas will be of particular focus during the second half of 2018, as we evaluate our strategy to gain back that market share in a market that is ground zero for transportation and impacts of changes in market flow and capacity into Mexico City. These shipments also have an impact on our volume growth assumptions for the second half of 2018. We'll continue to see solid performance in our Automotive business, with growth turning ahead of most third-party estimates for Mexican production.
 In addition to increasing production in Mexico, our growth will benefit from market share gains with some of our biggest customers. New equipment coming online during the third quarter will be a welcome support for this business during the second half of 2018.
 Our Industrial &amp; Consumer business unit will continue to benefit from strong demand and tight truck capacity, particularly in the paper and appliance businesses. We are closely monitoring the ongoing trade developments for any potential impacts on our metals business as well as other segments. We expect our ag and min volumes to be slightly up from second half of 2018, with steady demand in both grain and food products.
 As previously noted, we expect our Energy business to be down year-over-year and during the second half of 2018, as it will be impacted by the closing of a coal-fired power generation facility in Texas. However, we do expect continued growth in Canadian crude, as customer volumes on the new contract started ramping up towards the end of Q2 and have continued into Q3.
 Over the last few months, the question has been raised on whether we would continue to invest in Mexico at the pace we have over the last few years. As Jeff mentioned, we are continuing to work on both capacity and fluidity as well as origin and destination opportunities on our line.
 On Page 13, we wanted to provide just a short list of projects that have been publicly announced that KCS will be servicing.
 As you can see, we have over 20 customer projects as well as major opportunities at the ports of Veracruz, Altamira and Lázaro Cárdenas.
 As referenced on this Slide, you can see that our cross-border business was up 19% in Q2, demonstrating that each line of business continues to grow as trade increases between Mexico and the U.S.
 KCS continues to be confident in the economic decisions that are being made by our customers as well as those we're making ourselves.
 As we have already mentioned, foreign direct investment in Mexico remains strong, and KCS will continue to appropriately invest to support the objectives and the growth plans of our customers.
 Now I'll turn the call over to our CFO, Mike Upchurch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thanks, Brian, and good morning.
 I'll start my comments on Slide 15. Carload volumes increased 1%, while revenues increased 4%, predominantly from rising fuel prices. Carloads and revenues were negatively impacted, mainly due to a decline in our coal business resulting from the closure of a utility plant in Texas. Excluding the decline in coal, volumes increased 3% and revenues 7%. And we did see strong sequential revenue growth at 7%, with strong incremental margins of 60 plus percent. Operating ratio increased from 63.5% in 2Q 2017 to 64.0% in 2Q 2018.
 We experienced cost headwinds from higher year-over-year PTC expenses of approximately $5 million and $6 million in higher casualty costs, in total, contributing about a 150 basis points of impact to OR. We also saw higher fuel prices that increased 33% in the U.S. and 16% in Mexico. Our adjusted effective tax rate for the quarter was 27.6%, lower than our guidance of 30%.
 During the quarter, we saw benefits from the lower GILTI tax and the State of Missouri lowering their corporate tax rate from 6.25% to 4%. Our reported effective tax rate was 24.2%, lower than our adjusted effective tax rate, primarily due to new guidance issued by the IRS in April that lowered our repatriation tax by approximately $4 million. We continue to believe our full year adjusted effective tax rate will be approximately 30%.
 Finally, we continue to be encouraged by our discussions with various congressional offices and the Treasury Department regarding some release of the unintended consequences of the GILTI tax.
 We believe there may be additional interpretive guidance issued by the Treasury Department sometime this fall that may help us mitigate at least part of our current GILTI tax provision estimate of $17.5 million for 2018.
 Reported second quarter diluted earnings per share increased 14% to a $1.45 per share, while adjusted diluted EPS increased 16% to $1.54.
 Average outstanding shares for the quarter were 102.5 million, a reduction of more than 3 million shares from a year ago.
 More details on reported and adjusted diluted EPS can be found on page 24 in the appendix, and a more detailed P&amp;L is available on page 23 in the appendix.
 Turning to Slide 16. Second quarter operating expenses increased 5% or $20 million over second quarter 2017.
 As I mentioned earlier, expenses increased primarily due to fuel prices; depreciation, which was predominantly from PTC; and $6 million in casualties, in the materials and other expense line item, which did include a negative year-over-year comparison due to a $2 million casualty credit we booked in 2Q 2017. Offsetting those increases were foreign exchange benefits of $5 million and fuel consumption and efficiency savings of $3 million.
 Turning to Slide 17. Second quarter compensation expense declined 2% or $3 million. Drivers of lower compensation and benefits expense includes $4 million in lower incentive compensation than 2Q 2017, lower-than-expected benefit cost and foreign exchange benefits. Offsetting those declines were a $2 million increase from higher headcount and wage inflation of $3 million.
 Turning to Slide 18. Second quarter fuel expense increased 17% as a result of a 33% increase in fuel price in the U.S. and a 16% increase in the price of fuel in Mexico. Offsetting those price increases, we experienced 4% lower GTMs reducing our consumption, realized a foreign currency benefit of $2 million and an additional $1 million in improved fuel efficiency.
 Turning to Slide 19. Let me briefly discuss our capital allocation priorities. As Jeff and Brian discussed earlier, our first priority continues to be investing in our various growth opportunities. Our 2018 CapEx guidance remains unchanged at $530 million to $550 million. We expect 2018 to be our third year in a row of declining CapEx spend and declining CapEx-to-revenue ratio.
 We also continue to explore investment opportunities and ventures that might drive more revenue growth on our railroad, such as refined product receiving terminals in Mexico. During the quarter, we repurchased 503,000 shares of our common stock and on an accumulative basis, have now incurred $364 million to repurchase 3.4 million shares under the $800 million board-authorized program we announced in August of 2017.
 During the quarter, we purchased approximately a $100 million of equipment on lease, and now own approximately 77% of our equipment, up from 20% in 2011. Overall, our strategy of owning more of our equipment has achieved an approximately 250 basis point improvement in OR.
 And finally, we were very pleased to have Moody's upgrade our credit rating to Baa2. And we look forward to the day S&amp;P also recognizes just how much our credit has improved in the more than 5 years since their last upgrade.
 And with that, I'll turn it back to Pat.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Just a couple of comments here before we open up for Q&amp;A. One of -- obviously, one of the significant new developments since our last quarterly call would be the elections in Mexico on July 1.
 I think everyone knows how that turned out, and as expected, Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, known as AMLO, was the winner of the presidential election in a very wide margin.
 His MORENA party coalition won 61% of the seats in the house of deputies and 54% of the seats in the Senate, which is obviously a majority but falls short of the 2/3 majority that would be required for any constitutional amendments.
 Based on his postelection comments and messaging that has come from himself and his key staff and cabinet leaders, we're really pleased with that commentary and don't expect that he will pursue any constitutional amendments that are adverse to our interest or adverse to the economy and the strength of the economy in Mexico. Obviously, financial markets have been relatively calm and positive about this result. Peso has appreciated by 5%, and as you've seen in some of the data that we presented here, in the second quarter, both foreign direct investment in Mexico was up significantly and our cross-border business revenues and volumes also increased significantly.
 So it's very early on. I will say we like what we see in terms of the messaging, the dialogue with the U.S. government leaders, meeting with Secretary Pompeo and Secretary Mnuchin and others that took place a few weeks ago, seem to be very positive, off to a good start. But it's early, and obviously, we will keep our fingers on the pulse and stay very close to the transition team, as we move forward to the December transition of the government and see how things develop from that point on.
 In the past, I've offered suggestions for the headlines for our quarterly performance and outlook, which I'm certain all of you find extremely helpful, particularly those who are writing research updates over the weekend.
 When I look at our performance and commentary and the way we feel about the outlook, some of the potential headlines that come to my mind are solid volume and revenue growth in most strategic growth areas; very pleased with the performance in Automotive, plastics, refined products; the growth in our cross-border business was just outstanding.
 As I mentioned at the very beginning, we're certainly disappointed with the 1% volume growth, but I feel like the weakness is isolated to Energy, some of which is crude oil timing and the international intermodal, which Brian talked about in his comments and we'll probably have questions on that later on.
 Second half outlook points to improved sequential growth in both volume and revenue, and I'd finish by saying the long-term outlook shows multiple oversized growth opportunities in several of our strategic growth areas.
 I feel very good about the future, long-term and short-term. So all things considered, we can never feel too disappointed about any quarter which shows record revenues and earnings per share.
 I feel good about the -- while it's very early on in the new Mexican administration, we're optimistic about the initial commentary that it is coming from the new leadership team and the outlook for improved U.S.-Mexico relations and possibly a resolution of NAFTA in the near term.
 So with that, I will conclude and open up the line for questions.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  (Operator Instructions) And our first question is coming from the line of Ken Hoexter with Merrill Lynch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kenneth Scott Hoexter,  BofA Merrill Lynch, Research Division - MD and Co-Head of the Industrials   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Pat, thanks for the thoughts there at the end. Maybe just expanding on that a little bit, can you talk a bit about the production challenges in Energy, maybe some of the timeline to get there? And then secondly, on pricing. Mike, you talked a bit about pricing. Maybe talk about what -- when we should expect to see that accelerating, given some of the market tightness right now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Ken, what you mean by production challenges in Energy?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kenneth Scott Hoexter,  BofA Merrill Lynch, Research Division - MD and Co-Head of the Industrials   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I thought that's what was set up earlier in terms of getting the production in Mexico, the facilities. I thought you said there was some production challenges.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Ken, this is Brian, I'll take that. It's primarily storage capacity in Mexico around refined products. As we told you before, there are at least 4 or 5 major storage facilities being constructed on our line right now. The majority of those will be at least 1 or 2 tanks completed in the fourth quarter or early first quarter 2019. Right now, we're moving a lot of the unit trains, and then they're being offloaded directly into truck. And so that will help us significantly when we have that storage capacity and space. When it comes to pricing, what I would tell you is we feel very comfortable with where we're at, both on our renewals as well as our same-store pricing. We feel very comfortable that we're going to be in that mid-single-digit range moving forward and continuing to accelerate into the back half of the year, around most of our major, let's say, opportunities in the refined products area. There's just so many things that are happening, but we're very, very comfortable that we're going to hit that mid-single digit range on our renewals. So hopefully, that gives you what you need.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kenneth Scott Hoexter,  BofA Merrill Lynch, Research Division - MD and Co-Head of the Industrials   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. And then Mike, thoughts on pricing, on the timing for, maybe given the tightness in the market, when we could see the acceleration you were referring to?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Well, I think it was Brian who made those comments, but I think you're going to see a pickup in third quarter, based on the renewals in the second quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Your next question comes from the line of Jason Seidl with Cowen and Company.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jason H. Seidl,  Cowen and Company, LLC, Research Division - MD and Senior Research Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Staying on pricing a bit, (inaudible) fairly decent disparity between your core pricing in the quarter at 3%, renewals at 5%, and that obviously bodes well going forward. Where is the strength coming from? And why do you think the market is jumping like this? Is it all about tightness in the trucking space? Or are there other things at work here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Jason, this is Brian. I would say we're seeing it fairly broadly. We feel very comfortable in our Automotive business, in our Chemical &amp; Petroleum business, Industrial &amp; Consumer. So we see it fairly broadly, certainly, intermodal domestically and cross-border, as truck conversion continues to happen. It's a great pricing environment for the intermodal carriers. And so I feel that it's pretty wide swap, if you will, around pricing. We feel very comfortable. It's a great environment for us, and our customers are actively looking for options on rail. And so we feel pretty good in that space right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Jason, this is Mike. I might just add one thing, the soft spot in pricing for us has been for a while intermodal in Mexico, particularly at the port at Lázaro, where we're billing in U.S. dollars, truckers are billing in pesos. So our service has effectively become 50% more expensive over the last 5 years, given what's happened with the currency. But we are looking at some rebate opportunities tied to volume increases that would help fill out some trains that aren't at maximum length. So we want to look at those opportunities. Anywhere from 25% to 35% capacity left on those trains, if we can fill that out, I think we might be successful in driving a bit more volume out of Lázaro.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jason H. Seidl,  Cowen and Company, LLC, Research Division - MD and Senior Research Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  And then that should help the incremental margins [to analyze] how much capacity left.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Correct.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jason H. Seidl,  Cowen and Company, LLC, Research Division - MD and Senior Research Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Let me stick with some cross-border commentary here, because you mentioned that. You mentioned it was like the strongest growth that you've seen, I think, ever cross-border. What are the reasons behind that? Are people trying to ship ahead of any maybe issues with tariffs or at NAFTA? Or are people really just starting some of the peak season a little bit early?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  No. I would tell you, Jason, I think that the -- there's a couple of things that are driving it. Certainly, there is more intermodal business. Our new service with the BNSF has continued to increase. Our service with the UP continues to grow. We're also seeing some sourcing changes in steel, where a product may have been coming from China or other places, it's now coming in, in through the U.S. and then down into Mexico into the steel plants. And so there's some sourcing changes in the steel area that are having a pretty significant impact on cross-border. It impacts our line of -- the length of haul, but overall, we're very positive on the way that our cross-border business and the fluidity the Japanese team are creating at the border. We're going to continue to utilize that and try to fill each one of those trains out, as that business continues to grow.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I would just add to that. I don't think you mentioned refined products. That opportunity is -- in spite of some of the challenges in storage and facility and capacity that Brian mentioned earlier, that business is growing very, very rapidly. So we ask ourselves the same question, Jason, is some of this sort of a little bit of a blip because of concern about what's going to happen with tariffs or trade. We just don't see it. I'll jump on that one, because I'm sure there will be questions later on about the impact of tariffs. And so far, we just haven't seen any impact -- any negative impact in our business even into the third quarter because of the tariffs that have been announced or threatened or both of those. And I'll make one more comment about Lázaro. And I think that is an important consideration as you all think about the volume weakness that we've seen in the first half. Business is there, and as I said in my comments, there's a lot of strength in our business across the board. It feels to me like our business is stronger than our results reflect. And we've talked a lot about the timing of crude oil, but I think the international Lázaro intermodal business is another area of weakness. And we've been very thoughtful about how we deal with that. So the business is there. If we were more aggressive in discounting to retain or gain share back, I think our volume numbers would have been better. We're trying to be very thoughtful about how we deal with that, as Mike mentioned with rebates, volume incentives, other things rather than just cutting prices, and we'll continue to try to address that. But I think it's important to say that the core business is there, we have just chosen not to do what's -- what some of our customers might want us to do in terms of pricing reaction to maintain that volume.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Our next question comes from the line of Allison Landry with Crédit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Allison M. Landry,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Director   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So just following up on some of your comments regarding Lázaro, Pat. How do we -- in terms of the second half of the year, how much of a drag do you think that Lázaro could be in terms of total Intermodal volumes or even your overall volumes? Just as we think about the worsening decline in the second quarter, and it looked like the comps in the back half of the year are pretty difficult. So just trying to understand if this is an incremental risk to the second half outlook?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I'll ask Brian to get into more detail. I don't think there's incremental risk. I really think there is some upsides, some opportunity to gain business back and share back, but again, we're going to be very thoughtful. At the end of the day, I hope you appreciate this. We're going to be disciplined about how we price that business to maintain an acceptable level of profitability and returns and -- but I think there is more upside and opportunity in the second half in international intermodal than there is risk at this point.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Allison, this is Brian. I would say, the only thing I would add to what Pat said is whenever you end up in a situation where someone has made a pricing decision that impacts a large market like that, what happens is you get flow imbalance. MTs end up in places they shouldn't be, there's not enough capacity to handle other pieces. And so there's always a transition, there's always a recalibrating of where that freight comes in, and we're right in the middle of that. So we're actually trying to take advantage of some of the actions that had been taken in the past and be able to be a thoughtful provider that provides a secure way into Mexico City without taking an unsustainable pricing action that we just don't think it's something that can last longer than a 3- or 4-month timeframe. And so we feel very comfortable with our plan that Mike kind of laid out, using the rebates, allowing people to use us. So I don't think there's additional risk, and we're certainly looking to try to make those opportunities more prevalent here in the second half. But it's certainly something that we're managing on a daily basis, and our team is very engaged in understanding what's going on in all the ports on the western side of Mexico.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Allison M. Landry,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Director   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. So just to clarify, it sounds like you're taking these actions as we speak and hopefully, we'll see some of the volumes come back a little bit. Is that fair?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Absolutely. Most of the actions have already been taken, Allison. So we're in the middle of it right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  And remember, there is typically a build at Lázaro because of peak season. So we're going to get some benefit from that in third, fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Our next question is from the line of Ravi Shanker with Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley, Research Division - Executive Director   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  If I can just follow up on the pricing commentary, I think it's pretty interesting that you're getting mid-single-digit pricing on renewals. But I think, you also said that some customers may not be willing to give you business at the price you want. So how do you find a balance there between price that you're willing to take and the volumes? The mid-single digit is kind of above what we're hearing from any other rail on renewals. So it doesn't make sense to maybe ease off the gas there? Maybe you're trying to get some more volumes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, Ravi, this is Brian. I'll take that one, and then I'm sure Pat and Mike will have some input there. I would tell you that I think, from a pricing environment, we have so many new opportunities that are happening. Pat mentioned refined products, the changes that are happening in both paper, the paper markets, the way that box companies are used, and they allow us for some additional opportunities. Intermodal, obviously, is an area right now where the entire market is seeing pricing capability. We believe that we're being very thoughtful. We have responsibility, obviously, within Mexico to play within some regulations that allow us to be in the space where we create the maximum amount of value for the freight that we're moving, and so we're looking at continued opportunities in both our automotive space, long-term contracts that we put in place, industrial consumer and the chemical and petroleum business. We're also looking at some additional businesses off of some of the ports that give us new opportunities with existing customers. And so when you think about that, we're being very thoughtful, we're in a space of making sure that we have not only market share gains that Jeff and his team are creating the capacity and fluidity necessary. But like Pat said, the business is there, we just need to make sure that we're being thoughtful in the way that we go out, especially in that international, intermodal business. It does not make sense, I said this before, it does not make sense to rush to the bottom of the barrel from a pricing perspective because of the weakness in the peso and the weakness in some of the other things in some of the other port areas. So we feel like we have a great strategy, we're going to continue to monitor it every day with our customers and we get a lot of feedback from them. So I think, we're in a very balanced position right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley, Research Division - Executive Director   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Got it. I just -- go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Ravi, just -- I was going to add 1 point. Pat, I think, did a pretty good job in summarizing the disappointment around a few of our components of the business. Coal, I think that story is well known, we talked about that almost a year ago. Lázaro and then the crude and the crude was just a timing issue for us. So I think when you look at the rest of our business, we see a lot of strength in pricing and we use a lot of discipline with our network organization, our marketing organization and finance, all collaborating to make sure that we're getting the kind of yield and incremental margins that we're targeting.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ravi Shanker,  Morgan Stanley, Research Division - Executive Director   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Got it. Also, it's kind of hard to predict what a politician would do when they take office. But when the new government takes over, end of this year. Based on your understanding, do you think economic priorities and things like maybe addressing competition and the concession are like top of mind for them? Or do you think there are other social priorities that will come first? I'm just trying to take -- get a sense of how quickly after they take over will we know kind of what the impact is for you guys?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  José Zozaya is on the phone. So I might tee this up and then ask José to comment as well. I think, if you look at the main messaging of AMLO and MORENA, it was about corruption, security, other things that are very high importance to Mexicans and dealing with economic improvement in the economy by reducing or eradicating the cost and consequences of corruption. So far, based on what has been said and the messaging both public and private in meetings that we've had, it doesn't appear that there's certainly no anti-American, anti-NAFTA, they seem to very much appreciate the economic growth and the investment -- foreign investment that has clearly benefited Mexico. So I guess the answer to your question is we don't expect that to be top of mind in terms of major changes and the strategy or approach that the new administration is going to take once the transition occurs. José, any additional commentary there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 José Guillermo Zozaya Delano,  Kansas City Southern - President, GM &amp; Executive Representative of Kansas City Southern de México Sa de C.v.   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Pat. Just to comment, I think the meetings we have -- directly have with the new elected President's team. They have given us assurances that they will respect the concession terms as Patrick Ottensmeyer, you already mentioned to promote more foreign investment into the country and they -- as (inaudible) said, we are pro-NAFTA and pro-free trade.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question comes from the line of Matt Reustle with Goldman Sachs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Edward Reustle,  Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I'm curious when you factor in the challenges of the first half with some of the momentum you have going into the back half, is the full year OR improvement still achievable? And particularly, when you look out to '19, do you expect that, given what you're saying about the quality of the carload, the pricing and the talents you're going to have there, is that where we could see a material change in improvements in OR?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Matt, this is Mike. I'll take that one. Obviously, we're not where we want to be through the first half of the year with respect to our OR, we're slightly worse than we were a year ago but our goal continues to be a full year improvement in the operating ratio. We've got some momentum in the business, as we've been discussing here for the last 20, 30 minutes. And I think that volume will allow us to continue to improve our operating ratio. Believe me, nobody here is taking their eye off the ball in terms of improving OR and we have certainly incentives tied to that as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Edward Reustle,  Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Great. That's helpful. And then to follow up to your earlier point, that you're not seeing any accelerated demand as a result of the trade overhang. Do you think there is any pockets of pent-up demands? Just trying to get a sense of whether the business would be operating any differently if all the headline overhangs right there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  You know, that's a tough question. We ask ourselves that all the time and the way we've, kind of, feel about it is. We really haven't seen any tangible evidence that companies are pulling back or withdrawing, there's a lot of press earlier this year, I guess it was last year about Ford. I think that was kind of misunderstood, Ford did cancel a plant in Mexico but they built it in China. And they're just on a lot of examples that we've seen where customers have taken a turn, a hard turn, a reverse course. We don't know what we don't know and when I say that, I mean we don't know that there are companies that have discussed projects or right on the cusp or on the verge of making investments in Mexico that haven't moved forward because of those concerns. Our sense is that there is some of that but it's very hard to quantify.
 And then you just look at our business, look at our cross-border volume growth, if you look at -- I can tell you there is in spite of all the rhetoric and the concern about the election and NAFTA and all of those things in the refined products and the Energy segment, people are going actually full steam ahead. If we had capacity and facilities and terminals that could handle more business, we would be growing faster than we are in that segment. So they are not hesitating at all to move into those markets and pursue those opportunities. And then you just look at the foreign direct investment staff that Brian and Jeff talked about. So it certainly doesn't feel like this overhang is causing any serious delays or consequence to the growth in Mexico.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question comes from the line of Chris Wetherbee with City.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Christian F. Wetherbee,  Citigroup Inc, Research Division - VP   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I want to ask a little bit about the volume sort of outlook. So 3% to 4%, Pat, I think is the new number, you did 1% in the first half. You sort of looking for, I guess mid, single maybe even a little bit better than that in the back half. So I know we have the comps, I know we have some of the ramp-up in some refined products but maybe if you can unpack that a little bit maybe by quarter? Do you expect to see that sort of come back here in 3Q? Or do we have to wait more to 4Q and get some of that storage to open up in Mexico before we see those types of growth rates realized?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Chris, this is Mike. Maybe I'll give that one a shot. Obviously, we're at 1% volume growth through the first half of the year. The comps get much easier for us in the third quarter given the hurricane that we dealt with last year. But when you begin to put the building blocks together, we think there is an opportunity to see a couple of percentage point increase as a result of the comps related to the hurricane. We think there is a point around refined product. We think there is a point around crude, and then I think the area that is of highest risk for us right now would be Intermodal, given all the issues that we've discussed and getting some return back to volumes to the port at Lázaro and that could be Lázaro plus other Intermodal about 2 points. And that's how we get to our low end of the mid-single digits and we'll see whether we're right or not, but hopefully those give you the building blocks and that means the rest of the business continues to stay healthy and grows at about the same rate that it did in the first half.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  And I'll add 1 big caveat to that commentary and that is we're not forecasting a hurricane this year. And obviously, that's a wildcard. So some of the comps and some of the commentary about the second half of the year is clearly driven by the fact that we had a big hurricane impact last year, bigger than normal and we just -- we don't know what's going to happen this year. So that's a complete wildcard, but I'll just fall back on what I've said a couple of times here, it really feels to me and I think to us, the business is stronger than the results would indicate and don't want to make excuses but crude oil was timing. Intermodal is part of a thoughtful and intentional strategy, the business is there, we're trying to figure out a way to get back without, as Brian said going to the bottom of the barrel, so we'll continue to be disciplined about that but the business is there. We just got to find a way to get it back on our railroad in a way that makes sense.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I just want to add one thing. This is Brian. We are seeing some strength in a couple of areas in Lázaro that I do want to talk about. We are importing more vehicles into Lázaro than we had thought, some of our customers are up over 60% in what they're bringing into Mexico from other areas. These are for vehicle consumption in Mexico, and so Mexico as a trading partner is being very successful and Lázaro is a big part of that port strategy for them and we're seeing some success there. So we are picking up some additional volume in Lázaro that we didn't have before, we talked a little bit about the steel sourcing changes. But again, there's a lot going on down in the port of Lázaro. So we think that there is a very good strategy. We can keep going down the path we are, watching it daily, but making sure that we're competitive not only in Intermodal but in automotive, steel, carload and certainly their export volumes that they're sending out to Asia and to the western side of South America. So we feel very comfortable with the way we're operating down in Lázaro.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Christian F. Wetherbee,  Citigroup Inc, Research Division - VP   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. That's really helpful color guys, I appreciate all of that. And then Mike, I just want to make sure I understood your comments earlier in the call about incremental margin. I think you were giving out some numbers sort of ex-coal for the quarter and maybe there is a 60% incremental margin number that was associated with sort of the ex-coal business. I just want to understand if that's right? And then what do you think about sort of these potential tailwinds to volumes as you move into the back half of the year? It's sort of 50-ish the right number, I don't want to get too specific with the guidance, but how do you think about the incrementals and the environment where maybe you're growing closer to mid-singles?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, I think the incrementals in 2Q were more around 25%. Not to get into the game of excluding things, but we had a tough casualty quarter that probably would've gotten us a little bit closer to that 40% to 50% range. The sequential incremental margin was low 60%. That was my comment. And I think it's safe to say if we execute against the volume forecast that we have here, that's going to allow us to continue to target and generate roughly 50% incremental margins. That's been our long-standing goal and if we continue to see the volume that we're seeing here in July play out through the rest of the year, I think we'll be in pretty good shape.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question comes from the line of Justin Long with Stephens.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Trennon Long,  Stephens Inc., Research Division - MD   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So I wanted to follow up first on Lázaro, first, how much of the market share headwind would you say the function of truckload competition versus competition from other ports? And secondly, as we think about your ability to recapture some of this market share based on the changes you've talked about, do you have a target on where you would like to see market share go relative to where it is today?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Justin, what I would say is, up until I would say probably the April timeframe, the majority of the competition was a truck. It was peso based, they're obviously priced in pesos, we're priced in dollars from an international perspective. And so there was a significant deviation there between the 2, truck and rail. I would say in Manzanillo, there were a couple of things that were done from a pricing perspective, not only from a shipping line perspective out of Asia, but those rates were cut, I would say from a shipping line perspective to the point where there was really no reason for us to chase that volume. And so I think that the key is making sure that we understand how the shipping lines are going to use us, how the competition in truck is going to use the port of Lázaro. We feel very comfortable that the program we've put in place makes us more competitive than any other mode based on the volumes that they would be able to bring into that now. We understand that most of the decisions around those things are made in early parts of the year, February, January is when those bids happen, and so we're looking at capitalizing on congestion that may be caused by some of the other things that are happening at some of the other western ports. So it's a very complex issue, it certainly is multi-modal and multi-port, but we feel very comfortable if our customers and those that are looking for options into the Mexico city area take advantage of the programs that we've offered for this back half of this year. They will not only have a more secure transit into Mexico, a better service, but also be very, very cost competitive. So I think it's a good strategy. I think we're in the right space and we'll just see what happens.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Let me chime in here and address your question about market share specifically. We don't like to lose business. We have capacity on trains and on the Intermodal trains that we'd like to fill up and get some of that business back. But we don't really have a market share target, it's really -- we're going to be thoughtful and careful and make sure that we price this business and disciplined about returns in profitability, because it's a big driver of our volume weakness, I think it's a big opportunity for us going forward if we can kind of reach agreement with our customers. Certain amount of this is brinksmanship and negotiation. We think we have a better service, we have a more secure service and we have a lot of other business in Lázaro, Automotive and others, Petroleum that is competing for capacity. So again, I hope you guys give us some credit for being disciplined about this. We could've shown better volume numbers have we've been more aggressive in responding to the market and the pricing, but it just didn't make sense for us to do that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Trennon Long,  Stephens Inc., Research Division - MD   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Really helpful color. I think secondly, Mike I just wanted to touch on a few guidance items. I think last quarter, you talked about DNA coming in at around $360 million for the full year, the Mexican fuel excise tax credit being about $35 million. Any update to those 2 numbers? And also curious if you could comment on your expectations for incentive comp in the back half?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, no. We're still in that range, $360 million for the full year for depreciation. The tax credit -- excise tax credit, they're continually moving that up and down, it's hard to predict but I think that's probably still a pretty good estimate. I think, as we look out through the rest of the year, we feel pretty good about expenses, there are no big headwinds. I think you'll see a little bit of a step-up in comp given the volumes that we've been discussing here. That'll drive some incremental fuel from the volume perspective, but those would be kind of our key headwinds going throughout the year. And I think you had a second part of that question that I don't recall now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Trennon Long,  Stephens Inc., Research Division - MD   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Incentive comp in the back half, I know there was some abnormal trends last year with the hurricane so wanted to get your thoughts around that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, you saw on the slide on comp and benefits that we have a decline in incentive comp on a year-over-year basis. If the performance doesn't move up, I would expect we'll continue to see year-over-year declines, but we're not really prepared to give you any specific guidance on that. Too many open items, we try to accrue based on our forecast, actual results for the first 6 months and forecast for the back half. But I think it's safe to say, it'll be lower than it was in 2017.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question is from the line of Tom Wadewitz with UBS.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Richard Wadewitz,  UBS Investment Bank, Research Division - MD and Senior Analyst    [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I've got a couple on the volume side for you. I know there has been a lot of discussion on this new approach on Lázaro Intermodal. What -- something you've already put some of that in front of the customers, what's the response and what's the kind of conviction level? I think Mike, you said that, if I understood it right, we -- you are thinking of 2 points of added volume growth from the response out of Lázaro and just trying to get a sense of your conviction and visibility if that's taking place?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. That's Lázaro/Intermodal. So you remember, Lázaro is about 25% of our overall Intermodal business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Richard Wadewitz,  UBS Investment Bank, Research Division - MD and Senior Analyst    [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Specific within Lázaro, just seeing those volumes go instead of being down 15%, being up year-over-year, is that good visibility? Or how do you think about that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I think we're -- I think the customer feedback has been positive. I think what you have to remember though is again, those decisions have been made from a port and from a port of call perspective. And so it's really going to depend on what happens on the ground at the other ports, if there's congestion, if there has to be rerouting, if there has to be other decisions where capacity dries up. So I think, we're in a very interesting capacity constrained world right now, specifically in the Mexico City. And this stuff changes on a weekly and monthly basis. So what I would tell you is we're watching it closely. The customers are positive on the fact that we address the pricing issue against the peso, but I would tell you they're also very -- they won't understand the volume commitments, they won't understand and we as well, we're not in it for the short term, we're not in it to try to make 1 quarter or another. We're trying to have good long-term relationships with these carriers that make it a very secure, very cost-effective way for them to ship into Mexico City using rail. And I think that's what they're seeing in our strategy. So hopefully, we'll see benefits if we continue to see pricing that's I'll call it rational in certain modes. We're in the middle of a fight, there's no doubt about it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Richard Wadewitz,  UBS Investment Bank, Research Division - MD and Senior Analyst    [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So would you think it turns positive? Or just kind of less worse if you look at second half on Lázaro volume?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Certainly, less worse, the opportunity there, the business is there for us to turn positive. And I just want to -- I think, I've said this like 2 or 3x now, so we haven't changed our strategy. The market changed and we held our discipline. We think that's the right way to approach it. We think we've got a superior service. We've got superior security and the capacity is certainly there, but we are going to remain disciplined in our response to changing markets and make sure that we handle this in a way that generates an acceptable return and acceptable profitability.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  And Tom, when we look back over the last 5 years given the depreciation of the peso, we are far better off having stuck with price both from the revenue and margin standpoint. So that's why we feel pretty strongly about how we've handled the pricing strategy and the impacts in the market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Disciplined.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Our next question is from the line of Scott Group with Wolfe Research.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott H. Group,  Wolfe Research, LLC - MD &amp; Senior Transportation Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So wanted to just follow up one more again on these Lázaro rebate. So I think you said that because of the peso, there is sort of like a 50% effective change in your cost versus trucking cost. So in what percent sort of rebates are...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  [Over 5 years].
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott H. Group,  Wolfe Research, LLC - MD &amp; Senior Transportation Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  [Clearly], I understood, yes. What percent rebate are we talking about here? And I guess, you've said disciplined, obviously, a lot of times. How do you get comfort that rebates don't spread to the existing book of business? And maybe just with that, is this also showing up at all in cross border? Because I see cross-border intermodal revenue per car was down a bit in the second quarter as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I'll take couple of those. No, we don't see a spread into our book of business. It's tied to growth. And the cross-border revenue per unit, I think it's primarily driven by the very short length of haul that we have on the U.S. side connected to the BNSF service.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael W. Upchurch,  Kansas City Southern - CFO &amp; Executive VP   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Right. And the fact that we get paid on empty there, that have a lower rate than the full loads. But that's been good business for us, the volume growth we've seen from...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  And Scott, I would tell you from a percentage perspective, we don't obviously, give that kind of information out, but I would tell you is you have to take into account a couple of things, certainly, there is a vessel portion of a movement from Asia, there is a rail or inland portion. You have to look at the way that truck is handled inside of each of the ports, specifically around transload and transshipment, and then you have to look at capacity out of each one of the ports. I would tell you it's customer by customer, it's certainly dependent upon where the product is coming from and going to from a shipping line perspective but we're working very closely with our shipping customers in a very fluid environment. So certainly, something that's important but we're not obviously, going to give you any of those type of percentages.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott H. Group,  Wolfe Research, LLC - MD &amp; Senior Transportation Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And then, I just wanted to ask about the change over to the international cruise. I don't think you got any questions there. Is this in your mind a more of a volume or a cost opportunity? And maybe just with this change over to the international cruise, just refresh us what your capacity on cross-border trainings is going to go to? And what the current number of trains is today?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeffrey M. Songer,  Kansas City Southern - COO &amp; Executive VP   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Scott, this is Jeff. This initiative is all about fluidity and growth, it's not a cost-saving measures per se. We're actually hiring and adding a few cruise on the U.S. side to get these trains from -- these refined product trains mainly on cross-border growth from Oman, Corpus Christi down to the bridge. This simply shaves a few minutes off of every train that wants to cross the bridge. So it's a capacity play, Scott, it's a volume play. It's also a safety play. It's a public benefit play for reducing blocked crossings, trains that stop either going South, blocked crossings in Laredo. Trains that stop and have that crew change on the middle of the bridge coming north are subject to maybe more vandalism than trains that want to roll right through there. So currently, we're -- we've seen some good benefits this year already with the other initiatives. The customs improvements, we saw last year. We're pushing probably over the last couple of months, an average of 25, 26 trains across the bridge. Right now, we started international cruise, we're only running maybe 4 trains a day with international cruise. It will take us quite a while to qualify all trains with cruise for the international cruise to operate on, so it's a long-term initiative. It's going to continue to gain us marginal time on every train across the bridge, until we get this fully implemented.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I think the key thing is as Jeff mentioned, its capacity for growth, its security, its safety. We are not reducing American jobs. We are not exporting American jobs to Mexico. This is all about growth and operational efficiency. We've been working on this for 5 or more years. It's a very complicated project and very complicated initiative, and as you've heard us say many times in the past what we are hoping to achieve here, not just with the cruise, with customs, with security, with inspections, with FRA, all of those agencies have been very supportive of what we're trying to do here. We're basically trying to replicate at the U.S.-Mexico border, the processes that exist today at the U.S.-Canadian border. So that's an important consideration. I think just, so people on the phone don't think that we're trying to do something that's unprecedented here or just ridiculous in terms of being aggressive. We're just trying to replicate systems that already exist in other places.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question comes from the line of Brian Ossenbeck with JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Patrick Ossenbeck,  JP Morgan Chase &amp; Co, Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I want to come back to AMLO for a second. There was a comment early about the government getting sworn in at the end of the year, but Congress will be constituted on September 1. So you know there is a possibility MORENA could still get the 2/3 constitutional majority with some party realignment they already have the 50% plus 1 on the local side. So how do you -- how do you handicap this outcome? Do you have any visibility to any changes that might be coming in Congress aside from what we've already seen in the polls?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  No. I mean, nothing other than what we've heard in the messaging that has come from the leadership from AMLO himself and from his key advisors and transition team. He's I think -- our view is -- and you guys, Brian, you guys got a pretty good research capability down in Mexico, so we get a lot of insights from your own people there, but he is sort of backed off some of the early promises or statements that he made about reversing Energy reform and even on public infrastructure projects like the high-profile Mexico City airport. What he said recently is he is going to look more at the contracts and seems to be looking and shining a bright light on possible corruption that may be involved in energy and airport or public works projects as opposed to just reversing course. He has said things about wanting to maintain a strong national energy entity. So making sure that PEMEX continues to exist and survive and be relevant, but way short of saying things like he wants to reverse energy reforms. So again, based on what we've seen and the messaging that has come out of the administration, it just doesn't seem like he has put constitutional reform at the top of his list. José, anything to add to that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 José Guillermo Zozaya Delano,  Kansas City Southern - President, GM &amp; Executive Representative of Kansas City Southern de México Sa de C.v.   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  No. Just the confirmation of what you just said on the direct conversations we have had with his team. They have also assured to us that they will review some of the contracts. And that's not looking for other things but to find out if there were some corruption on the contracts.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  You know, you guys I think some of those data and insights that we've gained over time is coming from many of you on the call or your research capabilities, but if he can really get at corruption, there is -- I've seen numbers recently that, that could be 2 or 3 points of GDP for Mexico, if he can really make a significant headway in reducing corruption and the economic drain that results from corruption. He's taken a 40% -- I think he's announced a 40% reduction in his own compensation and then because of the way the rules work in Mexico, that will filter down to all other levels of government. So austerity, corruption, security, those things really seem to be top of his agenda as opposed to any major changes in constitutional reform or economic policy. But as is the case with all transitions in government, we will engage with the new leadership and we will stay very close to what's going on and try to make sure we are active in not only informing but influencing the path forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Patrick Ossenbeck,  JP Morgan Chase &amp; Co, Research Division - Senior Equity Analyst   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Just 1 quick follow up for Brian. Frac sands sourcing changes, I know, has been a topic for a while now. But yesterday, we heard from Union Pacific that they're actually starting to see some declines in the Permian and some production impact from all the takeaway capacity. So you know franchises are bit different but still connected, just want to get your updated thoughts on that as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian D. Hancock,  Kansas City Southern - Executive VP &amp; CMO   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Brian, I would say that we concur with that, we're starting to see sand coming in from other areas. Certainly, our customers are using a lot of sand, but I would say there are some sourcing changes that are occurring in the market. We're not sure where they're actually going to land out, but certainly it's impacting the Permian basin and we're seeing it. So I would concur with that, but we're -- we still have a significant amount of sand moving, and we'll just stay closer. But it looks like to me that we're going to have both brown and white sand used for quite a while in this area. So that's why I would land on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  There are no further questions at this time. Mr. Ottensmeyer, I turn the floor back to you for closing comments.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Patrick J. Ottensmeyer,  Kansas City Southern - CEO, President &amp; Director   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  All right. It's a Friday afternoon in July, I'll go back to my suggested headlines for the quarter. Solid volume and revenue growth in most strategic growth areas, particularly cross-border growth. Our weakness in volume, we feel is very isolated, primarily the Energy, some of, which is crude oil timing and obviously, coal, which is pretty well understood. And now we've talked a lot about weakness in intermodal with some of, which is intentional and thoughtful, as we try to respond to changing market environment. Second half outlook points to improve sequential growth in volume and revenue. And the long-term outlook just shows multiple, oversize growth opportunities. So we still feel very excited and enthusiastic about the longer-term outlook. So feel free to use any of those headlines that you want and have a great weekend and we'll talk to you all in 90 days. Thank you much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  This concludes today's teleconference. You may disconnect your lines at this time. Thank you for your participation.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2018 Kansas City Southern Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>KANSAS CITY</city>
  <companyName>Kansas City Southern</companyName>
  <companyTicker>KSU</companyTicker>
  <startDate>20-Jul-18 12:45pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>95857</companyId>
  <CUSIP>485170302</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2607647</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US4851703029</ISIN>
</Event>