<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="7691067" lastUpdate="Thursday, May 30, 2019 at 4:09:01pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="7691067.F" expirationDate="Tuesday, December 5, 2017 at 8:30:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of LB.TO earnings conference call or presentation 5-Dec-17 8:30pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q4 2017 Laurentian Bank of Canada Earnings Call

Montreal May 30, 2019 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Laurentian Bank of Canada earnings conference call or presentation Tuesday, December 5, 2017 at 8:30:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  François Desjardins
      Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director
   *  François Laurin
      Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO
   *  Stéphane Therrien
      Laurentian Bank of Canada - EVP of Personal &amp; Commercial Banking
   *  Susan Cohen
      Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR
   *  Susan Kudzman
      Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Darko Mihelic
      RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst
   *  Gabriel Dechaine
      National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst
   *  Lemar Persaud
      TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst
   *  Meny Grauman
      Cormark Securities Inc., Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Institutional Equity Research
   *  Nick Stogdill
      Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst
   *  Robert Sedran
      CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Research
   *  Sohrab Movahedi
      BMO Capital Markets Equity Research - Analyst
   *  Sumit Malhotra
      Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Research Division - MD of Canadian Financial Services

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day, (foreign language), and welcome to the Laurentian Bank Financial Group Fourth Quarter 2017 Results Conference Call. Today's conference is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Susan Cohen, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, ma'am.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us. This afternoon's review of fourth quarter and fiscal 2017 results will be presented by François Desjardins, President and CEO; and François Laurin, Executive Vice President and CFO. All documents pertaining to the quarter, including the press release and investor presentation as well as the 2017 annual report, can be found on our website in the Investors section. Following our formal comments, the senior management team will be available to answer questions.
 Before we begin, let me remind you that during this conference call, forward-looking statements may be made, and it's possible that actual results may differ materially from those projected in such statements. For the complete cautionary note regarding forward-looking statements, please refer to our press release or to Slide 2 of the presentation.
 It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to François Desjardins.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Susan, and good afternoon, everyone.
 Two years ago, Laurentian Bank announced its 7-year transformation plan, with clear goals to accomplish by 2022: achieve a return on equity that is comparable to the Canadian banking industry, double the size of the organization and build a solid foundation. Well, I'm very happy to report that 2017 has been a successful year in which we have made significant progress in our transformation plan. As such, the board has approved an increase in the quarterly common share dividend of $0.01 to $0.63 per share.
 Our performance was strong. We reduced the gap in ROE compared to the Canadian banking industry average from 450 basis points in 2015 to 360 basis points now. We improved our efficiency ratio from 71% to 66%, 2 years ahead of our 2019 target. This is a result of a combination of revenue and efficiency initiatives, including the merger of 46 branches.
 In terms of growth, we have successfully moved forward on 3 of our 4 growth objectives. In fact, we are 1 year ahead of our targets for loans to business customers, residential mortgages through independent brokers and advisers, and assets under management at Laurentian Bank Securities. Although there has been growth in the mutual fund portfolio distributed by Retail Services, we are behind on our target. This is because we have not been able to grow the number of advisers as planned. We concentrated our efforts on loans to business customers, and with the acquisitions of CIT Canada and Northpoint Financial Corporation, we accelerated the change in the mix of the business and the margin improvement.
 From a foundational perspective, our move from traditional to digital banking as is well under way with the implementation of the first wave of core banking. We have also made great progress in terms of strengthening key areas of the banks, such as risk management compliance, human resources and technology. But I must admit that these very positive 2 years have also seen more than their share of economic challenges, market disruption and new regulatory requirements. What this means for us as the largest of the small- and medium-sized banks is that to continue progressing, 2018 will be a year of investment in people, processes and technologies. These investments will ensure disciplined growth, strengthen the foundation and simplify the organization. Looking forward, the next 2 years will be pivotal because of the implementations that will occur and the changes that will be fundamental to our bank. Taking this into account, we have reset our midterm performance and growth targets from 2019 to 2020 and are keeping the 2022 objectives intact. In 2018 and into '19, we will continue to roll out our core banking system as well as launch our digital offerings. This will mean a simpler product suite, straight-through processing and fully mobile distribution. The end of 2019 will also bring the implementation of our AIRB program, which will positively impact our capital in '20, '21 and 2022. It is fully expected that good governance, processes and procedures, documentation and technologies will be at the forefront of our efforts, as required by the AIRB program. Going forward, optimizing financial resources, including funding and capital, will lead to improved RWA management and is a consideration when resetting our growth targets. As well, the changing economic and regulatory environment could impact our targets. As such, we plan to manage the growth in residential mortgages to mid-single digits, and until the implementations of AIRB approach, we expect similar growth overall in loans to business customers.
 We are also introducing 2 new 2020 growth targets: assets under administrations at Retail Services and total deposits from clients, which we think reflect a more holistic investment profile of our clients. In addition to tracking AUM at Laurentian Bank securities, going forward, these 5 indicators will constitute measures of our success. Furthermore, we estimate that solely through organic growth, that is, without taking any advantage of future acquisition opportunities, our total assets are expected to reach $55 billion in 2022.
 In terms of our financial performance. In 2018, we expect that revenues and margins will benefit from the full impact of Northpoint acquisition, and ROE will be relatively stable. We will need an extra year to narrow the ROE gap to 300 basis points, but we should be able to close it completely and on time for 2022. With efficiency gains anticipated at '19, our efficiency ratio should stay south of 65% by 2020 and south of 60% by 2022.
 With respect to CET1, it is at the lower end of our range of 7.9%, given that our growth over the last 2 years has been ahead of our plan and that we have been investing in initiatives to build our foundation.
 The implementation of AIRB and RWA management should result in capital gradually strengthening over the course of '20, '21 and '22. Our projections suggest an improvement of 200 basis points of ROE once capital is redeployed. Nonetheless, we must also plan for the anticipated implementation of revised standardized methodology, even though we expect to adopt the AIRB before that implementation.
 Before I close, I know that you may have some questions about mortgage securitization today. And in full transparency, we disclosed earlier that we will need to buy back loans from a third-party purchaser because they were deemed not eligible. François Laurin will give some more color on the situation, but let me first say that this is largely a documentation and securitization eligibility issue, that it is not material for the bank, its operations, its funding, nor its capital and that we have worked to change processes to ensure that this issue is resolved.
 So, a lot of work is behind us, but there is still more in front of us. And as our organization evolves, so too has our name. To better reflect the diverse nature of our business and the sum of our parts, our businesses and legal entities are now collectively referred to as Laurentian Bank Financial Group. This new name embodies who we are really today. We are very proud of the progress that we have made here at Laurentian Bank, and invite you to read our annual report and have a look at the LBCFG website. There, you can find our results and accomplishments for 2017 and our plans for 2018 and beyond.
 I would also like to thank you for your continued interest, our shareholders and investors for your continuous support and our dedicated team members for your efforts and successes.
 And now, I would like to turn the floor over to François Laurin to provide a more in-depth review of our fourth quarter and 2017 financial results. François?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, François. Good afternoon, everyone. I would like to begin by turning to Slide 16, which highlights the bank's financial performance. Adjusted EPS in the fourth quarter was $1.63, up 11% compared with a year earlier. Fourth quarter EPS was impacted by 21% more shares outstanding. As outlined on Slide 17, reported earnings for the fourth quarter included adjusting items totaling $7.8 million after tax or $0.21 per share related to restructuring charges and business combinations.
 The drivers of our performance are presented on Slide 18. Total revenue for the fourth quarter of 2017 reached $268 million, an increase of 13% compared with a -- to a year earlier. Net interest income rose 18% due to strong volume growth in the commercial loan portfolio from organic growth and from the full quarter impact of the acquisition of CIT Canada and the recent acquisition of Northpoint. Other income increased by 5%. For the full year, revenue grew 9%, reflecting the positive impact of our strategic acquisitions.
 Net interest margin shown on Slide 19 was 1.75%. The main factor contributing to the 12 basis point sequential increase is the higher proportion of higher-yielding loans to business customers, mainly due to the recent acquisition of Northpoint. Driving the 13% year-over-year increase in average earning assets is the growth in loans to business customers of 22% and the growth in residential mortgage loans generated through independent brokers and advisers of 22% as well. Looking ahead, we expect margins to trend higher in 2018 due to the shift in the bank's portfolio mix, including the full year impact of the Northpoint acquisition and the recent increase in lending rates.
 Other income, as presented on Slide 20, totaled $91.7 million, an increase by $4.1 million or 5% year-over-year. The increase was broad-based, with particular strength in lending fees, reflecting the higher activity in the commercial portfolios and income from sales of mutual funds, reflecting the bank's focus on financial advice. As well, in the fourth quarter of 2017, the other category included a $5.9 million gain on the sale of the bank's participation in a mortgage broker company, Verico Financial Group. This amounted to $5.3 million after tax or $0.14 per share.
 Slide 21 presents adjusted noninterest expenses that increased by 8% in the fourth quarter compared to a year earlier, mainly due to the traditional -- sorry, the additional employees from CIT Canada and Northpoint, and higher performance-based compensation. For 2017, adjusted noninterest expense growth was 3%. Reported noninterest expenses were impacted by restructuring charges, as mentioned before. Reflecting our efforts to control expenses and grow revenue -- sorry, and grow revenues, the adjusted efficiency ratio in the fourth quarter was 64.3%. For the full year, this ratio stood at 66.1%, an improvement of 350 basis points compared to 2016. As well, adjusted operating leverage was positive for both the quarter and the year.
 Slide 22 presents the continued progress towards optimizing our sources of funding. To this end, in 2018, we may seek U.S. dollar facilities to better align the funding of Northpoint's U.S. dollar portfolio. With respect to deposit growth in the fourth quarter, it was strong, up 2% and 5% quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year, respectively. Attrition and branch deposits was in line with expectations given our branch mergers. Personal deposits sourced through independent brokers and advisers increased 4% quarter-over-quarter and 3% year-over-year despite a competitive environment. Growth in business and institutional deposits was strong. As well, securitization activities increased sequentially, reflecting additional lease finance receivables that were securitized.
 With respect to our mortgage securitizations. During the fourth quarter of 2017, as explained in our MD&amp;A, we identified some mortgages that were inadvertently sold to the third-party -- to a third-party purchaser. These identified mortgages amount to $180 million and are in the process of being repurchased by the bank in the first quarter of 2018. These mortgages equate to 1% of the bank's residential mortgage portfolio and 0.5% of its total loan portfolio. As such, this is not expected to be material to the bank's operations, funding or capital. Furthermore, these identified mortgages do not represent a credit issue as they are all performing in line with the bank's overall mortgage portfolio. I would like to add that no employees were implicated in any misrepresentation, and the bank found no significant concentration of mortgages with misrepresentation with any single broker.
 Finally, as of November 1, we began to enhance our quality control functions and underwriting procedures, including introducing new internal monitoring processes and reorganizing employees who deal with mortgage intake and processing.
 Turning to Slide 23. The CET1 ratio of 7.9% is presented under the standardized approach and is unchanged from the prior period. The slide also highlights the evolution of the CET1 ratio over the year.
 Our diversified loan portfolio is highlighted on Slide 25. Loans to business customers have increased to 33% of the portfolio from 30% a year ago and residential mortgages remain unchanged at 50%. Within the residential mortgage portfolio, Alt-A mortgages totaled $1.5 billion and represent 8% of the total mortgage book and 4% of the total loan portfolio. As well, mortgages in the GTA represent about 8 -- 20% of the portfolio, and the GVA accounts for 4%. LTVs remain low, and credit scores remain high.
 Turning to Slide 28. Credit quality remains good. In the fourth quarter of 2017, the provision for credit losses was $11.5 million, $5.1 million higher than in the prior quarter, which included a release of allowances and provisions of about $5 million. The loss ratio remained unchanged from a year ago at 13 basis points.
 Slide 29 highlights that the net impaired loans are relatively stable from a year ago, while gross impaired loans are $19.6 million higher. This increase is in line with the strong growth in the bank's loan portfolios, including the impact of the recent acquisitions. Sequentially, gross impaired loans increased by $33.4 million, reflecting 2 distinct commercial loans totaling $31.9 million and the addition of Northpoint impaired loans of $8.5 million. Overall, we continue to believe that the underlying credit quality of the portfolios remains good.
 While we have been stating this for several quarters, we continue to expect that over the medium term, that the loss ratio will gradually move higher as our business mix changes, but it should be more than offset by higher net interest income. Nonetheless, with our current portfolio mix, conservative provisioning and disciplined education process, we expect that the loss ratio will remain below other Canadian banks.
 To conclude, we are very pleased with the core earnings performance in the core -- in the fourth quarter and fiscal 2017, and the progress that we're making as we continue to execute our transformation plan.
 Thank you for your attention, and I will now turn the call back to Susan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At this point, I would like to turn the call over to the conference call operator for the question-and-answer session. Ron?
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) And we'll take the first question in queue from the line of Robert Sedran with CIBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Sedran,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Research   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wanted to ask around the mortgages that I guess both François and François talked about. When were the problems discovered? And when were these loans originated?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for the question. This is Susan. We were informed of this third-party -- the results of the third-party audits, the sample, at the end of September and have been working on it, investigating and doing audits since then. The mortgages have an average duration over 2 to 2.5 years, approximately.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Sedran,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Research   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And so it was the third party that bought these to your attention? This wasn't part of a regular review of your own book that you were doing?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, it was part of a normal course audit by the third-party, yes. And then we, obviously, took these results and took our own look at it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Sedran,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Research   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And just following on to what the new -- as you continue to look into what you find, I mean, I'm not exactly sure how loans that were not eligible for portfolio insurance ended up getting portfolio insurance. Can you add a little bit more color to that as well, please?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, there is really just -- to be clear, let's -- I'll just step back, and there's two issues here. One is related to documentation, and I can speak to that a little if you wish. And the second portion is really related to your questions and, yes, they were ineligible. They were products that are in line with our underwriting criteria and that should not have been eligible as per their characteristics, and it was really a systems issue. Our systems were not sufficiently refined and missed some adequate -- the adequate flagging mechanisms and there's just some manual error there. So that has been remediated with some workarounds, and our new core banking system has a functionality to avoid this type of issue, but that's really how it happened.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Sedran,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Research   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, and I'm sorry. I know others will have some other questions. I'm not looking to monopolize. Just one point of clarification, what was it about the loans that did not make them eligible for portfolio insurance?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. As I said, they're really the 2 issues. So the ones that are document -- that didn't have proper documentation and as a result, should not have qualified for the securitization. We can talk about that if you wish. But the ineligible ones are products that we call Equity 50, Equity 65, they're products that are in line with our underwriting criteria and then we sell outright. The Equity 50s have a very low loan to value, so it's a loan to value of 50% and has no income verification, as the loan-to-value is so very low. And Equity 65 is somewhat of a variance on that. It's a loan-to-value of 65%, the income and with a total debt service ratio below 50%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is François Desjardins here. The securitization, the third party purchaser has a securitization conduit, which has rules around what can go into the conduit or not. And these loans, by definition, were not allowed into this conduit even though they're perfectly good credits.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Meny Grauman with Cormark Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Meny Grauman,  Cormark Securities Inc., Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Institutional Equity Research   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just following up on that line of questioning. I guess, the fundamental issue or question is, what was the issue? I mean, is it the case -- or one would say potentially that you're just growing too quickly, and do you see any -- do you see that as valid? And is there any credence to that, that these errors come out when you're going so quickly, those kinds of errors have the potential to creep up?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That might be a part of it, but, in all fairness, the -- as Susan said, it's really 2 separate issues and has to do with -- the first issue is documentation. These are clients that want to get a loan and might misrepresent themselves. And then there's just documentation itself or the proofs of the representation from the clients. I think that overall, growth might be an issue but also, just process in terms of validation, and we've remediated those process by recombining these teams together. The second issue is eligibility, so that is a completely separate issue, where the credits were done perfectly fine and there's no issues in terms of documentation or any otherwise, but they just should have not been portfolio insured or should not have been put into the conduit. So going back to previous questions, we were, in a normal course, of course, we were looking at these. And once we were advised of the issues, we went back to look at all of the other portfolios that we have in the bank, and that is our disclosure today. Just to make sure, as François might have said, this is worth about 0.5% of the total book, so we deem that to be nonmaterial to the operations or to the funding. What we have to do is 2 things. First, buy back the loans that were mistakenly put that into the conduit and, of course, ensure that, that doesn't happen again and we built -- we have already changed processes to ensure that documentation is what it needs to be from the intake perspective.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Meny Grauman,  Cormark Securities Inc., Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Institutional Equity Research   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Is it correct that you're still going through a broader review? Or is that all done? You've checked everything that you intend to check?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François here again. As we disclosed in the MD&amp;A, we went through the whole evaluation on the B2B bank side, so that is completely behind us. And what is left to do is on the branch banking side and, therefore, we still have that to do. But applying the same rules, that's how we came out with the disclosure numbers. Our indications to date is that there is nothing to believe that it was -- it wouldn't be any other way than what we disclosed so far.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Meny Grauman,  Cormark Securities Inc., Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Institutional Equity Research   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 When do you expect that review of the branch network to be completed?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Over the coming months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Next 2 months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Meny Grauman,  Cormark Securities Inc., Research Division - MD &amp; Head of Institutional Equity Research   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And I'll let others go. Just a final question. You talked about how no employees were implicated. Is it your belief that that's going to remain that way? Or do you still leave that open? How definitive is that conclusion?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At this point, I would say, very definitive. We have no indication whatsoever that these things were intentional by any of our employees, nor any concentration around brokers whatsoever.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Gabriel Dechaine with National Bank Financial.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So I just want to clarify something. The top -- this Page 38 of the MD&amp;A here, the top half, like, you've got 2 issues here. One is you sold some mortgages to a third-party and it turns out there was documentation issues and client misrepresentations and those are -- those aren't paperwork issues. And then the second issue, I guess, is what went into these securitization conduits? That might be more of a paperwork issue. I guess -- I'll go after both areas, I guess. The top one, what are client misrepresentations? Can you clarify what that means? And you said the normal course audit, what happens? Normal course implies, I don't know, once a year, twice a year, I have no idea. So what changed in the past 6 months or a year to kind of uncover these things?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Kudzman,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP, Chief Risk Officer &amp; Corporate Affairs Officer   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So I'll take them in order. So first of all, you're right that there are 2 different issues, the documentation and the ineligible mortgages that found their way into the conduits that should not have. So let's go back to the documentation issues. That is a paperwork issue also. The vast majority are a lack of proper documentation, and it does include some potential client misrepresentations as well as client misrepresentations, and maybe that's where your question was. And what is a client misrepresentation? It's a situation where the client has provided or we suspect has provided inaccurate information in -- with the objective of obtaining a mortgage to be able to purchase a home that these credits are -- the credit is still very good and they are paying. So the vast majority of that first category is paperwork or lack of proper documentation. So I don't know if that fully answers your question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible) terminology here, but it's a different type of paperwork issue. The other one sounds like you just mistakenly shifted some...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that would be the case. A process issue, if you will, the first one. And the second one, we can just maybe summarize it as a mistake, a systems mistake or an operational mistake. But yes and the vast majority were the lack of proper documentation that disqualified them from the conduit and we are repurchasing.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the second one, the process issue, $5.2 billion of mortgages there. And it says no internal audit of such loans has been conducted, meaning that's [maybe $6] million of ineligible mortgages or ineligible for insurance, you don't need to audit it? Or is that something that is still coming, perhaps?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we've notified this third-party purchaser. And at this point, no indication that there will be an issue there. And if there is, well, we'll resolve it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then I guess, you're repurchasing $180 million of mortgages. And that would be from the, I guess, the paperwork, the misrepresentation part of the issues here. What if there were...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The both. They would be on the -- half-and-half on documentation and the mistakes, if you will, the administrative ineligible mortgages.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then what happens if it goes -- like, is it primarily broker deposits? What are you going to -- what funding are you going to -- you haven't purchased them yet, I take it. And what funding? Are you going to be stepping up, your broker channel activity? If you look through your branch channel, deposits are still shrinking.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel, François Laurin. We've started already. We've already repurchased $35 million out of the $180 million. The rest will be done by the end of this quarter. We have -- as usual, we have healthy excess liquidity balance and various sources of funding to be able to repurchase this without any materiality and impact on our books as of now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just to be clear on that. We have the funds already to purchase these loans back as we speak. Our funding is diversified and strong. We don't need to go and get extra funding. We have it already.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And are you reviewing -- because we've got $5.2 billion and $1.2 billion, there's $700 million of mortgages, it's well below half of your total mortgage book, is there more? Or are you undertaking a broader review than just these 2 buckets, I guess? And I'll throw in my last, while I'm at it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, that's -- let's be clear. When we did the review, and this is how François explained it, of course, is that we've agreed to purchase $180 million back already from the third-party purchaser. Obviously, these are the loans that had documentation issues and were -- or were not eligible for the conduit, and we've already made that determination. We have no need to repurchase the whole securitization conduit nor the second -- no indication that we need to do anything else than finish the audit that we have already started for the branch network and validate that our numbers are there, which we believe they're clear, and work to resolve those issues as well. So just in full transparency, when you add up $180 million plus $124 million, that's how you get to the $304 million number that we disclosed.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And obviously, as we change our processes, policies, procedures and make changes in the teams, that will not just the fit mortgages that are securitized but it's the entire process that has been modified.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then last one, I swear. Was there an -- you talked about no concentration of mortgage issues with a single broker, no issues with employees. Is this -- have you noticed a trend between Alt-A and conventional mortgages? Like, where are you seeing these issues?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is all conventional and there is no trend, neither with employees or with the brokers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from Sumit Malhotra with Scotia Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sumit Malhotra,  Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Research Division - MD of Canadian Financial Services   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm going to maybe tag in a couple of things just in terms of your outlook and this issue as well. François, when you were starting off, talking about the transformation plan, what's been accomplished and where things are going, you did mention that in both mortgage, residential mortgages and then your commercial book, you are expecting a moderating pace of growth. Let's just play that out a bit. I look at your numbers. Mortgages are up 10% year-over-year, one of the better rates in the Canadian banking industry. Commercial, obviously, you had some acquisition benefit this quarter but the growth has still been double-digit. So in talking about -- I think I heard you say mid-single digits was more realistic in the near term. Is that a combination of factors at play here, B20 economic outlook as well as some of the things we're talking about today? Or do you think it's just a reflection of where your business is right now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, first of all, it's a reflection of the size of the book today because as per -- as the size goes bigger, the percentages of the book intake goes smaller, so...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sumit Malhotra,  Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Research Division - MD of Canadian Financial Services   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rule of large numbers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, exactly. But no, we felt that going forward, we needed to manage our RWA better and we needed to have profitable growth, not just growth. As you know, we've been challenged with a new B20 during the past 2 years, and we're awaiting the impacts of that in the next year. Of course, that's coming in January. So, all things considered, that is really the reasons for the moderation of the growth, and that has nothing to do with the disclosure that we did today.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sumit Malhotra,  Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Research Division - MD of Canadian Financial Services   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then in one of the comments that you brought up, is that you said there isn't any issue related to specific mortgage brokers that you deal with or anything on an employee front. As you've gone through your review, are there any relationships, whether it's within B2B or some of the brokers you deal with that have suggested to you that perhaps, there are some counterparties you shouldn't be doing business with?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll just take that. Over the course of the normal process of Q&amp;A and on a regular basis, the quality control teams identify, all the time, brokers that do have -- that we don't want to do business with and that we warn and not do business with again for all kinds of reasons, including they send us loans that we don't want to do or other. This is like an ongoing process and everyone that does business with mortgage brokers do that on a regular course. The disclosure that we did today is over and above that. It was a more in-depth review, where we saw that we needed to get a lot better still than we were in ensuring that we have the proper docs, but also from a systems perspective, that we don't put into conduits things that are just by rules of the conduits, not eligible.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sumit Malhotra,  Scotiabank Global Banking and Markets, Research Division - MD of Canadian Financial Services   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Last one for me, and I hope I'm not mixing a few items together here. But you did push some of these midterm objectives back a year, to 2020, which is also supposed to be the year in which you start reporting under AIRB. As you have indicated, a step up in investment spend over the next couple of years and, certainly, AIRB always does give credit for your credit risk management. Are there any changes to that timeline as far as AIRB adoption is concerned? And is there anything -- as you mentioned today, the speed of growth in the mortgage brokers one of the factors for some of these issues not being captured. Is there anything that gives you pause in terms of the ability of your systems to adapt to the AIRB adoption?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. One is not linked to the other. The reset to 2020 was really to align all of the objectives midterm, and started with the fact that knowing what we need to do in the next 2 years from an investment perspective, and I had discussed this at the last call, we really need to invest. And of course, we're running systems side by side. We started implementing our core banking system and we're also running the old systems. And that will be in parallel with, of course, technology cost and people until we get everyone off the old system. That made our 300 basis points' target one year later than what we thought, and that was the basis for the reset in the year. From the efficiency perspective or growth, et cetera, we just recalibrated those to align to the same year. As for AIRB, that project is actually going very well. We're expecting that to be implemented at the end of 2019 and to start getting some benefits in '19, '20, '21 -- sorry, in '20, '21, '22. And of course, as I stated in my speech, we're still expecting to have the benefits of about 200 basis points of ROE lift once it's fully implemented. So, no, the reset of the targets had nothing to do with AIRB.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Nick Stogdill with Crédit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just on -- back to the mortgage topic. Is there any specific -- I guess, a few mortgages concentrated in Québec. Is there a geographic concentration for these?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, no.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But the ones in the branch, that will be mostly through Québec, that's fair?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Clearly, yes, but the one -- the repurchase we're making so far are for -- are not -- are diversified portfolio across the country.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. And the documentation issues you called out, is it an issue with respect to your standard? Or was the client's standard higher than yours? And more broadly, do they meet the original sort of B20 standards? Where -- I guess I'm just trying to understand, who is it -- is it an issue for you or the client more so?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It was in line. The audit was done and we've been pursuing in line with our own standards.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So these mortgages meet your own standards but they don't meet the third-party purchaser standards?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. The mortgages we will be repurchasing were lacking documentation as per our own standards.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, okay. And then just on the restructuring charges, a clarification here. Last quarter, you indicated you were at $5 million on the retail side, and you were getting to $6 million. I think there was about $4 million going through this quarter and then in the release, I saw you expect to incur additional costs over the next 12 months. So should we be kind of adjusting our forecast here? Is there more to do with that change?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin here. On the CIT integration, we've said that so far, we're close to $16 million has been taken into the integration, and we have less than $2 million to go before the end of Q2 for the integration. We're moving to our software system for the portfolio and we may have another -- close to $2 million of OpEx to -- restructuring charge to take by the end of February -- by the end of January. No, not January, so by the end of April, sorry. So, less than $2 million over the next 2 quarters. And then from the retail, on the retail, it was a little higher than we expected, just by a few million dollars. We expect about $4 million potentially over the next year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Nick Stogdill,  Crédit Suisse AG, Research Division - Research Analyst   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So that's incremental from what we had last quarter? Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Darko Mihelic with RBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A number of questions here. Going to the review of the mortgage portfolios and some of the issues here. The Equity 50 and Equity 65 products that were inadvertently sold into the conduit, I mean, those are relatively easy to find, right? So I guess the question here is, that is unlikely to grow from the current $91 million that you were going to purchase back, is that correct?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's correct.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's correct.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Find it, established and determined.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So then the only issue here is as you go through the branch system, we're looking for other issues of documentation and misrepresentation. And I guess what I find very strange in the commentary is that, typically, if you're lacking documentation, you would -- it's usually to be something around income verification. But you mentioned there's no trend, so I'm a little bit confused by a lack of documentation but no trend. Can you maybe speak more? I mean, can you give me some examples of what it was that was lacking, that the audit caught in terms of documentation or client misrepresentation?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I'd just like to clarify a point that the no trend is no trend among certain brokers or specific employees or specific branches, if you will, at this point. Lack of documentation, you're quite right. Client misrepresentation is when a client in trying to obtain a mortgage and not defraud anything else but obtain a mortgage to purchase a home, will give inaccurate information, which is mostly surrounding income and source of down payment, et cetera. That would be, if you wish to call it a trend, the main places where this lack of documentation is surrounded.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, understood. And then what -- at this stage, what's going to -- what would the third-party purchaser need to open up the conduit again?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We need to go over a confirmatory audit that they need to come back to clarify not -- to confirm there are full audit that we've -- a full review that we've done. And then, as we mentioned, complete, move on with the branch audit and then have their sort of blessing and accord to the results that we will of determined based on that review to come in the next few months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And did they commit to opening up the conduit once this was over and once you repurchased all of the mortgages that have these issues?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Maybe moving on to something else that I'd like to ask about, the MD&amp;A. It is with respect to Northpoint and the disclosure of its impact in the quarter and what it would have been for the entire year. So the first question is, was there something in the quarter for Northpoint that would have either suppressed or helped earnings in the quarter that would not be expected to continue going forward?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko, François Laurin here. I guess, just to make sure, you're referring to the note in the financial statement as if we -- the results of their operations that's disclosed there of over $3 million -- less than $4 million of net income?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So that net income is really on a reported basis per legal entity of NCF itself in the States as we purchased that entity. So it does then take into account the amortization of the intangible, which is over $3 million pretax that we [took] out of adjusted earnings. So that, you would have to take that out and it doesn't take into account the tax structure that's more efficient globally for that investment. So basically, this is closer to $7 million rather than the $3 million-something that you see in the financial statement, which makes it neutral and not -- slightly positive for the quarter even on an EPS basis. Even if we had decided we had mentioned at the acquisition that it would be only accretive in 2019. The -- it's clear to us that it will be accretive in 2018 going forward.
 I don't know if that...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Darko Mihelic,  RBC Capital Markets, LLC, Research Division - Financials Analyst   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, that's helpful. And I guess -- that's very helpful. Thank you for that disclosure. And just further on that topic, is the funding structure for NCF optimal right now? And if you could optimize it, how much would that improve the earnings?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There's not much difference at the moment between funding it in Canadian dollars, swapping it into U.S. versus having direct access to U.S. funding at this point. But we still will be looking at U.S. funding for, again, for diversification and full hedging and simplify it going forward. So you wouldn't see a very -- it wouldn't be a difference, noticeable difference, Darko.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Lemar Persaud with TD Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just continuing on the mortgage issue. François, is it fair to say that in pushing out your residential mortgage growth target from $9 billion by 2019 to $10 billion by 2020, you're not expecting to hit the brakes on mortgage originations as a result of this issue? Is that a fair comment?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is a fair comment. The comment I made earlier on the call is that we do have to take into consideration new B20 impacts, though, and of course, the rising-rate environment. So we were expecting -- we are expecting to have less of an intake than in the past, and that's pretty universal. The comments that the other banks have given are similar comments in that regard.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then my next question is, did the review of the branch underwritten mortgage that you guys are still undergoing result in a lift to NIE in Q1 '18? It sounds like you're going to be substantially complete by the time you guys report Q1 '18 results. Is that correct? And is there going to be any lift in NIE that we could see?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar, you're referring to the mortgage review?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The timing?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. It would be complete -- I think we will -- it will be complete by the end of Q1 2018. But your question is will that create a lift in NII?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You mean net interest and net margin?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, like expenses. Will there be any rise in expenses...
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Noninterest expenses. Clearly, it is an element but we -- it doesn't detract us from our target to meet the efficiency ratio going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lemar Persaud,  TD Securities Equity Research - Analyst   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. My next question then is, François, when you're talking about higher margins for 2018, are you talking about higher margins relative to 2017 as a whole or higher margins relative to Q4 '17?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Laurin,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, both, but clearly, the higher the both of the 2 is Q4. We definitely believe the acquisition of Northpoint will bring that margin up going forward from Q4 results you see, the $173 million.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll now take the next question from the line of Sohrab Movahedi from BMO Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sohrab Movahedi,  BMO Capital Markets Equity Research - Analyst   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just a few clarifying questions. Hopefully, when the securitization conduits reopens, will there be any pricing repercussions? Will you have to pay a higher premium?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We don't expect it at all.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sohrab Movahedi,  BMO Capital Markets Equity Research - Analyst   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And when you move to the AIRB, François, I mean, there's going to be an op risk RWA component. You don't expect this mortgage issue to have any regulatory capital implications with respect to op risk RWAs?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll ask Susan to give some color on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As you probably well know, the AIRB accreditation process is very formalized and very supervised by our regulator. And yes, operational risk processes count in the accreditation as well as charge to capital. But we've been moving on very well through their process and refining our process as we go forward. And this gives -- we've addressed this as immediately as we were notified and feel that it won't be an impediment to the AIRB process.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sohrab Movahedi,  BMO Capital Markets Equity Research - Analyst   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And you would expect to get the full benefit still? In other words, part of the explanation or part of the rationale here is we're going to close the gap from an ROE perspective because we'll have less capital intensity, and you think that formula still holds?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Yes, we do.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sohrab Movahedi,  BMO Capital Markets Equity Research - Analyst   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then just lastly on the Northpoint. Given the hurricanes and the extreme weather that had impacted some of their key markets, is the -- let's call it the equipment replacement cycle, is that going to be something that is going to be a net positive to the Northpoint business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stéphane?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stéphane Therrien,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - EVP of Personal &amp; Commercial Banking   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We, obviously follow the hurricane and the impact but, frankly, there would be no impact, positive or negative. Northpoint will continue to grow at the level that we're expecting them, but this would not be the main driver of their growth.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) We'll now take the next question from the line of Gabriel Dechaine with National Bank Financial.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gabriel Dechaine,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just had a quick follow-up. My last question was hurried, I guess. I just wanted to confirm what you meant by conventional mortgages. So the issues that you've uncovered in the documentation side, that wasn't alternative or in the Alt-A book, it was in the prime book?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 François Desjardins,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - President, CEO &amp; Non Independent Director   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, prime book, no Alt-A involved at all. And if I would add on that, just to make sure that everybody walks away with the correct information here. These are good credits. We like these credits. These are credits that we like that are all performing to the levels that we expect from the bank. Therefore, in summary, we have found an issue, we have to resolve it and buy back some loans, which we're in the process of doing and this will be resolved in the coming months or so. And of course, as I said in my initial comments, this represents about 0.5% of the total book of the bank, for which we have the capability of buying back to date. So this is why we view this as a securitization issue and not material to any of the operations, credit, funding nor capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Susan Cohen,  Laurentian Bank of Canada - Director of IR   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's it. Thank you. Thank you very much for joining us today. Should you have any further questions, our contact information is included at the end of the presentation. We look forward to speaking with you again at our first quarter of 2018 conference call on February 27th. Happy holidays to all.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's call. Thank you for your participation, and you may now disconnect your lines.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q4 2017 Laurentian Bank of Canada Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Montreal</city>
  <companyName>Laurentian Bank of Canada</companyName>
  <companyTicker>LB.TO</companyTicker>
  <startDate>5-Dec-17 8:30pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>95608</companyId>
  <CUSIP>51925D106</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2077347</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>CA51925D1069</ISIN>
</Event>