<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="5862336" lastUpdate="Thursday, November 12, 2015 at 6:10:27pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="5862336.F" expirationDate="Thursday, November 12, 2015 at 9:00:00am GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of LEG.DE earnings conference call or presentation 12-Nov-15 9:00am GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q3 2015 LEG Immobilien AG Earnings Call

Duesseldorf Nov 12, 2015 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of LEG Immobilien AG earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, November 12, 2015 at 9:00:00am GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Burkhard Sawazki
      LEG Immobilien AG - Head of IR
   *  Thomas Hegel
      LEG Immobilien AG - CEO
   *  Holger Hentschel
      LEG Immobilien AG - COO
   *  Eckhard Schultz
      LEG Immobilien AG - CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Andre Remke
      Baader Bank - Analyst
   *  Robert Woerdeman
      Kempen - Analyst
   *  Peter Papadakos
      Green Street Advisors - Analyst
   *  Bernd Janssen
      Victoria Partners - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to LEG Immobilien AG's conference call. At our customer's request the conference will be recorded. May I now hand you over to your moderator, Mr. Burkhard Sawazki, Head of Investor Relations?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Burkhard Sawazki,  LEG Immobilien AG - Head of IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, everyone. This is Burkhard Sawazki. I'm glad you could join us this morning for our earnings call. Our Management Board members, Thomas Hegel, Eckhard Schultz and Holger Hentschel will walk you through our presentation and give you more details on LEG's nine months' figures and our business outlook. As usual, this will be followed by a Q&amp;A session.
 With this, I will hand over to Thomas Hegel.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Hegel,  LEG Immobilien AG - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Burkhard. Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us for on third-quarter earnings call. I'd like to start with leading you through the nine-month highlights shown on chart 5.
 You all know that the third quarter was an extremely exciting one for LEG and, of course, also for us as the management team. We decided to support the takeover approach to offer our shareholders, on the basis of our successful business model, an additional growth optionality. However, we agreed on the termination of the business combination agreement. Against backdrop of this positive feedback we received from our shareholders we are very happy to continue our standalone growth strategy.
 On the basis of our extremely focused business model we are working very intensively on the optimization of all relevant drivers to maximize the value for our shareholders. We are committed to accelerate growth and in the last week we have already shown that this is not just a statement.
 The acquisition of the roughly 13,800 units is, in fact, another big step forward. The portfolio ideally fits to our focused strategy. In total, we have agreed on the acquisition of around 20,000 units year to date. We are expanding our leading market position in the Northern Westphalia market and we won't stop here. We are in talks for further acquisitions in our core markets to leverage our platform.
 Scale effects are on one side of the coin to enhance profitability for our shareholders. Cost efficiency is the other. At the beginning of this year we started a very comprehensive approach to analyze our entire cost structures and all our processes. The result of EUR10m annual cost savings we have now planned exceeds our internal expectations.
 Therefore, we are able to raise our EBITDA margin targets for 2017, from 71% to 72%. Consequently, a leading operating profitability and cash generation remains major cornerstone of our business model and our equity story.
 Just very briefly on our key operating and financial metrics, in the first nine months which are, again, a strong confirmation of the strength of LEG. Like-for-like rents in a year without major cost rent adjustments increased by 2.5% and in the free-financed part by 3.5%.
 A key differentiator is that we achieved such a letting result with annual CapEx and maintenance of around EUR15 per square meter. Our FFO climbs by 27.8% to EUR158.5m or by 7% -- by 17.9% to EUR2.76 on a per-share basis.
 The NAV, excluding goodwill, stands at EUR52.87. As you know, key growth driver for our NAV will be our property appraisal at year end. And here Eckhard will give you the first education later during this call.
 With that, I would like to hand over to Holger and the operations (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Holger Hentschel,  LEG Immobilien AG - COO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Thomas. Good morning also from my side. I would like to continue with the portfolio review on slide 7. In the third quarter we saw again a strong rental growth of 2.5% overall, despite absence of major cost rent adjustments, and of 3.5% for our free-financed units. In the unrestricted portfolio the very strong development was again supported by all of our three top markets, where we achieved an increase in rents of 3% to 3.9%.
 This result again reflects the quality of our portfolio with high exposure to urban areas, which are benefiting from a strong underlying demand trend and all our leading property-management skills.
 Coming to slide 8 let me now highlight a few specific markets to illustrate the underlying rent dynamics. In the high-growth markets we again saw strong rent momentum in Dusseldorf with a growth rate of 4.5% overall and even 7% for the free-financed units. In the Westphalia region rents grew by 5.3% in Gutersloh and 4.4% in Borken.
 In our stable markets we achieved strong performance in Hamm where we own around 2,800 units with 4.5%. And also in Solingen in the commuter belt of Dusseldorf with a rent growth of 4.8%.
 Finally, in the higheryielding markets, (inaudible) once again showed a very strong performance with an increase of 5% of the free-financed units. Also in our important Dusseldorf market, rents rose by 3.3%.
 Let's now move to the slide 9. The like-for-like EPRA vacancy remains flat year-on-year with 3.2%. In the higher-yielding markets the vacancy ratio is still above previous year's level. Earlier this year in our important Dusseldorf portfolio we have been affected by some capacity issues which has been solved by now. On a quarter-to-quarter basis we can already see a slight improvement of 20 basis points in this location. In relation to the entire portfolio, we are optimistic to increase the occupancy ratios in line with planning. And we can confirm our target to reach a very low like-for-like vacancy of around 2.8% at year end.
 Coming to the slide 10, which illustrates our maintenance and CapEx spending, in the first nine months we spent around EUR9.9m per square meter, which is still below the fiscal year run rate. You can, therefore, expect rising investments in Q4.
 For full-year 2016 we reiterate our guidance to spend around EUR15 per square meter and comparatively low ratio due to our well-maintained asset base and our high [tactical] discipline.
 With that, I would like to -- Eckhard?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Eckhard Schultz,  LEG Immobilien AG - CFO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let us now have a look at the financial highlights, slide 12, please. LEG's successful model generates a very attractive topline growth that's relatively low risk. We are increasingly benefiting from the structural advantages of our regionally focused platform and our portfolio density.
 Sound topline growth, scale effect from acquisitions as well as cost discipline, translates into further improvement of our operating margins and our leading profitability. Adjusted for the volatility of maintenance expenses, our adjusted EBITDA margin climbed by around 240 basis points on a yearly basis.
 On the basis of normalized quarterly maintenance expenses our nine month EBITDA margin reaches the level of more than 68%. If you do the math and if you strip out the distorting effects of our rent-restricted portfolio where you find the advantage] below the EBITDA line, our EBITDA margin would even be around 70%. I guess you will agree that this is a best-in-class ratio in the German resi sector.
 On the basis of our updated business plan we can provide a further positive outlook for the year to come. We expect a further significant improvement of the EBITDA margin to 72% in 2017. And this is without any additional adjustment related to rent-restricted units I was just referring to.
 On slide 13 the summarized income statement, once again, underlines our sound topline growth and its positive effect on our operating earnings. The net loss we show in the first nine months is solely attributable to one-off items in the net finance cost. Important items were both non-cash variation effects of derivatives of EUR77.9m, which largely relate to the convertible, and one-off refinancing charges of EUR51m.
 Generally, total cost for the refinancing, as we already mentioned, were lower than anticipated and, therefore, the payback period for our shareholders will be even shorter.
 On slide 14 we present how we derive our FFO. This chart again shows that a very high portion of this sound topline growth is feeding through to the bottom line. And, therefore, we saw a significant rise in earnings from EUR124m to EUR158.5m. Once again, we had a margin improvement on several lines of the P&amp;L, on the EBITDA and also on the adjusted NOI level.
 Due to the consolidation of new entities there were temporarily slightly higher admin costs which are in line with our planning. The decrease in cost ratio already reflects the synergies from acquisitions. In 2016 we expect decreasing admin costs, even in absolute numbers, which will contribute to significant margin boost.
 On chart 15 we have prepared an overview of the growth drivers of our FFO. And on slide 17 you will see that our adjusted EPRA NAV, excluding goodwill as of end of September stands at EUR52.87 with an attractive portfolio yield of 7.3%. In accordance with the EPRA definition, NAV per share is calculated on the basis of the fully diluted number of shares, given that our convertible is trading in the money.
 Adjusted for the dividend distribution of EUR1.96 in June, NAV climbed by 4.1% year to date. The NAV's most important driver is, of course, the revaluation of property portfolio which will take place at year end. The valuation process is in final stages, but we clearly expect a first moderate yield compression and a total valuation uplift in the magnitude of 4.4% to 4.7% or some EUR265m to EUR285m.
 The strongest contribution comes from our high-growth markets with valuation movement of more than 7%. In our stable and higher-yielding markets valuation uplift will be more in the region of 2.4% to 2.7%. Typically these markets see strongest momentum in the later stage of the property cycle, signaling further cash-up potentials for our portfolio.
 As you know, LEG's business model is generating additional value from tenant-related services, which are not capitalized on the balance sheet and, therefore, are not reflected in the NAV. At a discount rate of 6% for this very stable business, this implies an additional value of around EUR183m or EUR2.90 per share.
 Coming to slide 19 and 20, LEG's balance sheet remains very strong. We do not fuel our FFO by stretching our balance sheet. Our LTV stands at 40 -- 48.3%. Also, going forward, we aim to maintain an LTV of around 50% or slightly below that level. This helps to maintain a stable credit rating and also an efficient capital structure for an attractive FFO yield
 Finally, slide 20, gives you an overview of our financial structure as of end of September. In July one last tranche of EUR145m of the EUR900m refinancing package has been closed. The average debt maturity amounts to 11 years with average cost of debt of 2.3%. Our marginal costs of debt are, of course, even lower. We observe further tightening of credit margins. With our strong standing in the mortgage-financing market we currently get offers with credit margins of sometimes even less than 70 bps, implying total cost of debt of below 1.7% for a 10-year loan.
 Comparable implied bond margins of real estate companies with similar ratings, which are publicly available, are currently 130 basis points or higher. LEG can, therefore, clearly secure lower cost of capital for shareholders as an important, long-term value driver.
 With that, I would like to hand over to Thomas.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Hegel,  LEG Immobilien AG - CEO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Eckhard. And we now come to our business update, starting with slide 23 and the following slides. LEG's business model is building on sustainable strength which we will capitalize in the future.
 LEG has a regionally focused strategy on the region of North-Rhine Westphalia. We clearly show that our focused strategy bears structural advantages when it comes to operating performance and efficiency. But we are also extremely pleased with our exposure to the North-Rhine Westphalia region.
 We believe that within the attractive German resi market, North-Rhine Westphalia belongs to the market which -- with maybe the strongest cash-up potential. This statement is not based on wishful thinking but on fundamentals. NRW is key beneficiary of the accelerating net immigration to German. North-Rhine Westphalia offers a liquid labor market and an overall excellent urban infrastructure. Also 22% of refugees currently coming to Germany finally arrive in North-Rhine Westphalia. LEG's product of affordable living is perfectly tailored to this new macro trend.
 Many important cities in North-Rhine Westphalia and also in our portfolio have overcome the structural change which sometimes took decades. Permanent examples for this are cities such as Essen or Dortmund. Please have a look on chart 24. These markets are kicking off. And here we are still in an early stage of the property cycle. Rents and also prices are still at a low level, not only in absolute terms but also relative to the purchasing power and relative to other cities in Germany, as chart 25 reveals. In our view, there is clearly relative value in the North-Rhine Westphalia market.
 Coming to our portfolio, the value per square meter is at EUR826. The rental yield stands at 7.3%, while outlook for general growth is still improving. We forecast a like-for-like rent CAGR of 2.8% until 2017. Our portfolio combines low valuation and a very attractive, robust, growth profile.
 In this market we are on an accelerated growth path to exploit further scale effects. Year to date we have agreed on the acquisition of around 20,000 units. And, therefore, we expanded our leading market position in this market. At the same time, we kept our high capital discipline.
 Our acquisitions were not dilutive to NAV, clearly, FFO per share accretive. And they contributed driving efficiency with -- which is reflected in a widening of the EBITDA margin.
 The recently announced transaction, the acquisition of 13,800 units from Vonovia, perfectly fits into our strategy. This portfolio offers a very attractive rental yield, high synergies with our existing portfolio, and additional value upside which we can lift with our leading property management platform.
 The transaction price is roughly in line with our year-end IRFS valuation. The EBITDA margin reaches 72% despite higher investments into this portfolio of around EUR18 per square meter. With some higher investments we see clear upside to reduce vacancies from current 6.3% to below 5%.
 This track record of our acquisitions gives good reasons to be very optimistic that we can achieve our operating target.
 We have outlined the operating performance of our acquisitions on chart 30. In the North-Rhine Westphalia and Vitus portfolio we have increased our rents by 4% and reduced vacancies by 70 basis points, just within one year.
 Also taking into account that we are going to raise some additional equity for the last transaction, this year should be associated with an immediate FFO per share accretion of 3% to 4%.
 We are committed to further growth. We are a natural buyer in North-Rhine Westphalia due to our superior scale effects and our strong market reputation. Currently we are in negotiation for further acquisitions in our core market.
 As already pointed out, we clearly aim to harvest the fruit of regionally focused portfolio such as a superior efficiency. We started an accelerated cost-savings program in the beginning of 2015 to enhance our leading operating profitability. This was a very comprehensive approach covering all processes and functions. We are not shy at all to adjust entire structures if we see upside. As a result of our analysis, we have now identified a sustainable cost-savings potential of around EUR10m, of which EUR5m will become effective in 2016.
 Important, simple, measures are, for instance, the implementation of a centralized service center for standard tenant questions or a higher standardization of turn costs, which should help us to reduce cost and to shorten the lease period.
 Such measures have a certain lead time. We have to prepare a tender process for suppliers, etc. Therefore, we will see full effects in fiscal year 2017. As a result of the higher cost basis, and also due to additional scale effects, we raised our EBITDA margin target 2017 from 71% to 72% and, therefore, we will further strengthen our leading profitability.
 Last but not least, we decided to become somewhat more active in asset-recycling strategy to create additional value for our shareholders. To make this clear, we are not building up new cost structures for tenant privatization, but we are more thinking of the sale of entire apartment blocks which we see attractive -- where we see attractive exit opportunities.
 Another option is to dispose assets after successful transformation from opportunistic or value-add assets to core properties. We are just analyzing our portfolio and we should be able to quantify the potential impact on our numbers by beginning of next year.
 Let us now come to slide 30. As already mentioned, we are very pleased with the performance of our acquired portfolio. Within an average 17 months we have increased in-place rents by 5.1%. And we have also reduced vacancies by 40 basis points.
 Chart 31. On the basis of our updated business plan we -- which includes the recent positive developments, we can provide the following outlook for full-year 2014 (sic - see slide 30 "2015") and the coming year. We reiterate our financial outlook for 2015 with an FFO of EUR200m to EUR204m.
 Due to the positive consolidation effects of the recent Vonovia deal, which will be part of our numbers starting April 2016, we raise our FFO guidance to EUR254m to EUR259m. We can't give you a price/yield guidance for FFO per share right now, but an accretion of 3% to 4% versus the previous guidance of 4% to 4.09% is very likely.
 In 2017 we will see full-year impact of these acquisitions, additional cost savings and with our bottom-up planning we clearly expect an accelerating rent growth of 3% to 3.3% also due to the cost rent adjustment. This should translate into an FFO of EUR279m to EUR284m.
 Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your attention. With that, I'd like to open up the call to questions.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Andre Remke, Baader Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Good morning, sirs. A number of questions, starting probably with the pipeline for acquisitions. Can you give us an update here, especially in terms of what portfolio size is? Are there small sizes or mid-sized portfolios? And does it all relate to North Rhine-Westphalia? This is the first question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think we have provided everything that we deliver, on what we are guiding. And we have the ambition to grow as fast as possible while maintaining strict investment criteria. We have a focus on the total return of our shareholders, that means FFO and NAV growth. Our deals are value-accretive from day one and the execution risk is very, very low.
 When we are talking about our growth target, we started our guidance with 2 -- 5,000 units at the time of the IPO to provide a clear message that we have a dedicated growth strategy and also to give you some support for your modeling. We now see several smaller acquisition opportunities in the pipeline. We are focused on North Rhine-Westphalia, but as you see with Vonovia deal, we have some acquisition opportunities even in other regions, such as Rhineland-Palatinate, as one part of the Vonovia deal is based in Koblenz. So you can take these 5,000 units per year as a guidance and a minimum target, but we still have some smaller opportunities in the pipeline.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And probably -- may I ask can you probably elaborate a bit on the process of the acquisitions of the 14,000 unit portfolio from Vonovia? For how long did you discuss it or did the price change during the process? Are you willing to give us some words on that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, we can do. The acquisition of the 13,800 units from Vonovia fits perfectly into our strategy. And we think that we can provide evidence that we are at the end a better owner of this acquisition. We have negotiated this deal with Vonovia for, I would say, months. Of course this deal has been off the table for a few weeks. But given that we were already in advanced stages, we were able to reach an agreement finally within a short time frame.
 Both parties had an interest in the deal and therefore we had good negotiation power. You also know that Vonovia wanted to de-lever. We successfully negotiated an attractive price and also the right portfolio contribution for LEG. At the end we are very happy with the results and, again, the deal perfectly fits to our strategy.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And may I ask did the price change over the process?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We don't want to comment on the pricing (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay. That's fine. Then a question, you mentioned that you will not enter the privatization business, but probably here and there could be some block sales or entire buildings. Are there -- can you give us any indication of the potential volume or probably also on the markets which could be -- regard to asset recycling? Are these growth market or high-yielding markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Eckhard Schultz,  LEG Immobilien AG - CFO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, this is Eckhard speaking. As you know, we first of all, do a thorough analysis of our portfolio and that's what we're currently doing. We're analyzing our portfolio. And I think we should be able to quantify the potential impact and also the breakdown to the several markets on our numbers by beginning next year. And please understand that we cannot be more precise at the moment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then a very last question. Can you give us your views on the potential effects from the refugee topic for your Company and in particular, for example, how deep are the potential talks with municipalities already? Or is it more a macro topic, as you call it, with positive effects on the demand side in general?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thomas Hegel,  LEG Immobilien AG - CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me try to give you a short answer on a big issue. As you know, we already let more than 500, 550 units to tenants, based on discussions with municipalities. What we can do, as part of this item, we can implement our know how to municipalities and the government of North Rhine-Westphalia. That is what we are doing.
 As I said, the refugee item brings up pressure to our market and to our portfolio. Not saying that we can over all the refugees which are coming to North-Rhine Westphalia, just saying that we are building up a strategy together with the government of North Rhine-Westphalia, together with other big companies in North Rhine-Westphalia.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andre Remke,  Baader Bank - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you very much. That's from my side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Woerdeman, Kempen.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Woerdeman,  Kempen - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. This is Robert, Kempen. Question. If the takeover of Deutsche Wohnen was successful, would the combination then still look at this Vonovia portfolio or in other words was Deutsche Wohnen as positive on this transaction as you are?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think this is more a hypothetical question, because we terminated the business combination agreement. So I think (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's already been said why we took this deal off the table during the negotiation with Deutsche Wohnen.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Woerdeman,  Kempen - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That's clear. And then with respect to like-for-like rental growth you give quite a handsome figure for 2017 as expected 3% to 3.3%. What is the effect of the Vonovia transaction here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the anticipated annual rental growth for the Vonovia portfolio is in the magnitude of 2.2%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Woerdeman,  Kempen - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 2.2%. Okay. Thank you. All right. And then with respect to -- you mentioned more active capital recycling. Is it fair to assume that bits and pieces of the Vonovia portfolio will be repositioned, filled up and then potentially disposed of?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As I said, we are doing currently our analysis but as Thomas said, we're also thinking that we can turn around some assets and to stabilize these assets that we could sell also single assets. But again, I think at the beginning of next year we can be more precise and then we can also be more precise if a part of the Vonovia portfolio will be a part of that. But transfer of ownership will be April 1, so that's not a question in the short term.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Woerdeman,  Kempen - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That was it from my side. Many thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Robert.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are welcome.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Papadakos, Green Street Advisors.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Papadakos,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Good morning, everyone. Could we just walk through a little bit the privatization versus block sale strategy insofar as between the two options that you have, can you help us understand why is the block sale a better strategy to look forward? Is it ultimately the returns may be lower, but the risk is much lower, so on a risk-adjusted basis it's better? Can you give us some numbers of how you think in terms of those contrasting strategies, please?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, so, you know, I think, from the past our view on single tenant privatization, the problem with the single tenant privatization, at least in the majority of our markets, is that you start successfully with the first 25% to 30%, but then usually you end up in the Swiss cheese. So therefore you have -- (multiple speakers) -- you have double the administrative costs plus you have the cost of your own platform and then you have the management costs for the condominium management and you have to build up a cost structure and a sales structure for this privatization business.
 We are thinking -- in terms of capital recycling strategy, we are thinking more on disposing multi-family houses, for example, six-, five- or six-flat houses, because then we can play the market and we can take the advantage of the high prices. And we can realize also value there, without building up this cost structures, without creating a Swiss cheese. So that's our idea and therefore, given the experience we have made with the single tenant privatization, we will not go back to this route.
 But I think we can be a little bit more active on the capital side. That's also feedback we received from our investor talks during the last weeks and months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Papadakos,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Very, very good. Thank you. Then on the VNA acquisition, exactly what is the economic cap rate of that acquisition, i.e. the NRI less the CapEx reserve? I'm looking for a yield, CapEx-adjusted economic yield.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can I come back later on this question, please, Peter. I don't --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Papadakos,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay. No problem. And then just my final -- thank you so much for this thoughtful slide that -- you talked on slide 24 about potentially entering an upswing phase. But my question is, if we were having this call back in 1987, 1988, we could potentially be saying the same thing and in the end that didn't realize. So can you help us understand what are the structural drivers that you believe are resulting in a change in direction for cities like Essen or Krefeld or Bielefeld today?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, first of all, if you look at the structure of the labor market in North Rhine-Westphalia, you know that 30 of the 50 largest companies are based in North Rhine-Westphalia. And if you look at the development of the unemployment rate, unemployment decreased since 2005 by 35% to a very low level of 7.8% in 2014.
 So we -- the North Rhine-Westphalia underwent a structural change and now we have fundamentally a very positive situation. First of all, we have a still increasing number of one- to two-person households. You know that since 2012 we have a significant net immigration. For the first time in the German history a net immigration since 2012. And I'm not talking about the very recent development of refugees.
 On top of that comes the development Thomas has talked about. 1m refugees are expected to come to Germany. Finally, we do not know how many people, how many refugees will live here, but you can assume that all the forecasts which calculate with 100,000 additional people coming to Germany are not valid anymore. And this will have also a significant impact on -- a significant positive impact of the population. And therefore, we are very, very confident that this upswing trend will last for a longer time.
 And this is also reflected -- and that's a very important for us, that's also reflected in increasing rents and a significantly decreasing vacancy. Dortmund, for example, if you look today, has a vacancy rate of 3%. We have rental growth of well above 2%, 2.5%. So a complete upswing in this market and there is no reason why this -- we do not see any reasons for the time being that this will change.
 Maybe to your first question, so we calculate in this acquisition a 72% EBITDA yield, even taking into account the EUR18 CapEx maintenance. And the economic cap rate is around 5%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Papadakos,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're welcome.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen, Victoria Partners.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Good morning. Three questions. One would be on the expected revaluation towards the year end, the second one on the FFO guidance and the third one on rent tables. I may ask them one by one. You indicated the roughly 4.4% to 4.7% revaluation. I appreciate it's a bit early, but could you give us some rough guidance of how much of that should come from exceeding the like-for-like rent growth expectations, second component vacancy and what is left for yield compression? Just as rough components.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The yield compression, we calculate the yield compression with a magnitude of 30 basis points. So currently, it's between 7.2%, 7.3% and we expect gross rental yields slightly below 7%. And therefore, the yield compression component is 30 basis points.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So if I make a rough calculation, that's about 3% or so. So something like two-thirds would be coming from yield compression and a third or so would be coming exceeding like-for-like rental growth and vacancy. Is that about right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Too fast for me now. I will come back on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Sorry. On the -- on future market rent expectations, would you have -- and again, it's probably a bit early, but would you have any idea to what extent CBRE would be also become more optimistic on the longer-term market rent in their valuation assumptions?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I cannot speak for CBRE, frankly speaking. So -- but we are in discussions and CBRE clearly sees the positive development and also these numbers we are talking about, with the expected variation, you can assume that we have this discussed with CBRE upfront. So they do also see an accelerating trend in the market trends generally.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. I will wait for the year end. Second question on your FFO guidance. I appreciate that you can only give us at this stage an absolute figure for 2016. Is it correct to assume that you would go for typical, something like 50% LTV? So of the acquisition price you would calculate something like, whatever, EUR600m plus divided by 2 for capital increase?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, I think we have, when we announced the transaction last Monday, we also gave a soft announcement that we want to finance this acquisition at an LTV of 50%. And if you apply such a financing structure, this acquisition will be FFO accretive by 3% to 4%. So on top of the EUR4 to EUR4.09, you can assume that the FFO per share in 2016 will be 3% or 4% higher on a per-share basis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Could you give us -- could you confirm that this will be an asset deal rather than share deal. If I try to come to the total acquisitions cost meaning including ancillary purchase cost.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I can confirm that this deal is an asset deal. It's a real estate transfer (background noise).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it would be right to add, whatever, something like 8% or so in total, so getting towards like EUR650m or so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. So 6.5% real estate transfer tax and (multiple speakers) --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 -- 5% I think. That's not too far from reality, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Then final question on your rent increase, particularly coming from rent tables. Are there any limitations already, given the increases that you have undertaken in the last few years on this 15% increase over two years, meaning if we have -- if we calculate our increase on quotes sitting tenants, can we assume that the increase in rent tables applies still for the vast majority of your flats or have reached already this 15% and therefore are limited in your future increases for a meaningful number of your flats?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Holger Hentschel,  LEG Immobilien AG - COO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. Hello. It's Holger speaking. No, we see no limitation on this. We see that the rent tables will increase in the future. The markets are improving. And so our new rent tables partially reflect it's a positive momentum. At the end it's clear that rent table development is a little bit of a black box, because we have not a whole standard in Germany. But we see that also in this year the increases of the rent tables are very good, for example, in Dortmund with 3% and Cologne with 4% and so on. So that we see every year that there's a really good development of this Mietspiegel. And so we have every year enough space to increase our rent and we are not -- insofar that we are not limited on this 15% limit you said.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On average maybe -- you know that on average we, in a re-letting situation we increase the rent by 6%, so far below the 15% threshold. And we also gave a guidance for like-for-like rental growth for 2015, making it between 2.5%, 2.6%. For 2016 the rental growth will be in the same magnitude. This takes into consideration -- you know that we are planning our rent unit by unit, taking into consideration all relevant restrictions, such as rent caps, such as a 15% threshold. So all the legal restrictions are penciled in in our business model. So you can assume that the rental growth will be -- will grow in the magnitude in 2016. And 2017 we will see this hike to 3% to 3.3%, mainly due to the adjustment of rent-restricted units.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Janssen,  Victoria Partners - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That's very helpful. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). If there are no further questions, I would like to hand the floor back over to Mr. Sawazki.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Burkhard Sawazki,  LEG Immobilien AG - Head of IR   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There appears to be one further question, operator, if I see it correctly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, there are no further questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Burkhard Sawazki,  LEG Immobilien AG - Head of IR   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mr. [Sandabak], BMO Global Asset.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi. Thank you. Very last minute, but thank you. Just two quick questions, please. Can you help me understand why there's roughly a five-month time difference between announcing and closing the deal with Vonovia regarding this transaction?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 How do you derive the five-months delay?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, so you announced the transaction last week or two weeks ago (multiple speakers) --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 -- towards the end of the first -- yes, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. We announced an asset deal and we announced that we have an agreement with Vonovia and this agreement will be shaped out into a contract and that will be within the next weeks. And then the transfer of ownership will be at the beginning of the next year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sorry. At the beginning of the next year? I thought it was going to be towards the end of Q1.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At the latest end of Q1.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay. It seems quite a long time, but is that normal industry practice.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. It's a big portfolio and it is industry practice, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. All right. And the other question I had was relating to your dividend guidance. With your -- with this transaction announced and with further improvements in your EBITDA margin, is there room to increase your dividend payout ratio?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, as you know, our dividend policy, 65% payout ratio of our FFO I, which translates in more or less 95% to 100% of our AFFO. We believe that it's a healthy dividend policy not to pay more dividend than our AFFO. And therefore, I think this should be seen as a guideline. If we generate an AFFO which is significantly higher than the envisaged dividend payout, I think we can certainly think about adjustment. But as long as this ratio is approximately close to the AFFO, I think there's no reason to deviate from the 65%. By the way, given the earnings guidance for 2016, our stock currently trades at an attractive dividend yield at 3.6%, which is I think in the -- also a leading number. It's 3.9% actually, where the stock is trading today.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So stick to 65% payout.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For the time being, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Perfect. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're welcome.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If there are now no further questions from the audience, I hand back over to Mr. Sawazki.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Burkhard Sawazki,  LEG Immobilien AG - Head of IR   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. As you know, the IR team and I are available also after the call to answer your questions. So please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. Thank you and good bye.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The conference is no longer being recorded.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q3 2015 LEG Immobilien AG Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Duesseldorf</city>
  <companyName>LEG Immobilien AG</companyName>
  <companyTicker>LEG.DE</companyTicker>
  <startDate>12-Nov-15 9:00am GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>257132</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>B9G6L89</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>DE000LEG1110</ISIN>
</Event>