<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="3191137" lastUpdate="Thursday, July 22, 2010 at 1:10:25pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="3191137.F" expirationDate="Wednesday, July 21, 2010 at 1:30:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of LUV earnings conference call or presentation 21-Jul-10 1:30pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2010 AirTran Holdings, Inc. Earnings Conference Call

Dallas Jul 22, 2010 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Southwest Airlines Co earnings conference call or presentation Wednesday, July 21, 2010 at 1:30:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jason Bewley
      AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Director of Corp. Finance
   *  Bob Fornaro
      AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO
   *  Arne Haak
      AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO
   *  Kevin Healy
      AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Duane Pfenningwerth
      Raymond James - Analyst
   *  Bill Greene
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Glenn Ingalls
      Bank of America - Analyst
   *  Gary Chase
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Michael Linenberg
      Deutsche Bank Securities - Analyst
   *  Daniel Mackenzie
      Hudson Securities - Analyst
   *  Kevin Chrissy
      UBS Investment Bank - Analyst
   *  Steve O'Hara
      Sidoti &amp; Co. - Analyst
   *  Helane Becker
      Dahlman Rose - Analyst
   *  Michael Derchin
      CRT Capital - Analyst
   *  James Higgins
      Silio Securities - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day, ladies and gentlemen. And welcome to your AirTran Airways second quarter earnings conference call. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session, and instructions will be given at that time. (Operator Instructions). And as a reminder, this program is being recorded.
  I would now like to introduce Mr. Jason Bewley, Director of Corporation Finance. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jason Bewley,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Director of Corp. Finance   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, everyone. I would like to thank you for joining us for a discussion of our second quarter 2010 results. Joining me today are Bob Fornaro, our Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer, Arne Haak, our Chief Financial Officer, and Kevin Healy, our Senior Vice President of Marketing and Planning.
  I would like to remind you that this call will contain forward-looking statements. These comments are not historical facts and should be considered in this time-sensitive forward-looking statements that are accurate only as of July 21, 2010. If you would like additional information concerning factors that could cause our actual results to vary from those in the forward-looking statements, they can be found in our annual report Form 10-K, Forms 10-Q and other SEC filings on the Company.
  We will also be discussing several non-GAAP financial measures that we believe are helpful in gaining an understanding of our operating performance and providing a period-to-period comparison excluding special items. A copy of today's press release, recent SEC filings and a reconciliation of these non-GAAP financial measures are available in the Investor Relation section of the Company's website at airtran.com.
  Today we'll be discussing our second quarter results and our outlook for the remainder of 2010. At the end of the call there will be a brief question-and-answer session.
  Now I would like to turn the call over to Bob.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. After a challenging first quarter, AirTran has delivered a solid performance here in the second quarter. From an operations perspective, the results were the best we have ever delivered in the second quarter. Our on-time performance was 83.8%, our completion factor was 99.5%, and our industry leading baggage handling performance improved 4%, to 1.5 mishandled bags per 1,000 passengers. I want to personally thank all of our 8,000 crew members for this accomplishment. This is truly a team effort.
  During the second quarter, we reported a GAAP profit of $12.4 million, which includes an unrealized loss of $26.4 million net of taxes on the reduction in value of our future hedge portfolio. Excluding this item, we reported an economic net income of $38.8 million, or $0.23 a share compared to last year's economic net income of $46.6 million. During the quarter, our capacity grew 4.9% year-over-year, and we produced record second quarter revenues of $700.6 million which represents a 16.1% increase.
  We achieved a record load factor of 83.1%, which was up two points year-over-year. Our business class load factor rose more than five points to over 83%, which also represents a new Company record. Typically an increase in capacity load factors will exchange when it comes at the expense of yield. However, our second quarter passenger yield increased 9.4%, the highest year-over-year yield growth in four years, despite a 3% year-over-year increase in average stage. Our other revenues are roughly flat year-over-year, and Arne will give you a little more color on that during his remarks. Putting it all together, our total unit revenues increased 10.7% year-over-year.
  On a net worth front, we continue to make a lot of progress on growing and diversifying our revenues. During the past year, we have opened 12 new destinations from Orlando, mostly to small and mid-sized cities as well as in the Caribbean. The most significant progress in developing our network has been made in Milwaukee. While we have added only one main line destination year-over-year, we have grown our capacity here more significantly than any other city on our network.
  After a tough winter, Milwaukee has been solidly profitable for us in the second quarter despite significantly higher fuel costs. In fact, our unit revenue growth in Milwaukee far outpaces our system average, and during the second quarter was the best performing region in our network in terms of year-over-year unit revenue growth. While absolute profitability still trails our system average, its trends here are very good, as we continue to improve, as our own capacity growth begins to moderate and our newer roots continue to mature. All sides point to Milwaukee as having a very bright future on our network.
  Finally, just this week, the Atlanta City council voted unanimously to renew our lease at Hartsfield-Jackson International Airport for the next seven years, solidifying our position at the worlds busiest airport.
  On the cost side, we beat our nonfuel cost expectations in the second quarter. Our adjusted nonfuel costs were up 2.5% year-over-year, well ahead of our initial second quarter nonfuel guidance of 4% to 4.5%, and even better than our revised guidance of six weeks ago of up 3.5% to 4%. Fuel costs rose by over $68 million, a 43% increase.
  Since we last spoke to you in April, we revised the terms of our future aircraft deliveries, we intentionally retired over $90 million in convertible debt and extended our $100 million secured credit facility for up to two years. All in all, the entire team at AirTran should be pleased with the progress we are making. As Arne will elaborate, the year-over-year unit revenue outlook for the next several months looks even better than what we experienced in the second quarter. Our own capacity growth is slowing down, the percentage of capacity in new routes is declining, and our outlook for the second half of the year reflects substantial year-over-year earnings growth.
  I would like now to turn the call over to Arne to give you more detail on our financial performance and outlook.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Bob, and good morning, everyone. As Bob just mentioned, we reported a net income of $12.4 million in the second quarter. Included in these results is a $26.4 million loss net of taxes due to the reduction in value of our future fuel hedge portfolio. Excluding this item, our economic net profit was $38.8 million or $0.23 per share, versus an economic net income of $46.6 million or $0.34 per share in 2009.
  Excluding the change in value of our future fuel hedge portfolio, our pre-tax income was relatively flat year-over-year. For clarification purposes, our fuel hedge portfolio is a net asset of $16.1 million. Our fuel hedge portfolio is simply not as valuable as it was 90 days ago, largely because of the drop in prices in crude oil during this time period, which is a very positive trend for our Company. For a complete reconciliation of these items, please direct your attention to the reconciliation table at the end of today's earnings press release.
  Our capacity for the second quarter grew by 4.9%, primarily due to two additional aircraft which were delivered in the third quarter of 2009. Our traffic as measured by revenue passenger miles increased 7.9%, resulting in a record second quarter load factor of 83.1%. Second quarter revenues were $700.6 million, up 16.1% year-over-year and for the third quarter in a row, the highest quarterly revenues in Company history, despite having five fewer aircraft today than we did in 2008.
  Our passenger unit revenues increased 12.6% year-over-year to $0.1013 cents as a result of the 9.4% year-over-year increase in yields and the 3% increase in stage lengths on 4.9% more ASM. As was the trend in the first quarter, our pace of revenue improvement accelerated in the second quarter. Our April PRASM was up about 6% year-over-year. May was up around 12.5% year-over-year. And June was up around 19.5% year-over-year.
  Our PRASM performance did disappoint versus the outlook we shared in April, largely due to a miss versus our expectations in the month of May. In hindsight, I think we were perhaps too optimistic in our outlook for what is historically a shoulder travel period. But as we have just outlined for you, the year-over-year trend is still quite positive, and we expect this trend to continue through the third quarter.
  Our other revenues were largely flat year-over-year. So on a unit basis, our total unit revenue did not grow as quickly as our passenger unit revenue. There are a lot of components in this revenue catagory, and the trends were not consistent during the quarter. However, the majority of the shortfall is in the area of bag fee revenues, predominantly in second bags and oversize baggage revenues where we are seeing behavioral changes from our customers. On the cost side, our adjusted total operating unit costs were up 12.7% year-over-year in the second quarter, and our adjusted nonfuel unit costs were $0.0645, up 2.5% year-over-year.
  Our unit maintenance costs came in better than our expectations, while our unit distribution costs and landing fees and other rents grew at above average rates on a year-over-year basis. The change in distribution costs is being driven by higher average fares and a slightly higher percentage of customers using online travel agencies. Our airport costs rose as well, as we were presented notices from several airports reflecting higher than originally budgeted snow removal costs. Our economic fuel costs for the quarter was $2.37 per gallon all in, which includes the effects of fuel hedging.
  In regards to our financial position, we ended the quarter with $535 million in unrestricted cash and equivalents, and our revolving line of credit was undrawn. During the quarter, we revised the terms of our aircraft agreement with Boeing. As a result, we have reduced our aircraft deliveries by about 20% for 2011 and 2012. We will now add six aircraft in 2011. Two will be [leep] 717s and the remaining four will be 737-700s. In 2012 we'll add six aircraft, all 737-700s. This will reduce our growth rate to approximately 3% to 4% for this time period. More importantly, our aircraft purchase obligations have been reduced by over $200 million over the next few years.
  In July, holders of our 7% convertible notes due in 2023 had the option to put the notes back to the Company. Just over $90 million of the notes were put back to the Company and were redeemed by the Company in cash.
  Finally, we revised our secured credit agreement to extend the term through 2012. While the size of the facility is smaller reflects our improved financial position and our desire to lower our borrowing costs. To date in 2010 we have not used our revolver, and we are seeking to reduce the commitment fees we pay to the lender. As a result of these balance sheet accomplishments and our profitability, we are one of the few airlines to receive increases on our credit ratings from both Moody's and most recently S&amp;P. Our nonaircraft CapEx was $3.8 million for the second quarter and $5.7 million for the year-to-date.
  I would now like to spend a few minutes updating our outlook for the third quarter and the remainder of 2010. Our fleet plan for the balance of 2010 is expected to remain at 138 aircraft. Third quarter capacity is projected to be up approximately 1%, fourth quarter capacity is projected to be up approximately 1% to 2%. We expect to take delivery from Boeing Capital two leased 717s in February next year. We'll take delivery of four 737-700s from Boeing in 2011, with the first delivery scheduled for March of 2011.
  Our advanced bookings, and more importantly yield trends through the summer continue to remain exceptionally strong. July passenger unit revenues are currently trending up 17% to 18% year-over-year. Our August unit revenue outlook for passenger unit revenue growth which were up 14% to 15% year-over-year. While the outlook for September is always difficult to forecast based on these trends and the strong base of advanced booking for September, we are currently expecting our third quarter passenger unit revenues to increase between 14.5% and 16.5%. And our total unit revenues to increase between 12.5% and 14.5%. We expect our third quarter nonfuel unit costs will increase by 4% to 5%, and that our full year nonfuel unit costs guidance will remain unchanged at up 4% to 5%.
  In regards to fuel, we continue to add to our fuel hedge portfolio during the second quarter. As of today we have fuel contracts for approximately 69% of our anticipated jet fuel volume for the third quarter of 2010, 58% of our fourth quarter fuel volumes, and 45% of our 2011 fuel volumes. Based on an average spot price of $75 for crude oil and $10 for jet fuel refinery spreads in the third quarter, we currently expect our economic fuel costs per gallon to be between $2.29 and $2.34 all in, inclusive of taxes, transportation, fuel hedging and the plane fees.
  In closing, we are pleased with our second quarter results and diversification efforts. As you can tell, we feel very positive about our outlook for the second half of the year, and we currently expect our year-over-year earnings to accelerate in the back half of this year.
  With that I would now like to turn the call over for questions.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions).
  Our first question comes from Duane Pfenningwerth from Raymond James.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Duane Pfenningwerth,  Raymond James - Analyst   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, good morning. Just with respect to May, can you talk about what was actually the variance? Was it in the month revenue? And did you change something about the way that you revenue manage going forward?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, Duane, good morning. I think it was really end of month revenues. We had a very strong advance booking base, and we didn't see as much follow through as we expected. And again, I think a contrast after June, where we had very strong advance bookings and we had - - strong follow through. So, again, I never know whether it is an anomaly or not but, again, it kind of stuck out. Given the advanced booking dates we expected it to be better. And as we're sitting with July, July is pretty much closed. Again, we had fairly strong within the month bookings. So I'm not sure whether, again, May wasn't a trend is more of an anomaly for us.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Duane Pfenningwerth,  Raymond James - Analyst   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Fair enough. And with respect to guidance, how do you think about September, given what you learned about May? In other words, how do you consider - - a shoulder month with less visibility that is the last month of the quarter, this month relative to the guidance that you have put forth?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Duane, it is Kevin. Just - - when you look at May, it was a bit of a transition month. Because you came in the year with advances much lower than the prior year, where - - in 2009 we put a lot on the books really early. In 2010, we held out for a higher yield, and we are seeing that. May was a bit of a turnover and you have to look at it a little bit differently. September is the sort of thing you never want to, you never characterize it as feeling good about September.
  But basically, you are going into September with good average fares, good advance bookings - - you can always do a little bit better there. But I feel pretty good about what we have got on the books now. And particularly the way the capacity allocations are out there, in terms of the network changes that we put in place over the last year or so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 One thing I would add again. I think - - September is normally, the waiting isn't as much. It is about 25% to 26% of our revenues. So it's not as meaningful. I think we are also beginning to see - - a little capacity [moderization] as we get out there. The supply and demand is getting better and there's also fewer new routes. Last year going into the Spirit job we added a lot of new routes. Again, that number has been down substantially as we move into - - the last quarter of the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Duane Pfenningwerth,  Raymond James - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Bill Greene from Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Greene,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, good morning. - - I want to talk a little bit about some of the ancillary trends. The ancillary numbers are actually down year-over-year. You mentioned the bag fees and some behavioral changes. I'm wondering if you think that perhaps we are further along in this ancillary process? United, on their call yesterday, suggested we are kind of in the third inning there. But your trends would suggest that it's a bit more mature. So maybe there is a difference between the legacy opportunity and the low cost opportunity. In light of Southwest's efforts, I'm just curious how you think about that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just as far as (inaudible) we're not going to say talk about any pricing or fee levels, but we can talk about the trends.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill, I think you see behavior trends or changes in all of these things you have really from the beginning in terms of how people approach travel and other things like that in terms of the number of bags carried, versus checked. Really has really from the beginning, changed. - - I think with ours it is a little bit different in when you look at the makeup of the network a little bit differently.
  The bigger issue really on the ancillary story is the underlying fares have come up quite a bit in year-over-year growth. I think that puts it a little out of kilter where last year, you were discounting heavily to get people on the plane and producing ancillary revenue. Now you are getting a much, much higher yield and still filling planes. We are looking at - - other ways, again, as Bob noted, we are not going to go into any specific programs or anything like that. But I don't think we've hit the point where there is no more ancillary growth going forward, I think our focus now is on some of the bundling that we are doing, and also optimizing when and how we make offers. I think that, that, as much as anything, can draw a better take rate.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill, this is Arne. Let me add just one thing to this. - - first of all we kind of highlighted in the prepared remarks the trends weren't really consistent. May was, again, was the weakest in terms of the ancillary. We had a very nice bounce back in June. So it is - -, evolving. And the thing that I would say we can't lose sight of is that there really are cost benefits here to the Company as - -, we price accordingly to what customers want.
  A great example is, as Kevin talked about this change in behavior, on checking bags, for example, while it has come down, its sole significant revenue stream, but we are carrying fewer bags today. We also are staffing our ramp in Atlanta with fewer employees. It does reduce our cost space. And if you look, a great metric to kind of highlight this if you look at the number of employees per aircraft, it has come down again. And so part of that is being able to run more efficiently. So there certainly are benefits on the cost side for us as well for us as we run a more streamlined operation.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Greene,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Trying to compare again though to United. So United said they think they're serving the third inning of what they should be able to do on this ancillary stuff. Do you agree with that description of where we are? Or do you think you are further along?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't think it is late in the game Bill, it is hard for us to comment on where United is. They are an international airline versus domestic airline. I still think there is a lot of stuff out there for us to consider.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Greene,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. One quick question for Bob. If you look at the merger approval process that's underway with Continental and United and you were trying to be a little bit involved in the slot swap transaction. Can we assume that maybe there's an opportunity there if there were carve outs or divestitures that you would be able to take advantage of, or do you think that is probably not relevant for you?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There is always again some relevance. And I think - - certainly - - with Delta Northwest was going through in 2008 - - quite frankly, we were too weak to take advantage of any opportunities as we were reassessing our situation. But right not I think certainly we've got a lot of focus on New York, La Guardia in particular, and even a few slots are positive. And I think when you look at the Midwest, again there, I think there is some opportunity. The biggest change in capacity we see with Delta Northwest has been in the Ohio Valley, and I think there is some redundancy there as well. We happen to do exceptionally well in Ohio. So I think there is chances for us. I think there will be some benefits for us. And especially in some of these midsized markets that may lose some service. I think - - again this time around, we will be better positioned as a Company to improve our position - - assuming that merger goes through.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bill Greene,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for the time.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Glenn Ingalls from Bank of America.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, Glenn.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collections on business mix? You have seen a lot of other airlines talk about better business mix in the second quarter. Can you quantify that at all? Can you talk about your business mix in Milwaukee versus the rest of the system?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn, it's Kevin. Business mix is the sort of thing that is improving, and particularly in Milwaukee. When you look at the unit revenue trends that Bob has mentioned in the performance up there, what you are seeing is a significant penetration into the corporate market. Which would be expected, as we are maturing the network up there, we initially grew it largely in leisure markets and over the last 12 months have put the focus on the business market. So that is certainly improving. DWI is another where you are seeing a good one. And as you look forward, even Orlando is a market where you are seeing improving business trends, particularly with regard to meeting and convention travel. And that becomes a bigger part as we move into the fall where there is a significant improvement in meeting attendance at these.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 To go back and again to highlight - - Milwaukee, again our biggest improvement certainly getting more business travelers to the West Coast. But our biggest improvement is from Milwaukee to the business markets on the East Coast. Milwaukee in the second quarter - - we had a passenger unit revenue improvement in excess of 20%. So it is well above the system. And for June alone, it was probably, I believe it was 30%. So Milwaukee is exceptionally strong and - - again, Atlanta is probably coming back faster than the system average as well. Those are the markets that are predominantly where we carry our business travelers. Whereas, as you know, we still carry a lot of Florida passengers. Those are a little below the system average. The business markets right now are leading us as we move into the third quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And is the Milwaukee gain load factor, yield, or both?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's both, but primarily yield.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And loads really don't have that much room to move up in most of the markets. So it is largely on yield. And a change in local versus connections as well. So generally, every indicator in Milwaukee is positive.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And in general you have been trying to move toward a greater mix of O&amp;D versus connect. Can you quantify that at all in the quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm sorry? I didn't catch the last.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You have been trying to get more O&amp;D rather than connect traffic? I thought you had been changing the system around?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. I think that is a big piece of what is driving the overall improved performance. Especially true in Milwaukee. Where as we improve in Boston and DC and La Guardia in particular, those are the sort of things we are carrying far more local and fewer connections. The same is true in Atlanta. We are seeing the local percentage in Atlanta per departure, improve quite a bit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And what is your connect mix this year versus last year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't have that on the top of my head for this.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Here again, to go back and talk about mix. Again, mix is determined by two things. Again, the market it's going to go after but also your root structure. We still have probably about 40% of our customers are going to go in and out of Florida. So that is more leisure oriented. The pure business mix is probably about 30%, 35% - - round numbers, given the fact it is very Florida-oriented. And, obviously, the revenue is a higher percentage of that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn, this is Arne. The comment I would say, we are seeing an improvement. I don't think we are going to give you the exact number. (Inaudible) they are improving. If you look at the places where we have been growing and growing our network, those are areas that tend to have much higher locals, whether it is in Milwaukee, whether it's Baltimore, whether it's some of the point-to-point buying we are doing out of Florida. They all tend to outperform our historic system averages on local markets. So we are less relying upon the highly competitive connecting yields.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Glenn Ingalls,  Bank of America - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Gary Chase from Barclays Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, everybody.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, Gary.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Wanted to see if I can ask two questions just related to revenue. If you take a look at the guidance that you are providing, and appreciate the month-by-month color you are giving there, it does reflect some strengthening year-on-year numbers in the face of comps at least in an industry level that we think are getting harder. Wondered if you could maybe just put a little bit more color around what you think is driving that for you? Do you think it is kind of broad industry strength? Or do you think there is something specific maybe - - Milwaukee's fooling to an even greater extent? Is there an air AirTran specific story you think that's driving kind of the opposite of what we would expect to see around the rest of the industry?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 - - it is kind of hard to follow. Because - - it typically follows the industry norm. I mean, quite frankly, most carriers are reporting their first profit since 2008. And - - we have all been turning to profitability six quarters ago. So at least we have a tendency to be different, and again, last year, the leisure base to Florida helped us. I think what's going on now, we have seen, again I would say the leisure markets returned quickly last year and I think we had a faster rebound. We added a tremendous amount of capacity into Milwaukee last year. I think Milwaukee is still probably up about 25% to 30%.
  Now, the yields have really began to stretch. We have been in there two years or three in some of these markets and they are really - - we have really developed a very, very strong following. And quite frankly, our competitor has gotten weaker and we have gotten stronger. That is a real positive. - - Atlanta is improving for us. That is, again, that historically has been our strongest business market. It's starting to inch up and starting to move ahead of the system. It is important, because still 45% of our capacity.
  So I think those components and I think, - - the percentage of new roots, even post 2008, not only did we reduce capacity, we changed a lot. And so I think as we move into the last few months of the year, instead of having 12% to 14% above capacity in new routes, it is down to 4 or 5, which is a big difference when you begin to see the numbers. So I think that is a little bit unique as well. And - - some moderation in competitive capacity versus prior quarters. So there is a number of factors, again, Atlanta's starting to come back a little bit, and the biggest improvements are in Milwaukee, which is about 14% to 15% of our capacity right now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And you do see that as you look into these months like July and August. You see the increased contribution from Milwaukee and Atlanta versus where you have been?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, absolutely.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is slower in Florida because rebounded very, very quickly. Quite frankly, - - actually, we are optimistic about Florida, that is the place where we actually improved. But Florida really rebounded last year. We did not see the drop off that most airlines did, because we had full capacity in Florida and when everybody left, that helped us last year. So the business markets now that are improving, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then I wondered if I could just follow-up on this nonticket revenue question. - - just based on a lot of different commentary that you have made during the call. I'm trying to get a sense, I mean you said you think there are opportunities to optimize that a little further, you don't think we are in the late inning. But then of course you look at what you are expecting at least in the coming quarter doesn't appear to be much different than what you just generated in this quarter.
  So I guess the question is, is this something that you consider to be urgent where - - we should be expecting you to take action, on it soon? Or do you think as Kevin was alluding to maybe it's just a natural consequence of a higher overall ticket price and people may be behaving a little bit more carefully as they approach it, and it is therefore not something that you are terribly worried about or think you need to take immediate action on?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think it is not something we are terribly worried about at all. I think part of it is a reflection in the changing types of passengers that we are carrying. Maybe a little bit of behavior change. Business travelers obviously are going to it's a different set of ancillary revenues that will come from a business traveler rather than a leisure traveler and other things like that.
  So we talk about optimizing the offers and getting better at who and when and what you offer, at that sort of thing. I think there is upshot to it. It's a little more technology intensive and it's the sort of thing that we will be, we are working on and will be rolling out. But I really believe that the differences right now is just a fundamental improvement in the underlying yields, which is in part driven by the type and shift in the type of passengers that we are carrying. So - - (Inaudible - two speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Chase,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 All right. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Michael Linenberg from Deutsche Bank. Hi, good morning, everyone.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, Bob.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Linenberg,  Deutsche Bank Securities - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Two questions, - - Bob, you have mentioned this a couple of times you have said you that have seen some of your competitors capacity moderate some. I think Frontier, for example, I think they are pulling out of the Atlanta-Milwaukee market. What are other things that maybe that you are seeing that - - and I realize then maybe there are just a few anecdotes here. But - - this is the type of stuff that gives us confidence that the industry will continue to follow this path of being somewhat disciplined with respect to capacity issues? Any additional color would be great.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 - - I think referring to Milwaukee again for us we knew the market. We added a whole host of new routes. We've got 15, 20 new routes that haven't been in about two to three years now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Linenberg,  Deutsche Bank Securities - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And again, each year, its varied. We went in, we went in for the summer only. This year for example, you can go into the first winter or two in some of these long haul West Coast markets or even business markets, they are particularly tough. But what's happened is - - the frequent flyer base in the Midwest has eroded, and ours has gotten stronger. And so I think we are going to see fewer frequencies by Midwest to the East Coast markets, which are very important. Again, I think things like Milwaukee, they will be [elements] as well. The positive there is there's been some moderation. And I think we are again - - better positioned. Again, I think to improve Milwaukee.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Linenberg,  Deutsche Bank Securities - Analyst   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My second question - - you gave us kind of an early read on what July and August trends were looking and of course that is without a lot of the close in stuff, but kind of an early read. And you sort of - - you've provided the guidance for unit revenue for the full September quarter, which would suggest that September's probably going to be - - maybe similar to August, up a pretty healthy amount. Again, it is a bit out there.
  I'm intrigued, I think it was either you or Arne who just talked about a very strong base of September bookings. Have you seen an elongation of the booking curve. I mean, because of the higher fares, are people booking further in advance which are allowing you to put more people onto the books at higher fares. I mean, what's going on there? Has there been an evolution over the last 12 months? And I realize this is all in the context of the fact that you are probably just seeing a better mix because you now fly to more business markets, particularly in and out of Milwaukee.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will start out. Generally, I'd turn it over to Kevin. But the fact is we are - - 2009 was - - may have been the biggest anomaly, we're still worrying. But 2009 was a period of time where we kind of had the weakest advance bookings, and I think there was a lot of late this game. I think we are generally seeing a trend towards an elongation of the booking curve. I want you to just take it further Kevin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As I had mentioned earlier, coming in to the year, it has been a tough year to gauge what is going on with advances, because you came in with a much lower base than the previous year. But that was expected, and it was designed to drive up average fares and we closed pretty well throughout the first part of the year. As you get into the fall you have got a different look on things where we were last year. You were trying to drive volume and the average fares kept falling and falling, even relative to 2008.
  We're now seeing stronger advance bookings and good, average fares. So it is the sort of thing now, where you can get a good base on, we're getting a better mix of day of week-type flying and putting more seats where you need them, less seats where you don't, and getting better at sort of targeting demand with pricing offers. So - - it feels very good about the sale levels that we have out today are higher than they have been in the past, and you are still getting real strong volume.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Linenberg,  Deutsche Bank Securities - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good. Very good. And thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Daniel Mackenzie from Hudson Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Mackenzie,  Hudson Securities - Analyst   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, guys, thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Mackenzie,  Hudson Securities - Analyst   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got a couple of questions. To just sort of peel back the onion on a couple of things that have already been raised. The first question is kind of a two parter. Glancing at the schedule data in comparing Milwaukee to Orlando and Atlanta. I'm counting 58 destinations out of Atlanta, 46 out of Orlando which compares to 25 out of Milwaukee. What appears to be missing at Milwaukee are some of the smaller markets that have historically been AirTran's niche. Given rising labor costs, I wonder if you could talk about opportunities to fill up Milwaukee further. And then related to that, AirTran's had a mixed history using RJ's. But could you talk a little bit about that mixed history, or how that mixed history may or may not apply to Milwaukee, looking ahead?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think as we mentioned Atlanta, Orlando, Milwaukee, they are really, I mean, they are all different. - - Atlanta we have size, we have 250 departures a day. You can fly to some small cities because you can supplement the local markets with connections. But Orlando, I think between our number of cities and carriers like Allegiant. They'll all will be seeing markets like El Paso, Orlando and Las Vegas, most small cities or small markets can't support service yield because of the large volumes. Milwaukee is completely different. It is, we don't have the volumes and frequently turns of leisure roots.
  Certainly in Florida but you kind of have to be cautious and you have a building kind of hub takes a very long time. But you do not have quite the size or the scale that you have in Atlanta. - - the 717, is a pretty good airplane for small markets. I think we just entered Dallas, we are looking at a few others where 717s good. In terms of the RJ, we have a small RJ operation in partnership with Sky West. And there might be some small opportunities for additional RJs up there. But our primary focus is again trying to focus on you know, 717, 737s. Look at really what we are doing, it is - - we, it is really kind of established ourselves - - all the airlines with business class on every flight, that is helping us tremendously up there.
  Even so some of these commuter airplanes are pretty good. Generally speaking, of the cabin difference, is substantial, compared to most RJs. So I guess, I think for us, we will be focused on main volume airplanes. And we are also seeing, again, we're seeing heavy flows of traffic coming from northern Illinois. We have Milwaukee's kind of playing out just like we thought. For us we were sorry to win the local market and we'll bring it in from southeast Wisconsin and northern Illinois. Kind of a textbook example of what you would like to see in an area that has historically been overpriced.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The other thing I would add is Milwaukee as I noted before, when you look at it, it is still a growing part of our network in the entity that we are building on. And you know, a different when you compare say Atlanta which was when we arrived, more or less fully developed. This is more similar to Baltimore, where we phased into it and have grown it fairly consistently.
  We are a long way from being done up there but I think it's an approach that has worked pretty well. We initially started with service to Atlanta and Orlando, built, and got into a very good position in the leisure market, and have consistently grown into the business now to a point where at which point you are at critical mass where it can really start building off of itself, that is going to be debatable. But, I think we are in a very strong position to continue the steady growth that we've done in the past.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Mackenzie,  Hudson Securities - Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Yes, very helpful. Thanks for that.
  And then my second question - - looking ahead, it looks like almost half the competitive capacity coming into AirTran's market is coming from Delta. The other half, largely from Southwest and JetBlue. So it looks like the mix of competitive capacity is changing versus historical patterns. That of course suggests AirTran's cost structure will need some depth versus where it has been historically. So I'm wondering how you are thinking about managing, pardon me, the cost structure looking ahead, versus where it's been historically relative to the industry.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Managing the cost structure is, I think we've gotten, again really our Company in 32 areas, very good value, very good operations and we lead with our cost structure. And that is the combination that that works and I think if we tried to deviate from that formula - - we'll see mixed results. The cost again and the quality operations you really go hand in hand. You mentioned the Delta Southwest - - those are probably our key competitors. They watch everything that we do. We keep thinking we can these costs.
  You've probably heard me say this, we've been at it for a long time. We think we have got some pretty good cost advantages versus Southwest now and some really big ones versus JetBlue. And again, and (inaudible) versus delta, I think it is, we do two budgets every year, - - one in fact, what we do and we manage what we are doing. As Arne mentioned, we are getting benefits by carrying fewer bags. We have always had the best baggage delivery numbers in the industry. They have gotten better. We need fewer people to load the plane. We need to look at all this stuff.
  So I think the discipline, we have been doing it so long really it really is second nature. And I think we widened our advantages over the last couple of years. I think we could stay there. So, again, I don't see much changing. - - what we have seen is, we have seen a lot of the legacy carriers reorganize through bankruptcies and we still have huge advantages. So I think - - certainly over the foreseeable future I don't see us losing our cost leadership. A lot of it is internal focus and a just a much different mind set than other carriers have.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan, I think we have always understood what our core competitive strength here as a Company, and it is our ability to manage costs. Because we compete with the world's largest airline in Atlanta. We compete with the world's largest low cost airline in Southwest. We do it, we do it successfully. And we have been able to do it for quite sometime. And so, I don't think that the capacity that you are talking about is anything unique or anything really new to what we've seen over the last several years. It is just, this is the world we operate in. We have a Company that can do it, can do it successfully and there is not a long list of airlines that have been able to deliver like AirTran has.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Mackenzie,  Hudson Securities - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. Thanks a lot. Appreciate that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Kevin Chrissy from UBS Investment Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Chrissy,  UBS Investment Bank - Analyst   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, just a couple of quick questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, Kevin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Chrissy,  UBS Investment Bank - Analyst   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tax rate, Arne? Are we back to the 39 now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Chrissy,  UBS Investment Bank - Analyst   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And second. Do you guys used ITA software for your website search and such?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We do - - no, not directly. Not on our website.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Chrissy,  UBS Investment Bank - Analyst   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks. I'll leave it there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Next question comes from Steve O'Hara from Sidoti &amp; Co.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve O'Hara,  Sidoti &amp; Co. - Analyst   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi. Good morning. I was wondering if you could just state whether you think you get a benefit from having a lower bag fee in your network versus carriers that have higher bag fees in those same markets?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Listen Kevin, I'm really not going to get into bag fees relative to anybody else. If you look at the broader question of the bag fee impact on demand, I'm not, there is no way to really measure it. If you look at loads overall, we are still hitting record loads and unit revenue performance. So on that I don't think there is really much we can comment on.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve O'Hara,  Sidoti &amp; Co. - Analyst   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And in terms of the cost structure, I mean, are you focused more on keeping a relative advantage, or maintaining - - your cost structure to the best of your ability?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think it is the latter. - - one of the things that I think we could paint this industry with a brush and a focus on - - relative performance. And generally, again, as an industry, you want to perform and that leads to the kind of paint you into a weaker position. And so us, it had to be the absolute number. I think that needs to be the primary focus. When you're done at the end, you can look back - - the result is relative. But from an actual perspective, you've got to look at there stuff constantly. Again, it is ultimately - - very, very disciplined process.
  It's very unpleasant to work around AirTran in November because I guess actually the budget process starts around Labor Day and it goes a very long time. It is just typically - - we rebudget every year - - big year, which we've got again this year, and it is a practice of again really constant focus. Like I said, I think we are very, very comfortable again really, where we are. It's certainly harder when you are not growing. But it doesn't mean there is not things you can improve. When you look at it now, where we stand we are in a very good position.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve O'Hara,  Sidoti &amp; Co. - Analyst   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then I guess finally, I think you said you were going to begin some leased aircraft next year. I'm just wondering does that affect the, I assume the maintenance costs to be higher on a leased aircraft versus a new aircraft? And is that, but I also assume that would be kind of factored into the lease rate?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve, this is Arne. The lease rate is either two used 717s obviously. Lease rate is quite competitive. And because we are our 717 fleet on a large amount of power by the hour relationship with the original manufacturers, for the most part the cost profile should be no different than the rest of our 717 fleets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve O'Hara,  Sidoti &amp; Co. - Analyst   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks a lot.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Helane Becker from Dahlman Rose.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Helane Becker,  Dahlman Rose - Analyst   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, Operator. Hi, gentlemen. I just had one question related to the third quarter specifically. As we go into the summer months, very often your operations in the southeast get affected by hurricanes. Could you just talk about your A, your plan A, in advance of kind of what you are thinking about where your capacity is and so on. And then two, what percent actually would be addition of the routes in Milwaukee and some of the other service you've added our of Baltimore is now really so southeast-focused?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well hurricanes - - if you drive by the church and light a candle and hope they stay away. That is really the best hurricane strategy. And quite frankly, we actually get, we don't have many new buildings, but we actually just opened up a new system of operations new call center right across the street where we are. If we look back at our operation to get it - - September is arguably our weakest month of the year from a revenue standpoint, and it is kind of the way it works for us. - - we pulled down a capacity level in September, it is probably 22%, 23% below July, but the adjustment capacity is even more so in the Florida routes. It is typically a weaker month down here. It's one of the, it's really the only real weak month is September.
  So we are, we have deeper pull downs than we did say four or five years ago. We try to do that with day of the week capacity. I think in terms of the impact - - four or five years ago, we probably had 95% of our capacity in the southeast, and today it is probably 65% or 60%, because of the bigger Baltimore operation and the operation in Milwaukee. So it is smaller, it is certainly what it was in capacity, again we reduce our capacity, in September, more than we did four or five years ago.
  But yes, really beyond that, it really is, it really is hard to tell, and again it is some years you get two or three of these things and some years you get none. I would say generally speaking - - we probably don't focus on it as much as we used to. Really, you can't plan on it. We do focus on pulling September down because of the weakest in the leisure traffic during that month.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Helane Becker,  Dahlman Rose - Analyst   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay, great. That is very helpful. And then I just wanted to get one clarification on the maintenance costs. Because with the fleet, that was the only one I thought was maybe a little bit higher than I might have expected with the relatively new fleet. And coming to your maintenance holidays. So is that the run rate we should be thinking about? And then going into 2011 with less capacity growth planned, are the increases likely to moderate?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Helane, this is Arne. In regards to maintenance I think this is actually our maintenance guide came in a little bit better than what we thought. We've had a big increase this year related to 717s. That we are not going to see the same kind of increase year-over-year next year on our 717s. It's going to be a much more CPI like look on the 717 maintenance costs. 737s, there are fewer of them, they are upwards trending but it is not a dramatic increase. It is a fairly routine look. Sequentially, I think absolute maintenance dollars are probably going to be pretty similar in the third quarter, maybe slightly higher depending on where the block hours come out and completion factor.
  For next year - - I think the trend is likely to be up, we can't give you any kind of firm numbers yet. That is something where as Bob said, football season is kind of - - or budget season is kind of like football season around here. - - we are going to spend August and we might let up a little bit come January before we start talking about where we think the costs are coming out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just to be very specific, we have 175, 180 engines for the 717s and a very (inaudible) most of these airplanes have another eight, nine years to go in terms of contracts. This is the last big increase, other than we have CPI. So a step up this year actually begins to moderate in November, December, and then I think again it won't be level, but more moderate, as we go forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Helane Becker,  Dahlman Rose - Analyst   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Okay. Thank you for your help on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Our next question comes from Michael Derchin from CRT Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Derchin,  CRT Capital - Analyst   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, guys. Just a quick one on the status of the pilot negotiations and also whether in that regard, whether the failure of the Spirit strike - - has any implications in the negotiations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well I think I won't give a very detailed answer because I think we can take it we are not going to negotiate in the press. But again, having said that - - our pilots and our management, we separately met with the NNP, we've gotten back to the table. And it is probably over the last seven or eight days, we have had our best progress than we have had in months, which is, I would say real positive. So I would say again I have been optimistic.
  I think we still have a shot of getting a deal by the end of the summer. If I look at the progress we have made recently - - I feel you know even better about that. So again, I kind of go back at the end of the day. We've got a group of pilots, they work hard, and as a group we all know collectively what it takes for us to be successful; quality, good cost structure. So we are going to make adjustments to the agreements. And I think we are starting to see things - - come together if I can draw a trend off where we have been over the last couple of weeks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Derchin,  CRT Capital - Analyst   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thanks very much, very helpful.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from James Higgins from [Silio] Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 James Higgins,  Silio Securities - Analyst   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, everyone. I have a question clarification on the longer term capacity outlook. I believe I heard a figure of 3% or 4% ASM growth in 2011 or 2012. Not to split hairs, but is that a total growth over that period or is that a per year growth?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A per year growth. And I would probably say, 2012 is probably the higher end of the range, depending on how, what kind of utilization rates we have on the aircraft list. The timing of (inaudible) in 2011 are more weighted toward the front half of the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 James Higgins,  Silio Securities - Analyst   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And that actually brings us up another question, which is relative to peak utilization you have seen over your network in past years, how far below your potential capacity levels are you currently?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Arne Haak,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - CFO   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think if you look at where our utilization is now it is about an 11.1. I think peak is about an 11.4, Kevin?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Healy,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - SVP Marketing &amp; Planning   [107]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's generally philosophically, we try to run and we have led up a bill. But it is probably about another 15 minutes - - out of 40. But this would make, but that is about the biggest that we could push it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 James Higgins,  Silio Securities - Analyst   [108]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [109]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [110]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I am not showing any further questions. I would now like to turn the program over to Mr. Bob Fornaro.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Fornaro,  AirTran Holdings, Inc. - Chairman, Pres, CEO   [111]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And again, I would like to thank everybody for joining us on the call tonight. - - we have accomplished a lot over the last year. We've renewed our lease in Atlanta, we've defined the terms of our aircraft deliveries, we have improved the financial profile of the Company, achieved significant improvements in unit revenue and we've continued to maintain our low cost advantage. I would just like to say I'm really encouraged by the continued growth of our yield improvements, the growth of our profitability and our competitive position in Milwaukee. And I think it sets us up for good earnings growth in the second half of the year. Thanks for the time today and I'll see everybody in October.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [112]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This does conclude today's program. You may now disconnect and have a wonderful day.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2010 AirTran Holdings, Inc. Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Dallas</city>
  <companyName>Southwest Airlines Co</companyName>
  <companyTicker>LUV</companyTicker>
  <startDate>21-Jul-10 1:30pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>92562</companyId>
  <CUSIP>844741108</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2831543</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US8447411088</ISIN>
</Event>