<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="2637662" lastUpdate="Friday, January 29, 2010 at 7:43:54pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="2637662.F" expirationDate="Thursday, January 28, 2010 at 7:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of MAA earnings conference call or presentation 28-Jan-10 7:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q4 2009 Colonial Properties Trust Earnings Conference Call

Memphis Jan 29, 2010 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Mid-America Apartment Communities Inc earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, January 28, 2010 at 7:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jerry Brewer
      Colonial Properties Trust - EVP, Finance
   *  Tom Lowder
      Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO
   *  Reynolds Thompson
      Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO
   *  Paul Earle
      Colonial Properties Trust - COO
   *  Bradley Sandidge
      Colonial Properties Trust - CAO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Michael Salinsky
      RBC Capital - Analyst
   *  David Toti
      Citigroup - Analyst
   *  Michael Bilerman
      Citigroup - Analyst
   *  Michelle Ko
      Banc of America - Analyst
   *  Rich Anderson
      BMO Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Andrew McCulloch
      Green Street Advisors - Analyst
   *  Robert Piala
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Dustin Pizzo
      UBS - Analyst
   *  Shane Buckner
      Wallace Capital Management - Analyst
   *  Michael Aryan
      Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst
   *  Haendel St. Juste
      Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon. I will be your conference operator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the Colonial Properties Trust fourth quarter earnings conference call. (Operator Instructions) Thank you, Mr. Brewer. You may begin your conference.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jerry Brewer,  Colonial Properties Trust - EVP, Finance   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Whitney, and welcome to everyone joining us today. We released our earnings this morning via Business Wire. A copy of this earnings release may be found on our website at colonialprop.com. We are also webcasting this call for your convenience. The replay will be available for your convenience at our website for one week after the call. Tom Lowder, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and Reynolds Thompson, President and Chief Financial Officer, will lead today's call. On the call, they will present an overview of our business developments, discuss our financial results for the fourth quarter and our guidance for 2010. After their comments, we'll open up the call to take your questions. Paul Earle, our Chief Operating Officer, and Bo Jackson, our Executive Vice President of Office, are also here to field questions. Much of our information given on this call may include forward-looking statements regarding our beliefs and current expectations with respect to various matters. Forward-looking statements are intended to fall under the Safe Harbor provisions.
  Let me remind you that much of our information we discuss on this call, including answers we give in response to your questions may include forward-looking statements regarding our beliefs and current expectations with respect to various matters. These forward-looking statements are intended to fall under the Safe Harbor Provisions of the Securities Law. These estimates are also based on a number of assumptions, any of which, unrealized could adversely affect their accuracy. See our latest SEC filings for the detail and explanation of risk. Any non-GAAP financial measures we discuss are reconciled to the closest GAAP financial measures and filings that can be found on our website. I'll now turn the call over to Tom.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Jerry. Good afternoon to everyone. Good morning to our friends on the West Coast on the call today. We'll discuss the initiatives that we've been pursuing this year, fourth quarter results and our guidance for 2010. As I've outlined on previous calls, our initiatives for 2009 were to strengthen the balance sheet, improve liquidity, address near-term maturities, reduce overhead, and postpone or phase developments. The fourth quarter capped a very productive year in terms of executing these initiatives. For the year, we raised a total of $150 million in new capital through a successful equity offering in our at-the-market equity program. We completed $506 million of secured financings with Fannie Mae at an attractive interest rate and generated proceeds of $51 million from the sale of commercial assets, as well as $56 million in condominium sales. This capital was deployed in delevering the Company and lengthening the debt maturity schedule through our repurchase of $579 million in unsecured senior notes in the exiting of seven joint ventures comprised of 37 properties that eliminated $231 million of our pro rata share of property-specific mortgage debt. By year-end, our leverage ratio had improved by 500 basis points to 53.8%. The unwinding of the joint ventures was a particular accomplishment as it served to help simplify our business, reduce overhead, as well as significantly reduce our near-term maturities. For the year, corporate G&amp;A improved 23% for a savings of over $5 million. Our focus is clearly on multi-family operations, and we will continue to build on the initiatives that we set out in 2009. I'll speak to the 2010 directives at the end of the call. Now Reynolds will provide some details about the fourth quarter operating performance and financing activities. After that, I'll discuss guidance for the next year. Reynolds?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Tom. FFO for the fourth quarter was $0.25 per share compared with a loss of $1.62 for the prior year. Operating FFO, which we define as FFO before transaction income, was $0.25 per share compared with a loss of $1.73 per share for the prior year. Our fourth quarter same property revenues were down 3.8% compared with the prior year, and NOI declined 10.7%. While the downward trend is moderating, we continue to experience job losses in our markets, and this continues to put pressure on revenues. Fourth quarter average rental rates were down 6.2% compared with 2008 and down 2% versus the third quarter. Rental income has continued to decline, and we expect to see this trend at least through the first half of next year. Same property occupancy ended the quarter at 94.7%, an increase of 30 basis points from the third quarter. Annual revenues declined 2.8% with average rental rates declining 3.5%. The revenue decline, combined with the 3.8% expense growth, produced an annual 6.9% decline in NOI.
  The fourth quarter expense increase of 7.9% was primarily a result of the timing of our insurance true-ups being completed in the third quarter this year versus the fourth quarter last year, resulting in a $1 million negative variance this quarter. However, for the full year, our same property insurance expense improved by $400,000. Qualified traffic for the quarter increased 4% as compared to the prior year. Rates on new leases decreased approximately 11% for the quarter based on 5,100 new leases. Renewal rates for the quarter improved 50 basis points compared -- or based on 2,800 renewals. Financial and job-related turnover continues to be at elevated levels, up roughly 190 basis points over 2008 to 26.5%. However, it has dropped below 27% for the first time since the fourth quarter of 2008. We would anticipate this number trending down as the economy stabilizes. Improving housing affordability has allowed many of our major markets to work through elevated single family home inventories, which are down approximately 24% from a year ago. However, the impact of the improved affordability continues to show up in our home buyer turnover which has trended up to 19% in the fourth quarter representing a 520 basis point increase sequentially.
  While the unsold housing supplies moderated to early 2006 levels, lower sales volumes keeping home pricing down and the supply at above normal levels. These factors will continue to put pressure on revenue in 2010. We believe occupancy in 2010 will remain stable at approximately 94%. The new lease rates will continue to decline resulting in declining revenues and NOI in all of our major markets. Given the recent moderation of job losses and the typical trailing pattern we see in multi-family revenues, we could potentially see the rate of revenue decline moderate in the third and fourth quarters of 2010.
  As Tom mentioned, we continue to make substantial progress in exiting joint ventures. As we discussed on our third quarter call, we completed the exit of our joint venture with OZ Retail, LLC. In unwinding the JV, we transferred our interest plus $45 million in cash, which was used to repay $38 million of mortgage debt and a $7 million note to help our previous unit holders. We were released from our $50 million pro rata share of the joint venture's debt and received 100% ownership of Colonial Promenade Alabaster, a 98%-leased retail center in Birmingham.
  Also, as previously discussed, we sold our 10% joint venture interest in Colony Woods, a 414-unit apartment community for $2.5 million. The new news on the joint venture front since our last call was the exit of our 17-asset DRA-CRT joint venture and the sale of our Colonial Center Mansell office joint venture. In unwinding the DRA-CRT joint venture, we transferred our 15% ownership interest and made a $24.7 million payment in exchange for 100% ownership in one of the joint venture's assets, Three Ravinia, an 813,000 square foot Class A office building in Atlanta. As part of the transaction, we repaid the $106 million of debt on Three Ravinia and were released from our $141 million pro rata share of the joint venture's mortgage debt maturing in 2009 and 2010. Additionally, we were released from the $17 million loan guarantee we had previously provided on the property. We continue to manage all of the properties that were previously part of the DRA-CRT joint venture.
  We sold our 15% interest in the Colonial Center Mansell office joint venture in Atlanta to the majority partner for $3 million in cash, and we were released from our $13.9 million pro rata share of the mortgage debt. The net result of exiting the seven joint ventures this year was the elimination of $231 million of our pro rata share of mortgage debt, $125 million of which was scheduled to mature in 2010.
  Regarding our disposition activity, we completed the sale of Colonial Promenade Winter Haven for $20.7 million. The 23-year-old property was unencumbered, and the proceeds were used to reduce the outstanding balance on our unsecured line of credit. We also sold 23 condominium units for total sales proceeds of $4.9 million, which included the remaining 14 units at the Grander. We now have two condominium projects which are in Charlotte. After taking into account a $1.7 million impairment on the remaining units at Metropolitan, our condominium investment has a total book value of approximately $22.3 million.
  Regarding development activity, at the end of the year, we had one active retail project under construction, a Publix-anchored shopping center in Gulf Shores, Alabama. It is expected to open in April of 2010. We have $3 million remaining to be spent on this development.
  During the quarter, we recorded a $6.5 million impairment charge related to our retail development Colonial Promenade Nor du Lac. The charge is a result of our intention to develop a power center in phases over time as opposed to our original lifestyle center plan. Also, you'll note in our release that we recorded an income tax benefit of $7.9 million in the quarter, which is the result of the new NOL carryback rules that were passed in November of 2009. The new rules allow us to apply taxable [reached] subsidiary losses against income realized in 2005 and 2006.
  There were no repurchases of unsecured senior notes in the fourth quarter. For the year, we were successful in repurchasing $579 million of our outstanding unsecured debt and recognized almost $55 million in gains from these repurchases. Our Board has authorized a new unsecured notes repurchase program for up to $100 million that will run through the end of 2010.
  Finally, I'd like to remind everyone of the equity offering we completed in early October that raised net proceeds of $109 million. Together with our at-the-market equity program, we raised over $150 million of capital in 2009 which was used to reduce our outstanding debt. As a result of all of our activity, we now have only $44 million of consolidated debt maturing in 2010 and $57 million in consolidated debt maturing in 2011. Our ratio of net debt plus preferred to gross assets reflects our improving balance sheet. We ended the year at 53.8%, a 500 basis point improvement from 2008. Tom?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Reynolds. I think we can all agree that's a long list of accomplishments for 2009, but as you'll note in the release, we've issued guidance for 2010. So let's talk about 2010 for a moment. We are projecting that 2010 net operating income will continue to be under pressure from the lack of any jobs improvement and the corresponding impact on rental revenue. There have been signs the economy has been improving in our markets, but unfortunately this economic improvement has not been accompanied by job growth, which of course we all agree is the key driver for our net operating income in the multi-family sector.
  Our 2010 full year guidance is as follows. Total funds from operation is expected to be $0.92 to $1.00 per share with operating FFO in the range of $0.92 to $0.97 per share. On a GAAP basis, we're anticipating a net loss of $0.70 per share to $0.78 per share. Our same property net operating income guidance range expects a decline of 6% to 8%. We expect same property revenue to be down 2.5% to 3.5% and expenses to be higher by 2% to 3%. Development spending will be roughly $25 million to $30 million. Land and poor sale residential dispositions will be $15 million to $25 million. New secured financings are expected to be between $150 million to $200 million. Gains from the repurchase of our corporate securities and land sales are expected to be as much as $0.03 per share. And corporate G&amp;A is relatively unchanged from last year at $17 million to $19 million. Finally, you will note that we have assumed approximately $25 million to $50 million for acquisitions. We are actively looking for opportunities available in the market, and we anticipate funding any of those acquisitions through the issuance of new equity in 2010. Consistent with last quarter, the Board declared a quarterly cash dividend of $0.15 per share.
  As we look ahead to 2010, we're much stronger. We are leaner. We're a focused Company. More than we were certainly at this point a year ago. We've made significant progress to strengthen the balance sheet, raise capital, sell non-core assets, and unwind highly leveraged joint ventures. For 2010, we've established the following directives, and I hope this has been helpful to all of you in our past calls in 2009 to point out our progress on the directives we've had in the past. But for 2010, we've established these four directives. First of all, to simplify the business. And I want that to resonate not only at the corporate level and to you and the efforts we've made in joint ventures and so forth, but all the way through the operations in our business to become a better operating Company. And in so doing, the second directive is to improve our margins. I'll speak in detail a little bit about this in a second, but of course we've got challenges with revenues in the multi-family area this year. We've acknowledged that with our guidance, but we can still work on margins in all level of our operations to make sure that we're doing our best to get the most of the bottom line.
  Number three. Our third directive will be to strengthen the balance sheet. We're still not where we want to be. We still want to continue to delever the Company. And the fourth, but not least with all of this, we want to grow the Company. And we will continue to look for opportunities out there, but with all -- with a mind that with growing the Company, we will also continue to improve the balance sheet, which was the third directive I just spoke to. We'll continue to simplify the business, as I've said, through exiting JV activities and streamlining our other internal processes. And we'll work on that second directive all through the level of the Company to improve our margins where we have the opportunity. I've spoken to the third directive of strengthening the balance sheet, and we will continue to look for opportunities out there. When we find these activities, we'll match them up with funding of new equity for those opportunities.
  We're likely to experience much of the same economic challenges in 2010 that we had this past year. That being said, we expect a rebound in the business later this year and early next year in 2011. We're strong believers in the long-term growth characteristics of our diversified Sun Belt markets and the demographics which drive future demand for multi-family, namely the large and growing Echo Boomer population coupled with the projected job growth that we expect to return to our Sun Belt markets. I hope this guidance for 2010 has been helpful to you, and we look forward to your questions. So now at this time, Operator, would you please open the call up for questions?
 
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions) Your first question from the line of Michael Salinsky with RBC Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hello, Mike.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just to be clear, the guidance you laid out there. That does not assume any significant job growth even in the back half of the year? And it also does not contemplate any additional job losses from this point, correct?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, from 30,000 feet to overview is a tough two quarters the first half of the year with things getting better in the third quarter and perhaps at the -- by the end of the year we might see a little light at the end of the tunnel, but a pretty tough year. Reynolds, why don't you speak to how those numbers lay out by quarter although we don't give quarter-to-quarter guidance. You can give Mike a view of how the numbers work.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mike, as Tom mentioned, our view is that we will continue to see pressure on jobs, particularly in the first half of the year with hopefully that moderating later. When you look at those trends and rolling down our NOIs and then compare that to prior periods, you are going to see some pretty steep NOI quarter-to-quarter rolldowns in the first and second quarters with moderation in the third and getting closer to a lower number toward the end of the year. So it'll be somewhat of a steep slope based on the way we view the revenue trends coming down in comparison to 2009.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's helpful. Second of all, could you just touch upon what rates on new leases versus renewals were in the fourth quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The new deals roll down approximately 11%. And the renewals were up about one half a basis point.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Has that continued into the first quarter? Have you seen that [deckat and barrel] so far?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We don't have any any new data to report on first quarter so far.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Two follow-up questions just for the joint ventures. It sounds like there's some additional joint venture unwinding planned. Just given the simplification goals. Is there anything immediate on the horizon? Or is that more back-end loaded at this point?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mike, there's nothing immediate on the horizon. Obviously it fits into our strategy that we feel like we've made so much progress there, there's not anything particularly from a debt perspective that is creating an inordinate amount of pressure. Yes, it fits into the strategy. But there is nothing that is going to compel us to have to do something that doesn't make financial sense. So we'll look for those opportunities and certainly take advantage of it when it's something that we feel like makes sense for us economically.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But it's on our list, and we'll continue to keep you updated by quarter. Our equity investment there. Our Board was pleased with our report. We have moved from $46 million in equity down to a little over $17 million in equity in JVs. I think we'll continue to make progress there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then finally, you had a fairly sizable spike there in CapEx spending in the fourth quarter. What's your plan for 2010 in terms of CapEx?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Why don't we let Paul Earle speak specifically to that. First of all, the fourth quarter and how that lays out for 2010. Paul?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Mike, we went through, late in the year, some roof replacements on several of the cornerstone assets. So if you look at the full year, the number is up some above our normal run rate. And the fourth quarter was replacing roofs on the cornerstone properties. If you look in 2010 and 2011 and going forward, it will drop back down to our normal run rate. You won't see that one quarter blip.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. A normal run rate would be?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Much closer to [675] to [725] per unit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Salinsky,  RBC Capital - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of David Toti with Citigroup.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Toti,  Citigroup - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, everybody. My first question is could you quantify where you think there might be upside or downside risk to your 2010 guidance in terms of how it might be impacted by employment numbers? And how that ties into your expectations for specific market performance?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll let Reynolds give the math, but I think it's -- we have given our range there for how we expect things to be. But if things were to turn worse, which I think is what you're asking the risk side of it. Reynolds, I believe for every 1% moved down in our same store number probably would get down to somewhere around $0.03 per share in our operating FFO. So if we get outside of that guidance range that we've given you to being worse, that would impact our budget numbers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Toti,  Citigroup - Analyst   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess asked a different way, what kind of environment are you underwriting for the year? I know you've described it a little bit. But in terms of, do you think there's more downside risk given the economic situation than upside?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we have tried to anticipate that we're going to continue to see jobs pressure, particularly in the first half of the year. And so, we have anticipated our revenues being under pressure through the first half of the year. With that moderating in the third quarter. So our view is we're going to continue to see that pressure. We'll continue to see rolldowns, and that hopefully will moderate once we get to the third quarter. Plus we'll be in a period where our comparison periods were under a lot of pressure as well, and there won't be quite as much variance from quarter to quarter based on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Toti,  Citigroup - Analyst   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's helpful, and then my final question, just has to do with the acquisitions. I know you probably can't be too specific, but could you maybe describe what the current pipeline might look like? What your regional focus might be? What your pricing expectations might be, and how you think about acquiring in the context of continuing to shrink and simplify the Company
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 First of all, as far as strengthening the Company, we've stated that when we do acquisitions, we'll be mindful that we need to bring in additional equity to do acquisitions. So we still have that directive, which we'll report on to you quarterly about how we're working to delever the Company in addition to growing the Company. But more specifically about the product in the markets, we will stay in our footprint that we currently are in, and we are prejudiced toward looking to add where we are under 10% of our total properties, we certainly would rather add in markets where we have less product now. For instance, Charlotte, where that's 14% or so of our total NOI in the multi-family area. An acquisition in Charlotte would be very difficult for us just because we have a prejudice to reduce our numbers down from that level and not to exceed that level in any of our markets. So if you were to look at some of our markets where we're maybe getting 3%, 4%, 5% of our NOI. We would prefer to be in those markets, and we prefer to be, quite honestly, in the markets that have received the most pain -- where we've seen the most downturn in rent revenues. So that we could take advantage of the opportunities there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom, it's Michael Bilerman speaking. Just had a follow-up from David. I guess as you talked about the need to delever. I think that is clearly the right strategy to continue to move down and reduce risk. And I think you talked about the acquisitions being equity funded. How do you marry-up issuing what it still expensive equity? Your shares are trading [8.5] to a [9] cap. You are 12 times FFO multiple. So that equity is very, very expensive relative to, I would say, the yield that you would get on assets. So how do you marry those two things up?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael, this is Reynolds. Yes, we feel like we're in an environment here where clearly we've got some short-term math that will put pressure on us. Particularly if we're using equity to go after these types of acquisitions, but it's also an opportunity for us in that while it is not nearly as dilutive as delevering and paying down debt. And we like the idea of participating in the market today, hopefully finding some newer product that is attractively priced. And as Tom mentioned, is in markets that it might have some substantial upside down the road. And we get the added benefit of if we use the majority of those are purchased with equity, we get the benefit of improving the balance sheet. We'd rather do that now. And while it may not be accretive today or even slightly dilutive today, we're going to have assets that we like long-term that will grow in the future. And in this year and in this environment when the operations are tough, we can work on the balance sheet and continue to get our debt and equity in line with the rest of the peer group. So we're balancing all of those things, but we think it's important to be out there and try to take advantage of what we hope will be some attractive opportunities for growth with nicer assets down the road.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And let me add just as far as the risk to the guidance numbers we have given you. We really modeled this out to match off those, too. But those activities, while they could come earlier in the year, and we would certainly take advantage of them if we did have opportunities that came earlier to us, we have modeled those in later in the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the $150 million is a late year in terms of both acquisitions and the equity that it would fund?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's the way we have modeled our numbers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. We've actually only got $50 million of acquisitions modeled. And they're late year. The $150 million was financing.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So you have $50 million of equity in the numbers as well then? Is that -- or is there more -- ?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 $50 million of equity and $50 million of acquisitions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. That'd be the right way to think about it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In 4Q, or when is it? I'm just trying to think about the dilution.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 He's asking which quarter. It's -- to execute that, it's a slight dilution to our guidance. It's in our guidance, but it is a slight dilution
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And we've modeled it in in the third and fourth quarters.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For the full third and fourth?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 About half in the third, half in the fourth.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And you've modeled in the equity at what sort of cost?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are planning on probably thinking about an ATM-type program. And from a modeling standpoint, I'm not going to speak to exactly what we think that stock price is going to be, but I think we've been relatively conservative.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 $20, right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. ( Laughter)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Bilerman,  Citigroup - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Michelle Ko with Banc of America.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michelle Ko,  Banc of America - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about your underwriting assumptions for the acquisitions and developments? What kind of cap rates you would purchase at, and what yields you are expecting on developments? What kind of IRRs you are expecting for acquisitions and developments? And what kind of NOI growth you are assuming for the next few years?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There were a lot of questions in there. We will start with the easiest side. We've got a range that we've given you on the development side of $25 million to $30 million. That is related to our Publix Center in Gulf Shores. A small piece of that. We also have some dollars that we think we would begin to spend in Louisiana on the first phase of our Nor du Lac project. While we do have multi-family sites, we don't anticipate at this point spending any development dollars on those. But we are watching those markets and looking at the rents, and we'll do that monthly as we have been doing. And if we have an opportunity where something makes some sense, we'll look at it. With regard to the acquisitions, we are, like everyone else, looking at current rents, and a big factor in that is it's not a one-size-fits-all. It's what's happened in a particular market. So as Tom mentioned in markets that have experienced a significant amount of stress, we may have a different set of assumptions there than we might in a market that has not. And our bias is to be pretty conservative, but we do think there's some upside there to be had. That's how we're doing it on a market-by-market basis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And I would just to add to that, it's a view of not only the current in-place returns, but assuming in that same market our same assumptions per rolldown and rents. So I'm not going try to sell you that we're going to go out there and make acquisitions that are going to jump off the page and because they're rolling up in rents. We are making the same assumptions in those markets for acquisitions that we have given guidance here which is obviously a rolldown. So we want to be realistic about that. We want to look at, in a certain market, if we have an average age of eight years in that market in our product and $120,000 a unit. Obviously, if we can buy at $80,000 a unit for a new project, that would also be a positive check on the acquisition list that we have brought our portfolio down to a better number per unit in a better age per unit that would help our overall portfolio. So those are additional factors.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michelle Ko,  Banc of America - Analyst   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess in some of the markets that you're looking at where you're located have had cap rates increased or decreased over the last 90 days?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think cap rates have surprisingly stayed low. We wish we could go out there and buy product all day long at 8% cap rates, but we haven't found any of those opportunities. So they continue to stick on a lower range south of there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michelle Ko,  Banc of America - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Great. Just one final question. So let's say you don't find any acquisitions for this year. Where would you spend the extra cash that you have?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Remember, we're going to fund this with equity. So we wouldn't raise it until we needed it. It's kind of a looking at the pipeline and trying to match those things off.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's not going to affect our guidance that we've given you if those opportunities don't happen.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michelle Ko,  Banc of America - Analyst   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. Okay. I see. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Rich Anderson with BMO Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hey, good afternoon, everybody.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hello.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds, did you say that you expect rental income to be declining at least through the first half of 2011?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Revenue, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Revenue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 2010. Not 2011.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You said next year, so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we're still stuck in '09.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My bad. 2010.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We had such a good time in '09, we didn't want to leave it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I figured you didn't remember what year it was. You have got enough on your plate.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is definitely true.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So revenues decline, and then you are saying a declining rate of decline during the second half of the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. The income tax benefit -- new law or whatever. How should we be modeling that for future period?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's a one-time deal. We've taken everything that that is going to give us. It's done.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. I figured that. Just wanted to make sure. The $4.6 million in asset sale gains this quarter. Was that -- was there part of that from the joint venture transactions that you did?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. That was to the net income basis. Those were not FFO gains related to that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. They weren't FFO gains, but you had some gain activity from the joint ventures that you sold out of?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It was primarily the Winter Haven sale that we had. 100% on asset.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Why aren't you managing Mansell and the retail JV assets?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Part of the attraction of working on the simplification was our ability to make some improvements in what we're doing internally with regard to overhead. And particularly in the retail deal to go from managing a portfolio of 11 assets spread across the Southeast to one asset here in our backyard gave us an opportunity to really simplify what we were doing in our back office and externally and improve our overhead situation. So that was on the retail side. In Atlanta, our partner wanted somebody else to manage that, and it made sense from our standpoint. When we picked up Ravinia, we have got a nice asset to focus on over there. We are going to be moving our offices down to that building and concentrating our efforts on leasing that project up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Again, for the fourth quarter, just so I have this right. There are a lot of moving parts, and I am easily confused to begin with. It basically comes down to the $7.9 million of gain -- the income tax gain -- offset by the $8.4 million of impairments. That's why you came out with a number pretty close to consensus. Is that how the math worked, or was there -- ?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pretty close. Those do largely offset each other.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just wanted to simplify that for myself and make sure I wasn't overstepping or oversimplifying it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You probably are, but it's the way the math worked out, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I know I am, but just want to make sure that that's basically it. Everything else cancels itself out. Finally, you lost your investment grade rating on your senior unsecured debt during 2009. Now you are authorized to go back and buy back more unsecured debt. I guess I don't know why, but it seems like without the ability to issue unsecured debt at this present time to take some of that -- or potentially take some of that out of your capitalization. I'm just wondering what the thought process is there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There, too, one, we're very aware of our situation with the rating agencies. And that is something that we are working on with the work we're doing on the balance sheet. We would obviously like to be in a position to work back toward revisiting that with the rating agencies at the appropriate time. I think ultimately we're going to have to have fundamentals behind us in addition to having our balance shape to go revisit that. In the meantime, we've got an opportunity to lengthen our debt maturity schedule and lock in attractive long-term rates given that we believe rates will rise in the future at some point. And we don't want to lose all of that opportunity. So we know where the boundaries are with regard to all of the different constituencies, and we are going to maximize what we can do without having to cross any of those lines while we have got an opportunity to do it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You lose some opportunity to get back into investment grade range if you don't have debt out there trading and all that sort of stuff? Does that impact anything?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't believe so. I think we've got to be careful about how much properties we place secure financing on in regard to that. And I think those are some of the boundaries we're looking at.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wouldn't know why, but it's just a brainstorming-type question. How would you say your conversations are going with the rating agencies now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Improving. It's amazing what a little equity does for you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rich Anderson,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That sounds good. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Andrew McCulloch with Green Street Advisors.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon. You had some moving pieces on the property management front. What are your expectations for management revenue for 2010?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the JV third party fee side, let's see if we can grab a number for you out of our model. It may take a minute.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew, it looks like it's approximately $10 million.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 How do your margins run usually on that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In the past, they have been 20% or so. They're going to be squeezed a little bit. They're not going to be that good going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Then you mentioned a noticeable uptick in moveouts to home purchase. How does that vary from market to market?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let's drill down. Paul, you've got that chart in front of you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I believe I do. Atlanta was 18% of our moveouts in that market. Austin, 23%. Orlando, 25%. Phoenix was 29%. Charlotte was only 13%. Does that give you -- ?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was looking at the increase -- where the biggest increases were?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There was an increase in Richmond, an increase in Raleigh. A slight increase in Orlando. And an increase in Austin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. Just one more question. Sorry if I missed this. Your ownership interests in the Blue Rock office JV ticked up, what was going on there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It should not have.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was just looking on page 14. I'll follow up with you offline on that one.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew McCulloch,  Green Street Advisors - Analyst   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [107]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of [Robert Piala] with Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [108]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [109]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Afternoon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [110]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just want to draw down a little bit into the revenue guidance for 2010. You said minus 3% midpoint. What markets do you specifically see will post worse revenue declines in 2010 versus 2009?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [111]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul, you want to -- ?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [112]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, for 2010, we feel it's going there is going to be continued pressure in Atlanta, Charlotte, Phoenix, and Dallas-Fort Worth. Those are the larger markets that we feel we're going to be under continued pressure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [113]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are there any markets which it would be better than this year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [114]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 He is talking about revenue.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [115]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On revenue, well, we're seeing some improved conditions in Savannah and Charleston. A lot of our smaller markets, Huntsville, Mobile, Birmingham. A little bit of improvement is starting to occur in Orlando where the rate of decline is much less than it was in early 2009.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [116]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Sorry if I missed this, but what was driving the expense growth 7.9% this quarter? It's basically like what's happening in Phoenix, for example, the expenses were up 31% year-over-year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [117]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phoenix was really two components, real estate taxes and insurance.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [118]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As a global comment, the rise in the fourth quarter was related to insurance where we trued up insurance accruals in the third quarter this year versus trueing them up in the fourth quarter last year. And then there's some more specific information with regard to -- that was across the portfolio. And then, with regard to certain markets, as Paul mentioned, we've got some tax numbers that might have had adjustments and accruals and third quarter last year versus fourth quarter this year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [119]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it's better to look at the year-to-date?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [120]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Absolutely. All that washes out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [121]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No matter which week it falls, it can be third or fourth quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [122]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I see. And just last question, what was the peak during the housing boom in the percentage of moveouts, home purchases?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [123]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 38% was our peak. If you remove this last run-up in homeownership rates, our run rate for over seven years was about 15%. When that started to move up, it peaked at 38%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Robert Piala,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [124]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I see. Thank so you much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [125]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Dustin Pizzo with UBS.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dustin Pizzo,  UBS - Analyst   [126]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Good afternoon.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [127]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hello, Dustin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dustin Pizzo,  UBS - Analyst   [128]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hey. You had talked earlier in your opening comments about the home inventories declining in some of the markets. Can you just talk, perhaps anecdotally, because I know it's tough to get any real hard numbers. But what's your sense as to what percentage of those additional buyers that you're seeing out there may actually be out buying homes as opposed to vulture investors that are then turning around and re-renting those homes to either the owners that had previously foreclosed or to perhaps renters that are leaving your communities?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [129]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Real buyers versus investors in the home purchasing.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [130]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think if you go to Phoenix and Las Vegas, you'll find that there's some investor activity in it. If you look at the reports published by Ron Johnsey at Axiometrics and people that are in the multi-family sector, you'll find that they're maybe plus 50% of the purchasing that's going on may be investor-related. I think if you move into Austin and Dallas and Tampa, Orlando and across the other markets, the change or the shift has been over to end-users.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dustin Pizzo,  UBS - Analyst   [131]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [132]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Shane Buckner with Wallace Capital Management.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Shane Buckner,  Wallace Capital Management - Analyst   [133]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You had a handful of properties in the apartment portfolio. Two in Charlotte, and it looks like one in Scottsdale with very low occupancy rates, averaging around 80%. Are those property-specific issues, or is that just market forces?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [134]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [In Reynolds' comments], he was going through in that submarket there is a lot of supply delivered, and there were noticeable job layoffs. So we've gone through pretty significant transitions down to the Gilbert area, southeast Phoenix where a tremendous amount of supply came in. So we had a lot of pressure. We've actually seen that submarket start to recover we are pre-leased now to 89%. So we have seen that particular submarket begin to stabilize over -- after really nine to 12 months of some real pressure. The other properties like Heatherwood, in Charlotte, where we acquired -- .
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [135]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 He was asking specifically about Phoenix. Now you've heard our chief operating answer about the market being tough, but I'll say as CEO, we did have some vacancy in management there with the slow backfill. And it did have an impact of all of our properties in Phoenix. I don't want to sugarcoat the market in Phoenix too much. It's a very difficult market. I think we added to it by some of our management turnover there that created some additional rent loss, and I think you will see those numbers. Certainly physical occupancy numbers improved. You will still see pressure on the rent revenue rolldown there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Shane Buckner,  Wallace Capital Management - Analyst   [136]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And Heatherwood and Greystone in Charlotte, I think you were going to comment on those?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Earle,  Colonial Properties Trust - COO   [137]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Those were assets that we brought into the Company through the Cornerstone merger, and they were originally earmarked on our disposition list. We did not execute the sale of those properties, and so we have been moving through a renovation program. Autumn Hill was also on that list. I think if you will notice, that Autumn hill, we went through repositioning on that property. And we vacated about 30% of the residents, and we moved back up now to above 90%. And we will see some really significant NOI growth. Heatherwood, Greystone, Brookfield are going through that very same process. Where we will put those in the long-term hold category, bring some major improvements to the property, and then reoccupy the units.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Shane Buckner,  Wallace Capital Management - Analyst   [138]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [139]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from the line of Michael [Aryan] with Sun Capital Advisors.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [140]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hello. I might have missed part of the Q&amp;A session, so if my questions a bit repetitive, I apologize. Just regarding leverage and secure leverage. Did secure leverage go down because of the asset sales from quarter to quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [141]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [142]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then I think in your guidance, you said you are going to raise more secured debt. I think that with the ratings agencies, like the 25% secured debt metric is kind of the inflection point for a lot of these people, and just eyeballing it seems like you'd surpass that. Have you thought about that? Obviously, you probably have. How are you going to manage that if you want to get back to investment grade ratings?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [143]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. We very much have thought about it. Our number would be closer to 30%, but we're probably splitting hairs. We know we're trying to walk a thin line there, and we're very cognizant of where they want us to be. We've also got some opportunities like this year you saw that number jump up and down by taking other property-specific mortgages and paying those off, and a lot of that came through the sales and JVs and whatnot. So we think we'll be able to work through that and stay within their guidelines and still take advantage of some of the financing that is out there. In the long run, extending our maturity schedule and locking in some good long-term rates is going to be a good thing for the balance sheet. And I think all of the constituencies will recognize that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [144]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. My follow-up question is that the NOI declines have been pretty pronounced over the last year and one half or so. I apologize for my voice. There was a question asked by, I think, a man at RBC about, excuse me. I think there was a stat given by you that if theres with a 1% decline in NOI, it is like a 3% shift in either FFO per share earnings per share. Was that FFO per share?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [145]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's $0.02 to $0.03 per FFO.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [146]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If I'm thinking about this correctly, if you had roughly an 8.3% decline in NOI which is kind of at the high end of your range -- or a little bit above the high end of your range. Wouldn't you be FFO breakeven?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [147]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 To our guidance, or -- ?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [148]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. I'm just trying to look at it because you generated FFO of $0.25 a share for the quarter, right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [149]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [150]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So then if a 1% decline -- maybe I'm thinking about this incorrectly. If there's a 1% decline in NOI and that equates to a 3% adjustment -- a 3% Delta in your FFO, if you are above -- you know what I'm trying to say here -- if you're above 8% in NOI decline, that takes you to zero in FFO per share, correct? Am I thinking about this incorrectly? Do you understand the logic?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [151]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm sorry. I'm moving slow on you. I'm not following.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [152]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We're speaking to our same store net operating income, and then we're trying to relate it to FFO, and so -- .
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [153]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't understand what you're saying.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [154]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The $0.03 is the total FFO. It's not -- . We've already got built in the down 6% to 8% in our numbers, but it's not -- each 1% is not all from the $0.25 per share that you're
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [155]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Maybe what I'm trying to think of -- maybe another way to ask the question is -- I'm a bond analyst so this is a doomsday scenario-type question. How much does NOI have to decline for to you get to flat FFO or breakeven FFO? Or have you even thought about that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [156]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For to us miss our guidance?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [157]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, basically. Or just to be breakeven FFO -- have zero FFO per share.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [158]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We go from $1.00 on the high end to zero?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [159]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On a quarterly basis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [160]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. 1%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [161]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our chief accounting officer thinks he has everything figured out. (Laughter) [Grandstanding]. We normally don't let him talk. ( Laughter)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [162]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 They don't normally let me talk either, so there's something in common. You want to talk about that line. It's fine. Just because I noticed pretty pronounced NOI declines. So I'm just thinking about worst case scenario.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bradley Sandidge,  Colonial Properties Trust - CAO   [163]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 100 basis points of same store NOI equals $0.02 to $0.03, but we're talking about a full year. You're trying to compare back to a quarter, I believe?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [164]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You're right. I'm being unfair to you. Okay. It would have to be like 25% or 30%, or something like that. Okay. All right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [165]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Aryan,  Sun Capital Advisors - Analyst   [166]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [167]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Your next question is from Haendel St. Juste.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [168]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi there, can you hear me?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [169]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [170]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Most of mine have been asked, but I have a few minor ones. Did you give a cap rate on the Orlando disposition, the Winter Haven?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [171]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh, the Wal-Mart.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [172]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We've got one in our [KPIs], Haendel. It was approximately 8.7%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [173]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And that's trailing -- what type of NOI are you looking there? What's the CapEx?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [174]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's what we recognized in 2009.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [175]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And the CapEx assumption?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [176]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [177]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The dispo.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [178]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's a commercial asset.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [179]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's a Wal-Mart-anchored shopping center. We used it off actual expenses.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [180]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. If you put something in there, probably $0.10 or $0.15 a foot. We don't have anything factored into that number.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [181]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [182]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Cap rate would go down if you did.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [183]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, certainly. Okay. Hearing that certain healthier banks are starting to take another look at providing construction loans, have you seen or heard anything on that? Any color you could add on that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [184]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. Have not. We continue to believe construction is going to be very, very limited in the next 12 to 24 months.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [185]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I share that sentiment. I was actually surprised when I heard that from a few sources. Lastly, I saw one of your public peers acquire a busted development deal during the quarter. I am assuming that's something that you would also look to do if it were available at opportunistic terms, and you could raise the equity to do it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tom Lowder,  Colonial Properties Trust - Chairman, CEO   [186]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Reynolds Thompson,  Colonial Properties Trust - President, CFO   [187]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Haendel St. Juste,  Keefe Bruyette Woods - Analyst   [188]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [189]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At this time, there are no further questions. I will now turn the call back over to Mr. Brewer.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jerry Brewer,  Colonial Properties Trust - EVP, Finance   [190]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, everybody, for joining us today. We look forward to talking to you soon. Have a good day.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [191]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for joining today's conference call. You may now disconnect.
 
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q4 2009 Colonial Properties Trust Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Memphis</city>
  <companyName>Mid-America Apartment Communities Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>MAA</companyTicker>
  <startDate>28-Jan-10 7:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>111228</companyId>
  <CUSIP>59522J103</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2589132</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US59522J1034</ISIN>
</Event>