<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="3473052" lastUpdate="Thursday, March 17, 2011 at 9:25:28pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="3473052.F" expirationDate="Monday, February 21, 2011 at 1:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of MRK.DE earnings conference call or presentation 21-Feb-11 1:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Full Year 2010 Merck KGaA Earnings Presentation

Darmstadt Mar 17, 2011 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Merck KGaA earnings conference call or presentation Monday, February 21, 2011 at 1:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Joshua Young
      Merck KGaA - Head, IR
   *  Karl Kley
      Merck KGaA - Chairman
   *  Michael Becker
      Merck KGaA - CFO
   *  Bernd Kirschbaum
      Merck Serono - Head, R&amp;D

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Andrew Baum
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Richard Vosser
      JP Morgan - Analyst
   *  Marietta Miemietz
      Societe Generale - Analyst
   *  Fabian Wenner
      UBS - Analyst
   *  Matthew Weston
      Credit Suisse - Analyst
   *  Odile Rundquist
      Helvea - Analyst
   *  Daniel Wendorff
      Commerzbank - Analyst
   *  Jack Scannell
      Sanford C. Bernstein - Analyst
   *  Cornelia Thomas
      WestLB - Analyst
   *  Edward Dulac
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Vincent Meunier
      Exane BNP Paribas - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, everybody. We'll begin today's conference and conference call. Thank you and welcome to Merck's fourth-quarter and full-year 2010 earnings, analysts' meeting and conference call. My name is Joshua Young and I'm Head of Investor Relations for Merck. Before we begin, I'd like to introduce the two Members of Merck's Executive Board who are joining me today, Karl Kley, Chairman of the Executive Board and Michael Becker, Chief Financial Officer. Additionally, Bernd Kirschbaum, Head of Research and Development for Merck Serono, will be available to participate during the Q&amp;A session.
 We will be referencing a slide presentation as part of our prepared remarks today. For those of you joining us by telephone or webcast these slides can be downloaded from our Investor Relations website. Additionally, you can also download our 2010 Annual Report and financial statements in Excel. A recording of this meeting and a written transcript will also be posted to our website shortly after the call.
 I would also like to remind you that we will be making forward-looking statements on the conference call today and please review our disclaimer about the risks and uncertainties of such statements on slide number two. Also note that our guidance is related to current business conditions and our outlook as of today, February 21, 2011.
 As part of the agenda for today's call Karl will provide a broad overview of our 2010 performance, while Michael will summarize the details of our financial performance and provide our guidance for 2011. After our formal remarks we will be taking questions from both the live audience and for those of you who are on the conference call. If you are listening to the conference call via both a telephone and a webcast you will need to mute the webcast in order to ask a question due to the slight delay associated with the webcast. Now I'd like to hand the call over to Karl.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I would like to start by summarizing the key highlights of 2010 on slide four. First message is we generated a strong financial performance that was well balanced over all the metrics. We delivered organic revenue growth of 8%, benefiting naturally from the improvement of the global economy, strong market segments of our Life Science and Pharmaceutical businesses and continued strength in the emerging markets.
 Second, our Liquid Crystals business generated top performance, record performance, topping EUR1b for the first time and while returning to margins above 50%. Liquid Crystal is, and remains, one of the most attractive businesses in the chemical industries. We had an outstanding year yet we remain excited about its future potential. Third, we have transformed our Chemicals business with the completion of the Millipore transaction. The transaction bolstered our presence in the US while increasing our exposure to attractive segments of the biotechnology and the life science industry.
 The division generated an excellent year of performance which was particularly impressive, if I may say, given the complexity of the integration activities that were executed during the year. I am pleased to report, by the way, that our formal integration activities were terminated on February 1 and the new Merck Millipore organization is now fully in place.
 Merck Serono delivered solid improvements in its growth and profitability. Unfortunately, as you know, the performance was overshadowed by disappointments we experienced in our late-stage pipeline. And, finally, we continue to make important investments in innovation to drive future growth, opening of a research center in Billerica and this is for Merck Serono R&amp;D. Other R&amp;D centers, as you know, are located in Germany, Switzerland and China. We also opened a new Materials Research Center here in Darmstadt to support the Performance Materials division.
 I would like to look a little bit at the six years' history to make a point on our growth profile. Merck's organic revenue growth since 2005, if we adjusted for the financial crisis in 2009, it's basically a double-digit organic revenue growth since 2005. And this performance, for me, is a testament to our ability to drive innovation, establish leading market positions and also effectively manage our portfolio over time. By expanding our markets and continuing to invest in innovation I believe that we will continue to be an attractive growth Company with attractive growth rates also in future.
 Moving on to slide number six, which shows the sales by region, from a geographic perspective our top-line performance is becoming more and more balanced, with considerable growth coming from Asia, where we grew 60 -- 36% during the year. Of course, the six months' contribution of Millipore contributed considerably to the year-over-year growth we saw in North America during 2010, given their strong US presence. Finally, I would like to point out shortly that we have a considerably strong business in Latin America. This region continues to drive very strong performance, posting 15% during the year.
 Now let's move on to the divisions, first, slide number seven, Performance Materials. Performance Materials reported approximately EUR1.4b in revenue for the full year. This represents a top-line growth of approximately 38%, which included 27% organic revenue growth. The main driver of this performance was the Liquid Crystals business, whose record performance benefited from the strong uptake of our PS-VA products where we do have and enjoy a strong competitive position. We also saw increasing volumes for the other products in our Liquid Crystals Mixture portfolio and this led to a 52% return on sales margin, which was the highest level of profitability we have seen in this business for the past two years.
 Our Pigments and Cosmetics business generated good, steady performance throughout the year, delivering good revenue and good profit growth. I would be remiss without mentioning that the exceptional performance from Performance Material came during a year in which the division also completed a re-organization, established a new organization and divested the Crop BioScience business. The divestiture was completed in February 2011.
 I move on to slide number eight, and turning to the Merck Millipore division. The solid performance for both legacy Millipore and legacy Merck and the performance was driven by strong underlying trends in several of our markets. This includes benefits from healthy demand from the biotechnology customers, particularly as in 2010 new molecules entered the market and the division always sees strong incremental growth when a biologic enters a market where our products are part of the value chain.
 We also benefited from steady spending of academic customers. Many of those customers received incremental funds to invest into life science tools as a result of government stimulus initiatives. And, finally, after a difficult 2009 many of the divisions Lab customers returned to purchasing laboratory instruments which they deemed to be discretionary purchases in 2009.
 New product launches contributed materially to division's growth. Also the division generated a strong performance in emerging markets, such as China. And, finally, as I mentioned earlier, Merck Millipore successfully completed its formal integration activities as of February 1. And the fact that we have executed this integration and avoided any major disruption to our operations is a major accomplishment.
 We have retained key employees, such as Josh, put in place a new organization and launched a new brand identity for the division. And just to put this effort in perspective, we had 21 major integration teams involving hundreds of different employees that executed approximately 2,007 -- 2,700 discrete integration personnel on the nine and a half months.
 I would like to move on to slide number nine, Merck Serono. It was a mixed bag for the division in 2010. I think we did an excellent job driving solid growth and profitability in the division. However, on the other hand, we had setbacks in our R&amp;D pipeline that will adversely affect our future growth prospects. The division generated EUR5.75 (sic - see press release) in revenues during 2010, which included organic revenue growth of 5.1%. This growth translates into a core return on sales of 22.2% compared to 18.7% in 2009, which is a marked improvement.
 Clearly, an important event for the division during the year was the negative CHMP decision on Cladribine. We are awaiting the FDA decision on Cladribine with a date on February 28.
 On a positive note, we saw the approval of Erbitux in Japan for extended use for the first-line metastatic colorectal cancer treatment and the approval of Egrifta in the US for the reduction of excess abdominal fat in HIV-infected patients with lipodystrophy. We also successfully divested our Theramex business to Teva at the end of the year, which resulted in a EUR69m gain for the division.
 Slide number 10 shows the growth rates by product and therapeutic area. Neurodegenerative diseases, represented by Rebif, our highest-grossing product, grew 8.6% during 2010. This represents 4.5% organic growth -- revenue growth that was driven equally by Europe and the US. The 10.7% US growth benefited from net pricing gains and a favorable foreign exchange impact. Erbitux grew 18%, which is 15% organic growth. This growth was observed in all regions, driven especially by Japan and Latin America.
 The Cardiometabolic portfolio developed well, demonstrating again that our marketing capabilities in many markets of the world are going very strong. Finally, Saizen saw healthy double-digit growth of 18%, with top-selling markets in Europe and in North America. And growth in China was supported by the launch of Easypod, our electronic device of last year.
 Slide number 11; let me move into some more detailed comments on the development of our Neurodegenerative disease franchise, first, Rebif. We are working on formulation enhancements, including the serum-free formulation of Rebif RNF, meanwhile launched in worldwide more than 40 countries. And furthermore we initiated Phase I studies for the long-acting interferons, and the idea there is, obviously, to reduce the frequency of injections.
 Second, we extended the scope of our innovative injection devices with the launch of RebiDose, a single-use, pre-filled device for a quick and simple injection. We continued to roll out this first and only electronic injection device of its kind for multiple sclerosis, RebiSmart, to now more than 20 markets including Canada and many European countries. And, third, label extensions will strengthen the Rebif franchise.
 We completed the two-year Phase III study, REFLEX, in October 2010, and presented already the top-line results. The trial, involving more than 500 patients with a clinically-isolated syndrome, met its primary endpoint, demonstrating that Rebif significantly delays conversion to a clinically-defined multiple sclerosis. Full results will be presented at an upcoming scientific meeting. We intend to submit these data to European authorities in mid 2011.
 One of the most common questions, of course, we receive regards the future of Rebif and the MS franchise. Obviously, we need to wait for the final regulatory decision on Cladribine tablets in the US before we can comment fully on the future strategy for Rebif. But regardless of the decision in the US we are focused on continuing to serve the current Rebif patient base and sustain Rebif's position as the leading interferon of the choice -- of choice in the industry.
 Page 12, a bit more on Rebif. Having said this, of course there is no question that the marketing dynamics in the MS market are beginning to change and will become more challenging over the long term. We are clearly facing increasing competition from [Gollimord] now in an already highly-competitive environment. Price pressure will continue due to various healthcare reforms, especially in Europe.
 We expect Rebif will benefit from strong organic sales growth in the emerging markets and the benefits of global life-cycle management activities, as well as a strong position in the US. However, we do not expect that these dynamics will be able to fully offset pressures that we are going to see in the market. As a result, we expect that it will be challenging to drive organic growth for Rebif in 2011 and that we are rather likely to see a flat performance excluding effects of currency.
 On page 13 you see an update of the regulatory status of Cladribine. The first two approvals, as you know, were given in July 2010 in Russia and Australia followed in September, but tablets are available under the trade name Movectro in both countries since the end of 2010. In January 2011 CHMP confirmed its initial negative opinion issued in September 2010. We decided then to withdraw the marketing authorization application for Cladribine in the European Union.
 A potential resubmission would require new clinical data and we will consider it after new data become available. We are committed to complete our ongoing studies with Cladribine. Top-line results from CLARITY EXTENSION and ORACLE trials will be available by the end of this year and from the ONWARD study in the first half of 2012.
 Moving on to Oncology, I start with the highlights for Erbitux. One of the highlights I mentioned already, the granting of approval by Japan's authority for the use of Erbitux in first-line treatment for metastatic colorectal cancer in KRAS wild-type patients, which was given to us in March 2010. Japan, as you know, is a very important market for us and colorectal cancer is the most common cancer among women, the second amongst men, with approximately 96,000 new cases every year.
 The latest survival data from OPUS and CRYSTAL studies using extended chemotherapies respectively demonstrate that early tumor shrinkage with Erbitux correlates with long-term survival for the patient.
 The new analysis from Phase III CRYSTAL studies showed an outstanding medium (sic) overall survival of 28.3 months for colorectal cancer patients. With KRAS wild-type tumors, we experienced early tumor shrinkage during the first-line Erbitux-based treatment. We completed the recruitment of the Phase III study, EXPAND, in patients with advanced and previously untreated gastric cancer at the beginning of this year. The primary objective is to determine the benefits of Erbitux in terms of progression-free survival.
 Slide 15, more stories on Erbitux. We presented new data of the Phase II trial, BALI-1, for treatment of metastatic triple-negative breast cancer in December 2010, showing that Erbitux improved overall survival with a median of 12.9 versus 9.4 months. This improvement was not statistically significant. Progression-free survival improved significantly.
 The personalized treatment approach, which, as you know, is the guidance -- guiding principle in our strategy in Oncology, is widely accepted in the medical community and the number of service demonstrate that. A global survey showed that 66% of colorectal cancer patients are being tested for KRAS, indicating the preference for targeted treatments. And, moreover, one survey has shown that Erbitux is used as a first-line treatment in almost 60% of patients with recurrent and metastatic head and neck cancer. A second study revealed that 36% of locally advanced head and neck cancer patients are treated with Erbitux.
 Erbitux has become a standard of care in the treatment of both indications, colorectal as well as head and neck cancer. It is one of our main growth drivers looking forward. We expect Erbitux to continue its year-on-year growth trend with the existing indications. Furthermore, we will fuel this growth; number one, by increasing penetration rates, especially in first-line colorectal as well as in the recurrent and metastatic head and neck treatments; second, by growing geographically, especially Japan and emerging markets; and, third, we intend to broaden our tumor indications for the drugs -- for the drug.
 Very briefly on 16, the status of the two other late-stage ongoing trials; I think you are well aware where we are going. We resumed our Stimuvax clinical program in lung cancer in June 2010 following the FDA's decision to lift the clinical hold of the START trial. We closed in July the study, STRIDE, Phase III as well, in woman -- in women with advanced breast cancer. We presented good Phase II long-term follow-up data for Cilengitide for the treatment in glioblastoma, last year's ASCO, and we showed that after one year 37% of patients were still alive and the corresponding historic control is 20%.
 Some comments on slide 17 for the pipeline. In 2010 we stopped one -- some Phase I and II projects. The most new one -- or the most recent one is the discontinuation of one of the three groups of the Phase II/III trial April SLE study in Atacicept. The decision was taken following a recommendation of the Independent Data Monitoring Committee. They determined that the risk/benefit profile for the patients receiving the higher dose of Atacicept was unfavorable. The study continues as a two-armed study between the lower Atacicept and placebo.
 We announced the signing of a worldwide research and development agreement with Sanofi-Aventis. We collaborate in two Phase I trials, investigating novel therapy combinations of specific Sanofi-Aventis compounds and Merck Serono's MEK inhibitor to treat patients with various solid tumors. It's important to mention that nearly each of our projects in the portfolio is accompanied by our biomarker research activity. This is based on our positive experience with KRAS.
 Let me conclude this part on Merck Serono by stressing that we are confident to safeguard and to grow the business despite recent setbacks. We continue to see growth potential in the industry and, for us especially, in the next years for -- in this year for Erbitux and the emerging markets.
 Consumer Healthcare on page 18, disappointing, not satisfactory, EUR472m in revenues and deterioration of profitability. We experienced several operational and management challenges during the year. That being said, we expect the division's performance will improve markedly in 2011, and that comes from three priorities; number one, stabilizing and restoring market share in the Seven Seas brand; second, drive growth in Mexico with a very focused investment on key brands and store placement; and, third, reinvigoration of the growth of the division in China.
 So much to the divisions, but I would like to now to have an overall look with you on page 19 on the portfolio changes we did over the last year. I believe that few companies have been as active as Merck recently in reshaping their portfolio over the last five years. In this time we have sold our Generic business, Distribution business, done two transforming acquisitions in Serono and Millipore and completed numerous other small divestitures, such as, recently, Crop BioScience in February 2011 and Theramex at the end of last year. The net effect of all of that is that we now have a portfolio that we believe will enable us to continue to drive attractive financial performance in the future.
 And also with a full year of Millipore included in 2011 you can see how we --have much more balance we have in the business, particularly as it relates to our core operating result. The amount of revenue generated from Chemicals will increase from 25% to just under 40%, while the percent of our core operating result derived from Chemicals will increase from 24% to just over 40% in 2011. And this portfolio shift is about much more than diversifying risk.
 We have built new capabilities in the biotechnology and life science market, driven innovation in markets where we are now a market leader and we have the potential to capitalize on synergies between our various divisions over the next two years. And this is one of the reasons why I am excited about the Company's future.
 I would like to outline, on page 20, some of the key priorities that I am focused on as we look ahead to 2011. First, three of the five members of our executive team will be new in 2011. I list them here on this slide, even with pictures, I believe. Of course, we will need to come together as a leadership team to determine what initiatives we need to put in place to drive higher levels of growth and profitability in the business over the next five to seven years. I ask for your patient -- patience when it comes to revealing those plans.
 Next, we need to deliver on the value of the Millipore transaction and continue to establish Merck as a leader in the life science tools market. We see a number of important sales and R&amp;D synergies that we are in the process of working to capture. We also will finish the process of driving out cost of the combined organization to deliver on the EUR75m cost synergy target that we shared with you at the time of the completion of the transaction.
 Next, we need to focus on optimizing key franchises in Merck Serono and continue the momentum that we have experienced in emerging markets. And, finally, in January I communicated with many of our sell-side analysts that we recognize that we need to improve investor relations and investor-related communication. I am personally going to be involved in this effort and it's very high on my priority list for 2011.
 I would like to close my section of the presentation by stating that 2010 was, in many ways, a historic year for Merck. It was a year in which we added new capabilities through a [transformal] acquisition, effectively managed our portfolio and strengthened the Company in a number of important ways. It was also a year of change. We are in the process of making changes to our executive management team and we have pledged to improve our overall communication with capital markets.
 Many of these changes, particularly around our operational initiatives, will take some time to come together. Some of the changes around communication, including the format in which we provide 2011 guidance, will be different than what we have done in the past.
 I realize that for many of you on the sell-side this will make your jobs of modeling our financial performance slightly more difficult. But I would stress that we have tried to provide more focus on the business drivers and the upside opportunities and downside risks that the Company faces. All of this is done with the single -- singular purpose of putting together a plan that we can deliver on that accurately reflects the current visibility we have in the business.
 With that, I would now like to hand over to Michael who will take you through the financials in more detail. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Karl. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I am proud to present the financial details of a year in which we delivered good growth in the top and bottom lines and fully recovered from the global recession in 2008 and 2009. I will emphasize most of my comments and explanations on our performance for the full-year 2010, rather than just our Q4 results, as the full-year view correlates better with the time horizon of our full-year guidance. Unless otherwise stated, growth rates are based on a year-over-year comparison of the figures of 2010 versus 2009.
 I would like to begin with the full-year P&amp;L for the Merck Group, as outlined on slide 22. The reported increase of 20% in total revenues reflects 7.9% organic growth, a 3.7% favorable benefit from changes in foreign currencies and an 8.4% benefit from the acquisition of Millipore. As a reminder, we closed the transaction on July 14 and, consequently, consolidated Millipore for the first time in the third quarter last year, so the effect is six out of 12 months while in the last quarter it will be three -- it was three of three months.
 From a regional perspective, we reported 11% sales growth in Europe, of which 6.9% stemmed from the Millipore acquisition. Sales in North America increased by 31%, with Millipore contributing 21%. In Asia we saw sales increasing by 37%, helped by 8.3% from the Millipore acquisition. Finally, Latin American sales grew by 15%, supported by 2.6% growth from Millipore. This gives you an indication of what we can do on the top-line synergies. We profited very much in the US, where we are weak and Millipore was strong. We are both strong in Asia and we are strong in Latin America, where Millipore was not so strong.
 Royalties came in at prior-year's level, or slightly above EUR360m. I would like to iterate that we expect royalties to stay roughly flat for the next two years, followed by a decline of about 20% until 2014 and being stable then again from 2015 onwards. Sales increased 21% year over year, to EUR8.93b, of which organic growth contributed 8.5% and changes in foreign exchange 3.7%. The production costs increased 17.5%. This includes EUR86m from the step up of inventories from Millipore. Including this one-off charge, production costs would have been EUR2.3b, or 13% higher compared to 2009.
 SG&amp;A rose 17%, to EUR3.58b, including a negative effect of EUR87m of transaction and integration costs for the Millipore acquisition. You may remember that, previously, transaction costs were added to the purchase price and capitalized; that is no longer possible any more, so they come under integration costs. Stripping Millipore's contribution out, SG&amp;A would have been up by 7.5%. Going into more detail, marketing and selling expenses increased to EUR2.23b, or 20%, versus last year, out of which 8.5% was acquisition-related. Administration costs were up 13%, including 7% contribution from Millipore.
 The Group's R&amp;D spending rose moderately by 3.9%, to about EUR1.4b. Slightly lower R&amp;D costs in our Pharma businesses were more than offset by higher R&amp;D investments into our Chemicals business, reflecting our strategy to focus on innovations as a growth engine for both Performance Materials and Merck Millipore. For the next two years, we intend to keep the Group's R&amp;D spending rate at a level of 15% of total revenues.
 Finally, amortization costs increased by 24%, to EUR819m. As a reminder, around EUR570m of the costs are related to ongoing amortization of the purchase price allocation for Merck Serono's intangible assets. Additionally, the consolidation of Millipore leads to irregular amortization of intangible assets at a level of EUR190m per year, resulting in EUR96m for the second half of 2010.
 And, finally, the impairment of our pipeline drug, Safinamide, of EUR134m, which we forecasted already in July, is also included in this P&amp;L line. Adjusted for these amortization charges and one-off costs related to the acquisition of Millipore, the Group's underlying profitability, expressed as core operating result, improved 62%, to EUR2.1b, yielding a core return on revenues of 22.6%, up almost 600 basis points compared to 2009.
 Moving to a brief summary to the Merck Group's performance during the fourth quarter, we can see that the -- on slide 23, that the revenues of EUR2.55b represented 25% growth. This growth reflects a [20%] gain from acquisition, so three months out of three is 16%, six months out of 12 was 8%, as you remember, from acquisitions, and 4.8% for the benefit from changes in foreign exchange rates.
 Our operating result of EUR129m more than doubled from 2009, despite higher amortization costs from the Safinamide impairment. This was due to higher revenues and lower spending if we adjust for the costs of the Millipore transaction. Our core ROS increased by 840 basis points and benefited from the year-over-year comparison due to the weak level of profitability in Q4 2009.
 Moving to slide 24, exceptional charges in 2010 seem to be a minor at first sight, with minus EUR0.8m on a net basis. However, this line includes two significant events that were booked at the last quarter but that are balancing each other out. On the one hand, the sales of Theramex to Teva Pharmaceutical Industries had a positive P&amp;L impact of EUR69m. On the other hand, as we announced in December, the settlement of the claim of the US Department of Justice against our former Generics affiliate, Dey, triggered a payment of EUR215m. Since we started to book provisions for that settlement all the way back to 2007, it only negatively affected our P&amp;L by EUR67m in Q4.
 With this payment, the vast majority of claims against Dey are settled and the remaining provisions are immaterial since they are in the range of low double-digit million euros. The provision should cover all future costs for some still unsettled minor claims. Of course, this statement only applies to the outstanding lawsuit that we are aware of today. Should additional losses be brought forth we could see higher costs in the future.
 In 2010, the financial result increased 87%, to EUR252m, driven by higher interest costs following the EUR3.2b bond issue in March to finance the acquisition of Millipore. As a reminder, we were able to chase the bonds in three tranches with maturities of two, five and 10 years at very favorable conditions, resulting in additional interest costs of around EUR30m per quarter. In addition, financing fees of EUR10m for the bridge financing relating to the Millipore transaction weighted in the 2010 financial result.
 For the full year we saw a doubling of the income tax, to EUR220m, and an underlying tax rate of 25.3%. This compares to an unusually low tax rate of 21.6% in 2009, when we re-billed deferred tax assets, some of which had been eliminated in 2008. In addition, this increased tax rate is the result of the consolidation of Millipore and resembles the tax rate increase when we first consolidated Serono.
 At the time, the increase lasted a year, and I don't think that this time it will last much longer. As part of the integration we will restructure some of Millipore's tax holdings to help optimize our tax rate going forward. And if you would ask me what proxy to take for this year's tax rate, I would estimate somewhere between 25% and 26%.
 On the bottom line, higher revenues and lower costs increased net income to EUR632m, or EUR2.91 per share, up 73% compared to 2009. Adjusted for acquisition-related costs from Serono and Millipore the Group's core earnings per share rose by 52%, to EUR6.73.
 I would just like to make a very brief remark to the slightly distorted picture of Q4, where the operating result rose threefold; the EBIT by 50%; the profit before tax by 30%; and the profit after tax declined by 20%. The reason for this is that the exceptionals which influence the EBIT was zero in this quarter and positive by EUR40m in the previous-year quarter, as we released a provision that we had billed for the withdrawal of our psoriasis drug. On the level of profit before tax, we had a financial result which was twice as high as last year.
 And on the profit after tax, we had the effect on the tax rate, which I explained, which all took place in the third quarter last year, where we compare a EUR23m charge in Q4 of 2010 with a EUR5m credit in the last quarter of 2009, which then leads to the picture that we have; a minus 20% on the bottom line.
 This leads me to the financial performance of our four divisions, and I will start with Performance Materials, with the result presented on slide 25 for the full year. The division generated revenues of EUR1.38b, up 38%, of which 10% came from currency tailwinds. Total revenues of Liquid Crystals were also up 38% as well and crossed the EUR1b mark for the first time ever.
 On the one hand, this strong increase is reflecting last year's exceptionally weak Pigment and Liquid Crystals business, which suffered significantly from the dropping demand for [displays, cars] and cosmetics. However, on the other hand, it also shows our excellent positions in these dynamic markets, which enabled us to fully play out our leadership in innovation technologies and product quality against the backdrop of increasing demand from our customers.
 Consequently, the division's operating result jumped by 166%, to EUR580m, an increase of more than EUR360m. Out of this, Liquid Crystals alone contributed with an increase of EUR300m, driven by a healthy demand for our flagship technology PS-VA; stronger volumes; and higher capacity utilization; as well as a favorable foreign exchange development. This enabled us to nearly double our return on revenues to 42%, up from 22% we had in 2009. With a return on revenues of 52% Liquid Crystals' profitability returned to pre-crisis levels. In line with this strong performance the underlying free cash flow increased to EUR549m, up 81% compared to full-year 2009.
 Now turning briefly to the fourth-quarter results of Performance Materials, on slide 26, we report total revenues of EUR322.1m. This represented growth of 19%, which included a 14% positive benefit from changes in foreign exchange and 15% (sic - see presentation) organic revenue growth. We reported a 40.5% return on sales for the quarter, which included an impressive 54% return on sales for our Liquid Crystal business.
 On slide 27 I show the effect of the reorganization of the Performance Materials on the division's financials. I wanted to highlight the consideration that you will need to make when conducting a growth analysis in 2011. On the left-hand side of the slide I show the 2010 actual results for Performance Materials' revenues. The division will gain a Cosmetic Actives business that was previously part of the Merck Millipore portfolio. As a result, Performance Materials' 2010 adjusted revenues will increase by EUR68m, to EUR1.45b.
 The division's adjusted return on sales for 2010, which are shown on the right-hand side of the slide, will be 40%. When we provide guidance in a few minutes on the Performance Materials division, the forecasted growth will be off the 2010 adjusted revenue of EUR1.45b.
 Another key consideration when you consider Performance Materials in 2011 is the sale of the Crop BioScience business, which closed earlier this month. In 2010 we generated revenues of EUR46m and an operating result of [EUR16m] in this business. These results will be in our 2010 days, but will not repeat in 2011, which will affect the comparability of these results.
 With Cosmetic Actives entering Performance Materials, Merck Millipore's revenues are adjusted down to EUR1.61b from EUR1.68b we reported in 2010. As a result, Merck Millipore's adjusted operating result in 2010 will be EUR48m. Just like Performance Materials, the revenue growth guidance that I will provide to you on Merck Millipore will be off of the adjusted revenue figure of EUR1.61b.
 Now moving to Merck Millipore's full-year results, on slide 28, total revenues grew by 81%, to EUR1.68b. This performance reflected 69% from the Millipore acquisition, organic growth of 56% (sic - see presentation) and a 6% positive benefit from changes in foreign exchange rates. Marketing and selling, as well as R&amp;D, were up primarily as a result of the effect caused by the acquisition. With a core operating result of EUR313m the division achieved a core return on revenues of 18.6%, an improvement of more than 700 basis points, driven by stronger volumes in all businesses as well as a higher profitability for Millipore's business. As a result, the underlying free cash flow more than doubled, to EUR264m.
 I show Merck Millipore's Q4 financial performance on slide 29. The division generated 6.8% organic revenue growth in the quarter, which reflects the performance of legacy Merck. The division generated exceptional year-over-year improvements in both core operating result and underlying free cash flow in the quarter.
 Now turning to the full-year performance of Merck Serono, on slide 30, Merck Serono increased total revenues by 7.6%, to EUR5.75b, over 2010 -- for 2010, driven by a 5.1% organic growth. Sales increased by more than 8%, primarily driven by the sales of our top products, especially Rebif and Erbitux. All regions contributed to the strong sales increase. Europe, which represents one half of Merck Serono's sales, grew by only 2.9%, consistent with the challenging market dynamics of the region.
 Emerging markets continued to represent an important growth region and was a substantial driver for our growth during the year. Sales in Latin America increased by 14%. This growth included a 3% headwind from currency. Finally, sales in Asia, Africa and Australasia region increased 20%, to EUR932m, primarily due to the growth of Erbitux in the region.
 Royalty and commission income decreased by 2%, to EUR345m, primarily due to the lower sales of Puregon, as patents expired in certain countries. Our gross margin went up by 6.9%, to EUR4.79b, due to a disappropriate (sic) generate increase in our production costs. These costs included start-up expenses for the new large-scale biotech production center in Switzerland of around EUR25m. Furthermore, a strong price cut in some EU countries affected our gross margin. The 10% boost in marketing and selling expenses is due to strong exchange rate effects and investments in new products, namely, Cladribine tablets and Egrifta, and emerging markets such as China, where we built up the field force.
 The 13% jump in royalty, license and commission expenses is a result of higher Erbitux sales in Japan and Rebif sales in the US. The more than 10% increase in amortization of intangible assets is driven by the just-explained impairment of Safinamide. Our R&amp;D costs slightly decreased, to EUR1.17b, representing, again, our target of 20% of Merck Serono's revenues. The decrease is partly a result of the delay of the project Stimuvax and Cladribine tablets.
 Higher marketing and selling expenses were offset by the improvement in gross margin and lower important influences compared to 2009, which led to a 28% jump of our core operating result, to EUR1.28b. Our core return on revenues increased accordingly, to 22.2%. The 51% increase of underlying free cash flow was mainly the result of higher profitability of the division.
 I'd like, kindly, to remind you that with the Theramex transaction we completed at the end of the year we have sold EUR84m of revenue and EUR9.5m of operating result based on 2010 figures. Please keep this in mind when you start comparing Merck Serono's performance throughout 2011 with the prior-year's numbers.
 Now some comments on the Q4 performance of Merck Serono, on slide 31. The division posted a fine quarter of financial performance, posting EUR1.5b in revenues, which reflected 4.6% organic revenue growth. The approximately 10% (sic - see presentation) decrease of royalty and commission income is a result of lower income from Puregon predominantly due to the mentioned patent expirations. The 2.5% growth of the gross margin is below revenue growth, due to healthcare reform adversely lowering prices and lower gross margin as a result of the negative effects of adjusting for year-end plant cost variances.
 Marketing and selling expenses were up 17.1%, driven by higher Erbitux sales, especially in Japan. And Rebif in the US led to a 7% increase in commission and royalty expenses. As already said before and indicated at our last conference call, we had to impair Safinamide, our pipeline product to treat Parkinson's disease. The approximately 33% increase in amortization of intangible assets is driven by this write-off of Safinamide, of EUR134m, which now results in a residual value of Safinamide of EUR63m. The impairment was triggered by the results of the Phase III extension study, 018, which led to an updated assessment of the market potential.
 In addition, the new valuation covers a delay in the project as well as an increase in R&amp;D costs driven by increased regulatory requirements. This impairment is reflected within our operating result, but did not affect our core result, as the P&amp;L line 'amortization of intangible assets' relate to the purchase of Serono. We more than doubled the core operating result, to EUR298m, with a core return on sales of almost 20%. Consequently, underlying free cash flow rose by 141%, to nearly EUR450m.
 On slide 32 we present the full-year key financials of the Consumer Healthcare division for 2010. We generated revenues of EUR472m, with organic growth of 2.6% worldwide, exceeding average market growth in many countries. Our top five strategic brands posted double-digit sales increases. Marketing and selling rose by 11% and R&amp;D by almost 28%, as the division continued to implement its strategy on focusing on strategic brands.
 The substantial decline in operating result, by 71%, was due to the following effects. We undertook extensive restructuring in China in the second half of 2010 as a result of a too-quick expansion outside the four major cities. The UK was hit by a fire in May 2010 that destroyed a warehouse containing Seven Seas nutritional supplements, which led to respective bottom-line effects.
 Slide 33 shows the fourth-quarter performance of Consumer Healthcare. I would like to particularly highlight the good underlying free cash flow. Despite a decline in lower revenues and operating result the division saw a very strong cash delivery in Q4, driven by favorable changes in working capital.
 This leads me to the key balance sheet data. The acquisition of Millipore had a significant impact on our balance sheet, which you can see on slide 34. Total assets increased by about EUR5.7b, to EUR22.4b. Out of this increase, EUR4.9b are stemming from increased intangible assets mainly from the consolidation of Millipore.
 Moving to the Group's cash flows, on slide 34 (sic), you see that we nearly doubled the underlying free cash flow, from EUR852m in 2009 to EUR1.67b in 2010. This was supported by EUR265m higher profit after tax and EUR254m higher depreciation and amortization, which is included in the profit after tax but having no cash effect.
 We have capital expenditures lower by EUR71m. This lower CapEx was related to the completion of a number of major projects, including our plant in Vevey and our research center in Billerica, Massachusetts. Going forward we expect CapEx to stay at a level of around EUR400m per year. Changes in working capital show a negative shift of EUR57m, driven by higher accounts receivable, following the growth of our business and the sluggish payment in some countries in Southern Europe.
 The payment of the purchase price for Millipore and the transaction-related costs, totaling EUR4.94b, (sic - see presentation) are summarized in the line 'others', as well as payments of EUR241m for the settlement of terminal litigation. Of these EUR241m, EUR115m relate to the settlement with the US Department of Justice regarding Dey, as announced in December last year.
 On the other hand, we received EUR10m already from the sale of Theramex and expect the remainder, of EUR255m, to come during the actual quarter. Actually, it has already arrived. Further, we collected significant payments from Venezuela, totaling around EUR90m, leaving receivables of about EUR40m from that region outstanding by the end of 2010. In line with that, we reversed the provision, from minus EUR70m by the end of 2009, to EUR20m. Finally, Greece started first payments with government bonds on total outstanding receivables of around EUR100m.
 An important aspect of our financial performance is the reduction of net financial debt, and you can see that on our last slide before I come to the guidance. And you see that we have reduced, since July 31, 2010, our net financial debt by EUR655m, and this includes the payment of more than EUR200m in the Dey case, so without the Dey it would have been far more than EUR800m.
 This leads me to the guidance. The guidance for 2011 is shown on slide 37. As we enter the year we are confident in our ability to continue to deliver a solid financial performance. However, we have to acknowledge that operational planning for our upcoming year is much more of a challenge than usual, given the difficulty in predicting the outcomes of regulatory decisions and the impact from changing market dynamics.
 For example, all of you are aware the PDUFA date of Cladribine tablets, which is only one week away, obviously, it is impossible to determine today whether Cladribine tables will be approved or further delayed. Given the potential of Cladribine tablets, the approval, or lack thereof, would have a substantial impact on our anticipated financials for 2011.
 Outside of Pharma, another challenge that we consistently face is our Liquid Crystals business, where we typically have six weeks of forward visibility and a limited customer base that can quickly adjust its production due to the [complexity] of the consumer electronics industry. Predicting the impact of competitive and customer actions in this market is also an ongoing challenge.
 As a result of these factors we have tried to put forth a forecast that accurately reflects both the upside potential and downside risk we see in the business. We have also adapted the format of our guidance and return to a wider guidance range to accurately reflect our current visibility and put us in a stronger position to deliver on the expectations that we set.
 Let me begin with a discussion of the top-line performance of the Merck Group and our four divisions. We expect Group revenues to grow between 13% and 18% in 2011, which would result in 35% to 45% growth in our operating result. This performance would include a full year of impact from the Millipore transaction, which closed in the middle of last year. We expect the core ROS of the Group to range between 22% and 23% during 2011.
 I would like to stress that all of these figures assume the approval of Cladribine tablets and the corresponding effect on the top line and expenses. This assumption is no indication for our optimism regarding the outcome of the PDUFA date. It is neither an indication for the approval or not, or a delay or not, or a rejection or not.
 From a divisional perspective we expect that Merck Serono will grow between 5% and 10%. This guidance again assumes an approval for Cladribine tablets in United States, against the background that I mentioned. We have also assumed that incremental costs from the Cladribine tablets launch offset the impact from the higher revenues. Should we fail to get an approval in the US this year we expect that Merck Serono will grow between 1% and 6% in 2011.
 In terms of the underlying business we have made several other key assumption for important drivers of the Merck Serono's 2011 performance. We have previously acknowledged that our prospects for Rebif will vary, depending on whether or not we receive an approval for Cladribine tablets. What I can tell you today is that, independent of the FDA's decision, we expect that the Rebif franchise will come under pressure in 2011 and beyond from the changing market dynamics in the multiple sclerosis market.
 Our 2011 forecast assumes that the product will show a small amount of growth, but will fall from the growth rate we delivered in 2010. Our strategy will continue to be on sustaining the current patient base for Rebif and reinforcing its position as the leading interferon of choice on the market. We will also develop and continue to improve our devices, which are critical for the convenience and differentiation of Rebif. We have assumed double-digit annual growth for Erbitux, driven by deeper market penetration in Europe, Japan and Emerging Markets.
 Finally, we have assumed that we will sustain the high growth rates that we experienced this year in emerging markets. From a profitability perspective we expect to growth Merck Serono's core operating result in 2011, irrespective of the approval of Cladribine tablets. Currently, we expect growth in the mid to high single digit. However, our core ROS would likely be lower than the 22% we delivered in 2010.
 Now, turning to Performance Materials, I showed you the adjusted 2010 revenues and core operating result for the division earlier in the presentation. The following growth rates are off of these adjusted results and are not based on our 2010 actual performance.
 We expect that Performance Materials will generate between 2% and 7% growth in 2011. This growth assumes solid performance in Pigments, similar to what we saw last year. It also assumes that the division is able to increase its overall market share in Liquid Crystals. Our desire to increase our share is based on protecting our market leadership, increasing our customer intimacy and laying the foundation for new technologies to be adopted by our customers in the future.
 We expect to see increased competition in the PS-VA market during 2011, but we believe the overall impact on our share and pricing in the PS-VA market will be modest. Also we have slightly more top-line currency exposure in this segment of the business due to the limited number of Liquid Crystal customers in Asia. Like we do in any other year, we will work to offset this exposure through an effective hedging strategy.
 From a profitability perspective we expect the operating result of Performance Materials will be roughly flat during 2011. This assumes that we continue to invest heavily in R&amp;D to drive the next generation of Liquid Crystals product. It also assumes a negative mix effect in Liquid Crystals as we gain share in areas like VA and IPS.
 For Consumer Healthcare we expect sales growth of 7% to 12% in 2011. We expect the division to generate an operating result of two to three times' higher than what it's experienced in 2010. This improvement assumes a continued global economy recovery and a healthy return from the investments we have made in our strategic brands over the past several years.
 Finally, turning to Merck Millipore, we expect the division to grow 51% to 56%, off of the adjusted revenues of EUR1.61b during the coming year. This level of growth assumes that the division grows faster than the overall life science tools market.
 Other key assumption for the growth of the divisions include; growth in Asia drives a significant portion of the division's growth; demand from biotech customers will remain strong while the division's Pharma customers will remain under pressure to reduce costs. We expect Merck Millipore to report significantly higher operating result growth of 31% to 36%. This assumes that we capture at least half of our target cost-saving synergy of EUR75m during 2011.
 And this is all from my side. Thank you very much for your attention and I'll pass back to Joshua, to lead the question and answer session.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. We will begin the Q&amp;A session, taking several questions from the live audience before turning to the conference call. Yes, Andrew?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, it's Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley. Two questions, please. Dr. Kley, you have indicated that both large and small shareholders have not been happy with the recent share performance of Merck over coming years -- over previous years, and everything is potentially up for consideration.
 I'm just perplexed by the decision to invest another $65m in a research site near Boston, together with the other three you have, given the lack of anything really coming out of Merck research labs for decades, one could argue. Perhaps you could outline that strategy and whether we could see some reversal of the historic investment pattern?
 The second question is to Dr. Becker. Obviously, the Department of Justice is on enforcement drive right now for mis-selling of drugs in the US. I note that the DoJ has intervened in what looks like a key [tam] case, a whistle-blower case, in terms of marketing of products in the US market with your subsidiary. Perhaps you could outline whether you have taken any provisions for this and give any detail on the timing of a resolution and potential likely scale of the impact on the balance sheet?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So maybe if we -- we're going to collect a couple of questions and answer them all at once. So we'll take a couple more questions. Yes, Richard?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Vosser,  JP Morgan - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, thanks, Richard Vosser from JP Morgan. Three questions, please. The first is on the Liquid Crystals business. I just wondered if you could give us some more help on the market dynamics. What proportion of the growth, or what proportion of the panels were sold in China, Japan, the US and Europe in 2010 and how you see that geographic variation. What you see the growth rates in those markets varying in 2011 and what contribution each market has to the 11% volume growth that I think is mentioned in your Annual Report?
 The second question is on Stimuvax. And I just wanted to ask about the interim analysis and confirm whether that was just a safety look, whether you have looked at futility from an efficacy point of view yet in that analysis or for other analyses, and if you could give us an idea on whether there are further interim analyses before the final data readout in '12 at some point?
 And the final question; I just wanted to ask on the growth rates of Merck Serono, so the Merck Serono growth ex-Cladribine at 1% to 6%. You have mentioned, briefly how you -- what growth drivers you see, but I do see quite a few headwinds as well; EU pricing; the Theramex, as you said; Rebif been slightly growing; and the Pharma market, perhaps, from some other companies that have reported really at zero growth for 2011. So I was just wondering how you can get to the top end of that guidance; if you could give us some more color there that would be very useful. Thanks very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I will start. Andrew, I do not completely share your view that nothing has come out, but we can agree that little has come out of the Merck pipeline over the last years and maybe one of the reasons is that we were not part of a network in the US. And when Bernd Kirschbaum took over part of the basic analysis was that, amongst other measures, like re-organization, like people change -- we had a number of personnel changes over the last months and years and some other aspects. One of the aspects was we have to be -- if you want to play in an orchestra you have to be where the music is playing.
 And a good deal of the music is playing in the US and we have not been able, with our organization up to recently, to tap those resources in this environment sufficiently. So the decision to invest in the US, obviously, is not a decision today and -- yesterday and done toady, but part of a long-term plan and gives us the access to networks we have not been able to tap before. So I expect, in a long-term strategy, considerable benefits from this investment.
 Second question from Andy was to you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, there is a litigation in the US which has been settled, the payment is still outstanding and, therefore, it will not affect the balance sheet in 2011. It has affected the balance sheet in 2010.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It did affect it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It did. We have billed a provision.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 But you're saying this is separate from Dey?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's separate from Dey, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And can you say what the provision was that you took for this?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Inaudible) it was middle double digit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then there was a question on the different geographic footprint in the Liquid Crystal markets. Obviously, China is still a relatively small segment in the market. As you probably have read, many of the companies have announced investments in a number of factories, a number of plants. The major part of that still has to go on stream, so still, today, and also 2011, China will not be a major contributor to what happens in the Liquid Crystal business. The major part is -- in the past is played in Korea and Taiwan, which will also remain the major source of revenue and the major consumer of materials, basically, of all materials, from TN, TFF, IPS, VA, PS-VA.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Vosser,  JP Morgan - Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Could I --?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And in Japan we see growth returning. So in terms of quantity I believe Japan will deliver more than we have seen in the last two years.
 On numbers in revenues and profits on countries we have never disclosed and ask for your understanding that we will continue not to disclose numbers and values.
 For Stimuvax I pass on to Bernd.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Kirschbaum,  Merck Serono - Head, R&amp;D   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, on Stimuvax you will not expect me to speculate on interim allowances, but we, of course, have agreements with the FDA. And what I can say, after the lift of the clinical hold, the recruitment into the study picked up very quickly. And we have actually reached now recruitment rates that are above what we had before the clinical hold, which at least tells you the interest -- the continued interest of patients and investigators in the drug.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard, does that answer all your questions?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Then, no, there is one last question, which was on the Merck Serono growth; what do we have to do despite the headwinds?
 I believe that in pointing out the qualitative aspects how the business would develop, I have looked at opportunities and headwinds, and I mentioned explicitly the European pricing. The problem with European pricing is you never know who is hit by what, and when, and where, so it is hard to figure into your planning the next tax by any given European Health Minister. So if they fail to hit us, we could reach the 6%. If they would hit us, we could also reach the 1%. And that is why we enter with a corridor onto the discussion.
 On Rebif I think I was quite explicit in saying that I don't expect a big deal of growth in 2011, but rather expect a stable development, and I gave also the reasons why that. So the headwinds are factored in. If the headwinds are all blowing, we should end at 1%. If they fail, we should end at 6%. And the probability that we are in between is higher than being at 1% or at 6%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would like to add something to the US litigation. Some doubt has crept into my mind whether it did affect the 2010 balance sheet. It didn't affect the 2010 balance sheet; the provision was already billed in 2009. So the mid single-digit -- mid double-digit EUR50m round provision we billed in December 2009 already.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Richard Vosser,  JP Morgan - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is -- it's settled, yes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's now settled. And there's a couple of euros spare and the payment will be next year. So it's settled at a lower price -- at a lower amount, but the provision was not billed in 2010; it was built in 2009.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, Marietta.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Marietta Miemietz,  Societe Generale - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Marietta Miemietz, Societe Generale. My first question is for Mr. Kirschbaum. The Erbitux gastric cancer expanse study; can you give us any idea as to when you would expect it to read out? Looking at clinicaltrials.gov it looks like we should expect that late this year, early next year, and I'm just wondering why would it take so long for such an aggressive cancer to yield a PFS benefit.
 Second question, staying on Pharma, can you just walk us through some of the changes that the new Head of Pharma is implementing on the operational side and, in particular, what cost reduction opportunities you may see that are independent of the outcome of the FDA decision on Cladribine?
 And then I have a final question on Liquid Crystals. Could you just walk us through the competitive dynamics in the PS-VA space; whether any competitors have actually launched? And to the extent that you have seen, or are seeing, launches, how much of a technological advantage you still think you have in the vast majority of the applications, given that you are probably on your second, third, fourth generation of PS-VAs by now? Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 All right, we'll take one additional question. Yes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fabian Wenner,  UBS - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, it's Fabian Wenner from UBS. The first question on the Millipore savings; you said you wanted to deliver on the value of Millipore. Can you detail to us what you have included in your guidance for the Group's core EBIT? Is the full EUR75m in there already?
 Secondly, I think it was mentioned this morning that you don't expect to divest Consumer Health, obviously, because it disappointed this year. Is that generally your view? Do you not want to divest it? What's your goal in general for this unit? Can you lower the costs and raise margins?
 And, thirdly, if I may, cost progression as well, the cost containment in Pharma; what is your target plan for 2011? Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would kindly ask you to give Stefan Oschmann a little bit of time, even more than a little bit, a bit of time. He has just taken over. He is doing a thorough analysis and we have frequent discussions on what we think needs to be done and what will be done. And, by the way, Bernd is part of those discussions. So without announcing any specific date or any number we are working on a thorough analysis in all aspects and when we feel the time is right to communicate what we plan to do, we will do it. And you will be certainly among the first to hear it.
 This relates to the projects -- project review, this relates to pipeline but, of course, also to cost containment and cost reductions, which of course are part of the game plan going forward. So we will update you at a later stage.
 Second, also Pharma I have to be careful how I phrase it, because the first question is will you -- in the press, will you divest OTC. My answer is no. Even if I wanted to do it, I wouldn't tell obviously. The second question is do you exclude selling it. And my answer was I never exclude anything in life. I'm old enough to have seen everything and portfolio review is a continuous part of our game plan, as you have seen in the portfolio changes in the last years.
 Now the result of this -- my statement was that we are considering selling OTC. Obviously, the two things have nothing in common. So I would like to ask you when drawing your conclusions to keep those two things apart. The general -- let me give you a general outline how we look at OTC.
 It's an attractive business to be in. It's an attractive business in combination with the Prescription business and, not by chance, a number of companies are interested to build and to create a footprint in OTC who don't have it today. Second, it also fits perfectly in what we can do and what we are able to do, so also from a portfolio perspective it's a good thing to have.
 Third, we are strong in some products but also only in some markets, some countries, some regions. We have no global footprint, so the first strategic question is do we need a global footprint or is it sufficient to work as a regional player in this market? As you know, there are global brands, but also national and local brands, so it makes sense to look at both sides of the coin.
 Number four, if we would decide to go for a global reach and a global brand we would have to analyze the options. And for the time being I rule out that we do any major acquisition in this area because the prices to be paid at the moment are not the ones I am willing to pay. This does not exclude, of course, all kind of brand acquisitions, license acquisitions, partnering deals or what have you. This is part of our very normal strategy process and I think we have demonstrated over the past five years that we are not shying away from any portfolio adjustments if we think it's the right decision.
 The competitive dynamics in the Liquid Crystals is less a question -- should not be focused only on the PS-VA. The story behind the Liquid Crystals is that we are investing in a material, we're trying to place it with the customer, which can take anything between three months and three years, because it's not as easy as in Pharmaceutical; you get a registration, you start selling. You have to place it in the customer. You have to work with the customer, so it's a very intense process.
 And once it's in the market -- once it's in the first set, then the competition sees it and starts to try to find a way to have the same effects we have with a certain mixture with their singles and mixtures, of course, without violating patents. This can take any time. Again, depending how complicated the chemistry behind it, between three months to three years. If you enter a new technology it is never forever in this market. So that implies when we have -- the moment we have launched PS-VA and have the first customer we start working on the next technology. So while we're sitting here and talking business And I promise you there will be technologies also for the future.
 So I believe that in 2011 we will see competition coming in with PS-VA materials similar to us and we have to see whether they meet our quality, whether and what impact has that on pricing. But I definitely expect in 2011 the first PS-VA supplies from competitors in the market.
 Bernd will talk a little bit about Erbitux and then Michael Becker will round off this answer set with comments on the guidance on Millipore.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Kirschbaum,  Merck Serono - Head, R&amp;D   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, Erbitux gastric EXPAND you know that we have completed the recruitment. We are now following up with the patients. And this is an event-driven study, so this is really the one scenario where it actually may be good news if it takes longer.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, integration costs. Normally integration effects are fully in place on a full-year basis after two years and it creeps up until then. So for the time being we have spent about 35m of pure integration costs, another 30m is transaction cost. That's about one-fifth that you should imagine. For the next year we want to spend another 42m on integration cost and, therefore, we expect that at the end of next year we will have a running rate which is close to the 75m.
 This means that we have now a mixture of being somewhere between 25m and 50m and we also are considering that we may have a higher outturn of our endeavors to unearth synergies. So my expectation is that we will have about 30m to 40m synergies in next -- this year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. We'll now take a question from one of our conference call participants.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, sir. Our first question today comes from Matthew Weston from Credit Suisse. Your line is now open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Weston,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon, gentlemen, thank you for taking my question. A couple of simple financial questions just to follow up and then some more strategic ones. Regarding the financial questions, can you just tell me where the Theramex revenue is currently booked in 2010; just literally which revenue line? The same for Crop BioScience just to really understand where they're going to come out of the revenue going forward. Could you also give us US sales for Rebif as well just in terms of splitting that key revenue driver between US and ex US?
 Moving on, then, to something more strategic, you've discussed how you have high hopes that Rebif will continue to be stable in the current marketplace. Can you explain how you expect stability, whereas, one of your key competitors anticipates that Betaseron will fall double digit year on year, given the competition from Gilenia? And can you also explain the timeline for whether or not you expect to file -- re-file RebiSmart in the US?
 And then, finally, just regarding your guidance, can you explain what you've done with foreign exchange within your guidance going forward? Have you assumed that it remains flat at current levels? Have you assumed it remains flat on, I don't know, full-year '10 average? Or have you actually made an assumption about the progression of the euro versus the dollar. And of course I particularly ask, given your LCD business and how sensitive that is to the dollar/euro rate. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So I start with the Theramex and Crop BioScience, where I understood that you mean in which line of revenues does the business go into 2010 in sales. The sale of the business goes into exceptionals, so it is deconsolidated and the profit will be in exceptionals. There will be no sales in 2011 related to Theramex or to Crop BioScience.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Weston,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 By way of follow up, what I meant was literally which revenue line in 2010 was it present? Is it 'other cardiometabolic care and local' in 'other pharmaceuticals'?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's not the -- you mean in which division. We don't break that down. We are reporting per segment and, therefore, we have a -- and if you look at the overview that we have given with our main franchises it goes into the cardiometabolic care line -- it goes into the -- yes, local cardiometabolic care line.
 With regard to foreign exchange, we do our guidance always on the same exchange rate that we have our internal planning. And this is a fixed rate which is fixed through the planning process and it is slightly lower than the exchange rate that we have now. But the average exchange rate will be billed into the -- well, the development of next year. So there is no exchange rate that we guide. We take a past exchange rate just for calculation purposes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, for Rebif so it's roughly EUR690m US, or has been in 2010. Your question was, then, number one, on the life cycle management when would we be able to file the RebiSmart in the US. That's too early to say. We're still waiting for the result from a study there.
 Second, of course I can't comment on what competitors are saying to probably Betaseron. But we should keep in mind that Rebif is the standard therapy. With a standard therapy you have certain advantages. Second, if you look at the past we have been gaining market share amongst the interferons in the US, so I don't see why that trend should be changing. And last, again US, even if you have a new drug you know it takes some time until you get into the formularies and so on. So I was talking about 2011 and not 2012. But I still believe in 2011 that the statement which I made is accurate.
 In addition, on the overall franchise, I mentioned also growth opportunities there, number one, in a number of other markets, then US and Europe, emerging markets and so on, and I mentioned possibilities for life cycle management in a number of markets. So all of that I think underlines and confirms the possibility that we will be able to keep our [euro] together in Rebif, despite whatever other companies might be saying on their products.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, if we could take two questions from the live audience. Yes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Odile Rundquist,  Helvea - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, good morning, Odile Rundquist from Helvea. I understood that it's a bit difficult to give any guidance on the impact of European reform for 2011, but could you give what was the impact in 2010 from Merck Serono, the major product?
 And could you remind me what are the new requirements for Safinamide approval?
 And, finally, as Serostim is one of your five top-selling Pharma products within Merck Serono, could you just give me how much sales Serostim amounted in 2010? Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, one additional question from the audience. Yes?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Wendorff,  Commerzbank - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Wendorff, Commerzbank. A few questions, if I may, starting off with a follow-up question on the guidance for 2011; a clarification question really. Did I get it right during the presentation that, even if oral Cladribine will be approved, that the cooperating profit contribution will be close to zero, or is there an incremental profit? Would there already be an incremental profit visible even in the first year on the market?
 Second question on the pricing situation of Rebif. You've outlined the guidance for 2011. Does that include a continuous price increase in the US, or how do you see the situation there for Rebif?
 And, lastly, on the pricing of Movectro in Russia and Australia, I would certainly be interested in getting an update there on how you have priced the drug against other existing MS treatments. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I will start. I'll start with asking Michael Becker to say something on the guidance.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, the guidance with regard to Cladribine and its profit. If, and I say if -- and there's no assumption to the probability that Cladribine comes connected with the 5% to 10% guidance. If it comes of course a launched product, then I don't think that's possible to have a launched product in profit. So this guidance, 5% to 10%, includes a negative contribution of Cladribine.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Wendorff,  Commerzbank - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Maybe a follow up one on that. If it's not being approved I would assume that your core return on sales guidance in terms of the margin would be, then, obviously higher than the 22% to 23%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That depends on how the decision is. Is it just a blank out of [Fruzal]? Never ever. Or is it something different? And it depends on our ability to take out costs straight away.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Wendorff,  Commerzbank - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There are research costs, there are marketing costs, there are other fixed costs which you normally can't take out straight away, so to which extent this will then be result neutral or even we take out a negative product positive, which I doubt, depends on our ability to take out these costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. On the Serostim, roughly EUR70m in 2010 in revenues and sales. Movectro, at the moment these are too-small markets so the overall situation of Movectro can only be analyzed after February 28. And we also have no reimbursement currently in Russia and Australia. So at the moment I would like to ask you to wait until we can assess the overall situation.
 The total impact of EU reforms, I don't have it at hand. Investor Relations will provide it as a follow up.
 The last answer to Safinamide comes from Bernd.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Kirschbaum,  Merck Serono - Head, R&amp;D   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, on Safinamide we need to complete our big phase III trials, SETTLE and MOTION, and then we can talk about when we are ready to submit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, we'll take one question from the conference call.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, sir. Our next question today comes from Jack Scannell from Sanford Bernstein. Your line is now open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Scannell,  Sanford C. Bernstein - Analyst   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks very much, just one question. Over the last five years Biopharmaceutical R&amp;D spending, including government agencies, including the Pharma industry, including Biotech, has probably grown at about 10% a year. If consensus forecasts are right Biopharma spending is probably going to be flat, slightly down over the next five years and some governments are going to be spending less on biomedical R&amp;D, NIH, for example, in 2011. Does any of that affect the way you think about the growth of Merck Serono, both on the positive side and negative side so, for example, tighter spending but maybe more variablized (sic) costs? I just wonder if you could talk about that for a moment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you repeat the question?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Company Representative   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, it's okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Scannell,  Sanford C. Bernstein - Analyst   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sorry, I had an "it's okay". Would you like me to repeat the question?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just the last part of that question, Jack, would be good.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Scannell,  Sanford C. Bernstein - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. So clearly the overall amount being spent may be going down, but also there may be more impetus for variablized (sic) costs, for example, in the pharmaceutical industry. So I just wonder if you could talk about both the positive and negative risks of much slower growth in R&amp;D spending across biomedical players.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And, operator, we'll take one additional question on the conference call before answering Jack's question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, sir. We will take our next question from Cornelia Thomas from WestLB. Your line is open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Cornelia Thomas,  WestLB - Analyst   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, good afternoon. Just one question left from my side, and that also has to do with Millipore. Could you give us an idea of the organic growth you saw for Millipore in 2010 and what you're expecting for 2011 in terms of organic growth from Millipore? And by that I mean the legacy Millipore business, not Merck Millipore. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Unfortunately, I can't give you that organic growth because in 2010 we have no pro-forma calculation of legacy Millipore. And in 2011 we will have no previous effect of Millipore alone because everything is between blended with the Merck business. And therefore we can't give you an organic growth of legacy Millipore for 2010 or 2011.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Maybe to give you a better understanding what we're doing here, you can realize synergies in the cost area, in the revenue area only if you really put the two businesses together. So somebody representing reagents has now also [reviewed this last quarter] and the other way around. So in order to measure the effects in a historical pattern we would have to go back and do a number of as-if calculations which have no value added practically for the business. And therefore we are moving into the new set of numbers and that is why legacy numbers would lack comparison.
 On the first question, one of -- there are two different drivers for the Millipore Biopharmaceutical business. One is, of course, if a new drug enters the market and we are part of the value chain of that drug, then we would have an increase in our business with or without less R&amp;D spending. What I wanted to say that that is depend -- we are in a number of drug developments. If those drugs make it to the market Millipore business increases, because immediately quantities and revenues increase. If the drugs don't make it to the market, then we would fail on that as well.
 So the question -- the short-term question for 2011 is much less of reduced spending but much more how many of the drugs we are in make it to the market. Long term, of course, we see changes in the industry; the whole Pharmaceutical industry is struggling with the issue of R&amp;D efficiency. And we are working to find answers also for the Merck Millipore business how we can deal with that better. But this is a strategic decision -- discussion which I think goes beyond the scope of the analysts' call.
 The other risk is, of course, always academia. If you have less incentive by governments in academia, academia is spending less. And there it is a question of R&amp;D spend and less of products. But the level going forward to 2011, at least seems to me, still being attractively high. So I don't expect a major influence on our numbers from that part of the business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So just following up on a previous question, we estimate that the impact from European healthcare reform in 2010 was a negative impact of EUR15m.
 Any additional questions from the audience? Andrew?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Baum,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just a couple of brief ones. Just following up on my earlier question about why continue to invest in research, I think you took my question as meaning how to improve the ROI for research. In actual fact I was saying why play in the orchestra at all. You have other asset classes which you're good at, where the environment is less challenging. Is there really a role for an integrated research-driven company with the scale that you have in the current environment? That's the first question.
 The second question is, if I look at a couple of the recent setbacks Merck has had, you could argue it's the failure to commercialize Cladribine and the failure to get approval for Erbitux in lung cancer, both of which arguably was due to an underinvestment in running a second trial for the drug. I also observe that the compensation of the Board is tied to three years' rolling profit growth. Many of your peers have adopted over the years EVA or ROIC-based metrics. To what extent do you think that is a consideration that may reinforce correct decision-making throughout the organization?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Is there an additional question in the audience? Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The first one is a very fundamental strategic questions. I do not believe in first place that the question whether to play an orchestra or not has to do with size; it's rather how you play the orchestra. And I don't think that we failed on (spoken in German). German speakers to the front? Nobody? How you tune the instruments. So it's not a question to how you tune the instruments, but rather how you play them. And I believe the tuning was okay; the playing needs some improvement. And obviously also now we have a new conductor and let's see what comes out from that.
 But, still, the overall business model of the Pharmaceutical industry is certainly one thing which is in discussion, irrespective of size as we see, and it is also part of our internal discussion. At the moment we think we can deliver, but the strategic discussion is clearly on for all of us in this sector.
 On the Board compensation, I think the first thing we have to do is to get the share price into the Board remuneration and the buddies of the Company are discussing that. And I have all indications that from next year on there will be also compensation tied to the share price of the Board members. So this, for me, is priority over other measures, in particular, as the compensation of all top managers, except the Board level, is tiled -- tied to ROCE-type investment criteria as well.
 So in practice I can tell you, you couldn't run an organization, even if there's at the moment still a difference between the Board on compensation and the rest of the organization. If everybody tells you -- if you tell an organization please keep on investing like hell and they tell you, sorry, then we can't get any bonus, you wouldn't survive as a Board member for long. So in practice there's a link in the compensation scheme that still needs further discussion but, as I said, the first step is tying it to the chair and this will be implemented for 2000 -- for next year, so in 2011 for 2012.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are there any additional questions on the call, operator?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We will take our next question today from Edward Dulac from Barclays Capital. Your line is now open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Edward Dulac,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you and good afternoon. Just two questions, please. Firstly, with respect to Serono, sales guidance seems to imply in the case of Serono approval in the US -- excuse me, Cladribine approval in the US, about EUR200m or so in 2011. I was just curious if you could share with us your assumptions around what label [maybe it] had in the US, penetration rates and timing of reimbursement.
 Secondly, with respect to Rebif, in the third-quarter commentary you were able to provide some volume, pricing and currency dynamics for both Europe and US; hoping to get that for the fourth quarter as well.
 And then, lastly, with respect to foreign exchange, the quarterly [leap] was about 5%. I was just hoping perhaps you can give us an estimate of what -- how much of that flowed through to the bottom line. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And maybe one additional question from the call before taking Edward's question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question today comes from Vincent Meunier from Exane BNP Paribas. Your line is now open.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vincent Meunier,  Exane BNP Paribas - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hello, gentlemen. Three questions, please. The first one is on Rebif, the new formulation. Can you please give us an update regarding the regulatory process in the US?
 The second question is on Stimuvax and Cilengitide. Can you please give us an update on the timing of the phase III trials? When can we expect results, at least internal results?
 And, lastly, on OLED can you please give us an update on the market dynamics and the future mid-term opportunities for Merck and also for the industry in general? Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm sorry, can you repeat that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vincent Meunier,  Exane BNP Paribas - Analyst   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. The third question is on the OLED. Can you please give an update on the market dynamics and also the mid-term opportunities for Merck and the market in general?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Cladribine, I really ask for your understanding. Let's wait for the US decision on twenty-eight and then we will review the situation and then update you as soon as we have information. At the moment it is really a crystal-ball exercise which I think I wouldn't like to enter into too much.
 For the pricing effects of Rebif in the first quarter and so on, may I suggest that you get in touch with Investor Relations after the call to get details if they're needed for your models?
 On Rebif new formulation, as I said before, we're still waiting for the study results so it's too early to say when we can submit it for registration.
 OLED, I still do have the impression that in the TV and Display-related sector Liquid Crystal will remain the commanding technology for many years to come. It's a little bit of yo-yo with OLED. Sometimes everybody thinks OLED will be there tomorrow; next day everybody says, no, it's coming in 10 years. So my working assumption is that in the Display technologies Liquid Crystals will remain the leading technologies for many years to come.
 In Lighting I see better chances for the Organic Lighting devices. And in -- when we opened the new Material Research Center here in Darmstadt I was saying that we could -- would hope to be able to tell you more about that in 2012 and that related mainly to Lighting.
 On ForEx Michael Becker will add a brief comment, and Stimuvax, Celengitide questions will then be answered by Bernd.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Becker,  Merck KGaA - CFO   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. To foreign exchange effect on top and bottom line, I understand you meant full-year 2010. The currency effect on sales is roughly 270m plus, of course, and on total revenues roughly 280m, out of which 10m fall through to the bottom line. That is the effect that what a tailwind is for sales and revenues is a headwind for the cost lines.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joshua Young,  Merck KGaA - Head, IR   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So maybe just one additional comment in regards to the Rebif US and Europe. There was not a discernible difference in organic growth between either region for 2010 for the full year for Rebif.
 So, with that, that is all the time we've allotted for today's session. I'd like to turn the conference over to Dr. Kley for some closing remarks. We will have a re-broadcast of this call posted to our website a couple of hours after the event. So, with that, I'd like to turn it over to Dr. Kley for some closing remarks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bernd Kirschbaum,  Merck Serono - Head, R&amp;D   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, there were two questions on Stimuvax and Cilengitide I was just reminded. On Stimuvax I just mentioned before that the recruitment in the study is going very well. So we planned to recruit 1,500 patients, we are getting closer and -- but in terms of speculating what the exact timelines is, we don't do this. And Cilengitide glioblastoma going as planned, but no further comments on the timelines.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Karl Kley,  Merck KGaA - Chairman   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In closing, I think we delivered good numbers in a challenging year. The potential in our portfolio is good. The only one who can prevent us from delivering is ourselves, so it's mainly calling ourselves to deliver what we have in hand. I believe that we outlined the opportunities and the headwinds and challenges and believe, on that note, that a good 2010 will be followed by a good 2011.
 Looking forward to continued and extensive communication with you; all the best. Take care. Bye bye.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Full Year 2010 Merck KGaA Earnings Presentation]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Darmstadt</city>
  <companyName>Merck KGaA</companyName>
  <companyTicker>MRK.DE</companyTicker>
  <startDate>21-Feb-11 1:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>138961</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>4741844</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>DE0006599905</ISIN>
</Event>