<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="11599941" lastUpdate="Wednesday, August 29, 2018 at 3:55:13am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="11599941.F" expirationDate="Friday, August 10, 2018 at 2:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of MSI.TO earnings conference call or presentation 10-Aug-18 2:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2018 Morneau Shepell Inc Earnings Call

TORONTO Aug 29, 2018 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Morneau Shepell Inc earnings conference call or presentation Friday, August 10, 2018 at 2:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Scott Milligan
      Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO
   *  Stephen Liptrap
      Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jaeme Gloyn
      National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst
   *  Marko Kais
      TD Securities Equity Research - Associate
   *  Stephanie Doris Price
      CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - Director of Institutional Equity Research &amp; Software and Business Services Research Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Second Quarter 2018 conference call for Morneau Shepell Inc.
 Please note that this conference call will contain forward-looking statements, which reflect management's current beliefs and expectations regarding the corporation's future growth and results of operations. Actual results can differ materially from those anticipated.
 I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Stephen Liptrap, President and Chief Executive Officer of Morneau Shepell Inc. Please go ahead, Mr. Liptrap.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thanks, Paul. Good morning, and thank you for joining us. On the call with me today is Scott Milligan, our Chief Financial Officer.
 Yesterday, after markets closed, we released Morneau Shepell's financial results for the second quarter of 2018.
 Like always, you can access the news release, financial statements and our MD&amp;A on our website at morneaushepell.com. Today, I'll briefly summarize our results for the quarter, highlight some key client wins in support of our strategy and update you on the LifeWorks acquisition that closed on July 27.
 Then, Scott will review in more depth our financials with an emphasis on the LifeWorks transaction and its complementary impact on our business model and recurring revenue profile.
 We are pleased with our second quarter results as they continue to demonstrate good execution of our strategic plan.
 At a high-level, we delivered 7.5% revenue growth over Q2 last year and saw adjusted EBITDA grow 7.7%, all the while delivering EBITDA margin of 19.7%, up slightly from last year.
 The basis of these results is good growth across all 4 lines of business. In particular, we had some significant wins in Q2 to include the LifeWorks acquisition that complements each 1 of our 5 strategic pillars.
 As a reminder, these are: building out our core business; accelerating our U.S. presence and growth; investing behind technology in the HR space; enhancing our ability to integrate across our product offerings and cross-sell; and be more scalable in our solutions.
 Second, for the quarter, our sales pipeline continues to grow solidly and our recurring revenue increased in Q2 within the double digits.
 Third, we achieved strong growth in the U.S. well into the double digits.
 In addition to strong U.S. revenue growth, we had some significant wins in the quarter, and in July, we've signed a significant outsourcing agreement with a major U.S. company. Through this agreement, we'll be serving more than 250 organizations in the U.S. This is a powerful story that drives scale for us in the context of our strategy of both focusing on our core businesses and accelerating our U.S. growth.
 Also in the U.S. market, we signed up the American operations of a European life insurance company, elipsLife, which is a wholly owned subsidiary of Swiss Re, a leading global reinsurance company.
 What's interesting is that elipsLife is entering the U.S. market for the first time and what we're providing them is an EAP solution customized to their needs so that they can enter the market to target enterprise clients.
 So essentially, it's a channel agreement, focused initially on the American Midwest, with plans to expand across the country.
 It's exciting because it not only supports our U.S. growth strategy but through the new relationships we're building, it opens up new global opportunities as well.
 We also had another health and welfare win in the U.S. in excess of $2 million per year, and we added a student support program with Michigan State.
 This was an expansion of our international student program that we had put in place earlier with Michigan State. We also had a number of wins close to $1 million in Canada to include retirement solutions for a large mining operation, an EAP win in Québec and an absence management solution in the oil and gas industry.
 From a cross-sell standpoint, in eastern Canada, we landed an assignment to provide an absence management solution in addition to administering the organization's public sector pensions.
 I mentioned these client wins because they support the evolving direction and growth strategy of our company in this way.
 Today, we're more focused than ever on the U.S. market while ensuring we remain as we are today: strong in Canada. Today, we're more focused on innovation as a game changer. But also, we're taking the time to putting the effort in to answer a very strategic question: how best can we scale our company? Can we grow more efficiently and strategically? And that brings me to the acquisition of LifeWorks in July, which is a great example of how we're targeting acquisitions that allow us to accelerate our strategic plan.
 As you know, LifeWorks is a leading global well-being and employee-assistance provider, with strong market positions in the U.S., the U.K. and Australia, very complementary geographies to our footprint.
 As we previously talked about, LifeWorks significantly increases our overall presence in the U.S. and internationally from 15% of our total revenue to 24%. It makes us one of the largest well-being in the EAP players in the world.
 In addition to building out a geographic footprint, this acquisition gives us an opportunity to be the power brand in the well-being space on a global basis. Because today, in all ways accounts, LifeWorks is a leader and an innovator in evolving global markets for solutions and employee health, well-being and engagement.
 It's really an ideal match, Morneau Shepell is much deeper in the clinical treatment side of workplace health and well-being, and we have a strong technology platform to make that a great experience for our clients, employees.
 The LifeWorks' fast-paced platform broadens our solution portfolio across the HR well-being space to include employee engagement, rewards and recognition, human resource communications and employee perks.
 LifeWorks also provides an integrated cloud-based user experience, which we see growing over time and allowing us to further scale our business across the HR well-being space.
 LifeWorks' CEO, Jamie True, has joined us as a Chief Digital Officer. In this role, Jamie will lead the strategy and development of our enterprise cloud-based platform. In addition, he will lead the sales activities for our LifeWorks' line of business, which was previously our Employee Support Solutions line of business.
 With the acquisition, we add 500 talented employees, 4,200 customers, $100 million in revenue and strong recurring revenue model that is complementary to our own, that Scott will talk about.
 Put very simply, with LifeWorks, our combined organization offers a single one-stop shop to more of our clients, employee population right across the globe.
 And this is consistent with our vision for Morneau Shepell of focusing our growth strategy on solutions that positively impact the health and productivity of people, the heart of every organization.
 I'm pleased to say in the early stages of organizational integration with LifeWorks, things are proceeding as planned. Our teams are working together, collaborating on go-to-market strategies, where we're really excited about the cross-selling opportunities.
 So I'm handing the call over to Scott, who will bring us back to our finances. Let me say that we are pleased with another solid quarter of growth and strong execution of our strategic plan. Scott?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thanks, Stephen, and good morning. Before we go deeper into the results, I'd like to briefly refer to the financial impact and rationale for LifeWorks.
 While there's plenty to get excited about with the unified technology platform and the future of the combined business, there's still a lot of value to be created from the existing business at LifeWorks.
 We acquired a strong growing company of international scale and innovative scope that fits our business model and strategy perfectly.
 Stephen mentioned, that from a revenue diversity perspective, the acquisition increases our U.S. and international presence. Just as importantly, LifeWorks produces high-quality stable cash flow and earnings with its core EAP business delivering 90% -- 97% of total revenue today.
 And given the specific mix of solutions within their EAP portfolio, we see some real upside in terms of growth per client, looking ahead.
 We also anticipate strong EBITDA and earnings accretion in our forecast as we move into organizational integration and optimization.
 We expect significant -- we expect to generate significant run rate synergies over the next 2 years or so, primarily from cost rationalization and operational consolidation.
 In terms of financing the deal, again, the story, as we have discussed, is a very good one and in no way detracts from our financial health.
 The $325 million transaction price, as we noted in the immediate release, was fully financed with equity from a $210 million bought deal and the rest from debt financed by upsizing our credit facility to $500 million.
 On closing, our incremental debt is in the $200 million range, which translates into a debt-to-adjusted-EBITDA ratio of approximately 2.8:1.
 We're pleased with the financial profile of the business post-closing, and you can be assured that going forward, the value of being a well-financed, indeed financially strong competitor will remain central to how we operate and scale the business for future growth.
 Now let's turn to the financial results in more detail. First, looking at the year -- our year-to-date performance. In the first half, we reported $338.7 million in revenue, an increase of 7.3%. Adjusted EBITDA at $67.3 million is up 7.5%. Adjusted EBITDA margin was up slightly to 19.9% compared to 19.8% a year ago.
 We're tracking very solidly to where we want to be. As part of that, as Stephen noted, we had a strong second quarter where the company reported $171.2 million in revenue, an increase of 7% or $12 million from the same period last year.
 Adjusted EBITDA in the quarter increased 7.7% to $33.7 million, up from $31.3 million in Q2 2017. Adjusted EBITDA margin was 19.7%, the same as in Q2 2017.
 Profit was $13.7 million in the quarter compared to $12.1 million last year.
 During Q2, the company generated normalized free cash flow of $16.9 million compared to $15.4 million in the second quarter of 2017, and the company is maintaining its policy of paying a monthly dividend of $0.065 per share. I will now turn the call back to Stephen.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thanks, Scott. I'd like to thank everyone on the call for your time so far today, and we'd be pleased to now open the line to answer your questions. Paul, can you go ahead and open the line?
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  (Operator Instructions) The first question is from Stephanie Price from CIBC.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephanie Doris Price,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - Director of Institutional Equity Research &amp; Software and Business Services Research Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I was hoping if you can talk a bit more about the cross-sell opportunity for LifeWorks. Scott mentioned in his remarks [its] upside in terms of growth per client there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. One of the things -- it's Stephen here, Stephanie, one of the things that we're quite interested in, in the acquisition was the fact that LifeWorks really does offer a broad spectrum of services across the HR well-being space. And those range all the way from rewards and recognition to communication tools to recognition and things -- and employee perks. So we really see an opportunity to go into current EAP clients and sell them that broader spectrum rather than just EAP. Again, as we go forward, we see us being much more of a well-being player rather than specifically focused on the EAP market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephanie Doris Price,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - Director of Institutional Equity Research &amp; Software and Business Services Research Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Perfect. And then in terms of the technology platform, I wondered if you could give us a bit more details around that as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. It's -- let me just, kind of, build on what we said before. One of the things we were really interested, from a technology standpoint, we spent a lot of time over the last few years going very deep in a clinical app and a clinical technology platform so that people are able to 24/7 chat with the counselor, people are able to book appointments online and all of that. The decision that LifeWorks made over the last couple of years was not to go as deep from a clinical standpoint but to go much broader from an HR standpoint. So their platform is really a cloud-based app that employees go to, to get everything they need to do from a well-being standpoint. So in a way, we think of ourselves as being the workday of well-being, a place that employees go to, to get recognition within the workplace, a place that employees can go to, to grant rewards for other employees or managers grant rewards, a place that companies can roll out key communications and those type of things. So it is a place that employees are going to on a regular basis. And what we will do is we will take our deep clinical EAP app, merge those 2 things together and have that even a more robust solution than before.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephanie Doris Price,  CIBC Capital Markets, Research Division - Director of Institutional Equity Research &amp; Software and Business Services Research Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Perfect. And then just one more. In terms of the cost-saving opportunities and integration plans, hope you could touch on that a bit more?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. It's Scott, Steph. So the synergies are really based in -- so they're predominantly cost-driven, and they're really based in 3 areas. And that would be -- we have greater scale and frankly, a better cost base on delivery for clinical services. And so we will be spreading that cost base to the LifeWorks platform. Secondly, as we looked at sales and client success or account management and operations and the leadership structure across those functions in the 2 companies, there were some redundancies and opportunities for harmonization. So we've taken advantage of that. And thirdly, there'll be some traditional back-office savings and things like finance and HR and those kinds of groups.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question is from Marko Kais from TD Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Marko Kais,  TD Securities Equity Research - Associate   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Just wondering, since the deal was announced, has there been any feedback from some of your larger existing clients? And either from the LifeWorks' clients?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Marko, it's Stephen. A couple comments on that. First thing, leading up to even the close of the deal, I did have an opportunity to talk to some of our clients and some of the LifeWorks' clients on a confidential basis, just to get a really good sense as to what they were seeing and all of the feedback was extremely positive. Since we announced the deal, we've had a lot of interactions, obviously, with our clients. And I would say the biggest question is how quickly can we take a look at the new platform, and what does that mean? So that's been very positive. And we actually had a win fairly recently, which was a very large retailer across the U.S. They were in conversations with LifeWorks, but there was a slight hesitancy in closing the deal because they didn't know if there would be enough deep clinical support. So as soon as we're able to announce the deal, they really saw it as an advantage to take a hold of what we've done from a clinical standpoint, put it together with the technology that they were very interested in, and we're able to sign that deal and close it. So the reaction from customers has been extremely positive so far.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Marko Kais,  TD Securities Equity Research - Associate   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Also wondering, does LifeWorks impact your appetite to do tuck-ins over the new term?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. It's Scott here, Marko. I think our focus in the short term is going to be on the integration and complete success of this deal. It doesn't mean we won't look at other tuck-ins and other opportunities if they make themselves apparent, there's still a pipeline of opportunities out there. But our -- as I said, our main focus is on delivering on this one.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Marko Kais,  TD Securities Equity Research - Associate   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And my last question is just wondering if you could quantify the revenue impact of the deals in the U.S. that you signed in the quarter? Maybe outsourcing agreement? And I think it's like -- it looks like -- and when do you expect this to come online?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, the outsourcing deal that we talked about will be primarily end of Q3 into Q4 this year, it will come online. And it would be north of $10 million. So significant opportunity for us. elipsLife is closing in closer to that $1 million area. And it really is a partnership agreement, and that will also come online in Q3.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  (Operator Instructions) The next question is from Jaeme Gloyn from National Bank Financial.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jaeme Gloyn,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  First question is related to the organic growth rate of about 5% year-over-year. Can you give us a little bit sense as to where that was coming from, geographically speaking? Was that primarily coming from the U.S? And maybe a little bit of a drag from Canada?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, it's Scott here, Jim, it's -- I mean, percentage-wise, the percentage growth is, obviously, significantly higher in the U.S. than it is in Canada, in the high 20s. But given that the U.S. is such a small piece of the business, the contribution to growth is pretty even between the 2. So it's -- it would be low mid-single-digit growth in Canada and high 20s growth in the U.S.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, Jim, it's Stephen, just building on it. From a strategic standpoint, we continue to see long-term mid-single-digit growth in Canada, somewhere between 4% and 6% and range depending on the quarter. And we continue to look for double-digit growth in the U.S.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jaeme Gloyn,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay, great. And in terms of the LifeWorks' transaction and the cloud-based platform, how much of a contribution is that to LifeWorks' current revenue breakdown? And where do you expect to see that trend, let's say, over the next 12 months? And maybe a longer-term view as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, Jim, So for -- and this was in the numbers in the perspectives, but we refer them -- to them today. 97% of their 2017 revenue was traditional EAP, and 3% would be the cloud-based enhanced app. And -- but what we're seeing is new sales are either significantly much higher than that, obviously, on the new side. So we're -- they've gone from 0% to 3% last year. We're seeing, depending -- it varies month-to-month but between 30% and 50% of new sales are of the enhanced product. So it'll take a long time, obviously, to make that a huge piece of the business. But we see that as a significant growth opportunity going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jaeme Gloyn,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And then just 2 more on the LifeWorks and then one quick follow-up with respect to the commentary around that large win from U.S. client that was a little bit hesitant. Is that different than one of the companies you mentioned previously, the outsourcing agreement in American operations? I mean, [this is -- it's a] separate client, right, unrelated to any of those others that were identified? And provide some context as to the size of this client?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Milligan,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - Executive VP &amp; CFO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. So I think Stephen answered it. It's north of $10 million a year of revenue. And yes, it's just take from anything we've announced in the past.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jaeme Gloyn,  National Bank Financial, Inc., Research Division - Analyst   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Great. And in terms of the outlook for revenue growth with LifeWorks, the guidance right now is for -- is to not have any revenue synergies between the 2 companies. How much upside do you think there is on this? I mean, I look at Morneau as having access to $8 million lives, which is nearly double the lives that LifeWorks has. And I have to think that there's going to be some revenue synergies there. I guess, why the conservative guidance at this point?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes, Jim, it's Stephen here. I think as we look at it, and at least, as we go back to our experience and everything, cost synergies are pretty definite, and you can really get at them. So we've really focused on getting at those cost synergies, and we're confident those -- we do think there are some revenue synergies. We don't want to get ahead of ourselves though. As Scott mentioned, it's only 3% of the platform today. We do see it growing, but we're going to want a little bit more experience. We're going to want to be further down the road and having conversations with clients and everything before we'd want to walk into some revenues synergies going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  There are no further questions registered at this time. I would now like to turn the meeting back to Mr. Liptrap.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Liptrap,  Morneau Shepell Inc. - President, CEO &amp; Director   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Great. Thank you very much, Paul. I'd like to end by expressing my thanks to everybody on the call. We continue to appreciate your interest in our company, and we look forward to other opportunities in the future, including these calls, to keep you up-to-date on what we're doing to drive our growth and success as a business. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time. And we thank you for your participation.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2018 Morneau Shepell Inc Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>TORONTO</city>
  <companyName>Morneau Shepell Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>MSI.TO</companyTicker>
  <startDate>10-Aug-18 2:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>194377</companyId>
  <CUSIP>61767W104</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>B64ZLH6</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>CA61767W1041</ISIN>
</Event>