<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="5594739" lastUpdate="Friday, January 23, 2015 at 8:46:17am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="5594739.F" expirationDate="Thursday, January 22, 2015 at 10:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of MXIM earnings conference call or presentation 22-Jan-15 10:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q2 2015 Maxim Integrated Products Inc Earnings Call

SUNNYVALE Jan 23, 2015 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Maxim Integrated Products Inc earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, January 22, 2015 at 10:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Kathy Ta
      Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - Managing Director of IR
   *  Bruce Kiddoo
      Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO
   *  Tunc Doluca
      Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Ross Seymore
      Deutsche Bank - Analyst
   *  Harlan Sur
      JPMorgan - Analyst
   *  John Pitzer
      Credit Suisse - Analyst
   *  Jim Covello
      Goldman Sachs - Analyst
   *  Steven Chin
      UBS - Analyst
   *  Ambrish Srivastava
      BMO Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Blayne Curtis
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Michael McConnell
      Pacific Crest Securities - Analyst
   *  Craig Hettenbach
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Tore Svanberg
      Stifel Nicolaus - Analyst
   *  Vince Celentano
      Raymond James - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Maxim Integrated second quarter of FY15 conference call.
 (Operator Instructions)
 As a reminder, today's program is being recorded.
 I would now like to introduce your host for today's program, Ms. Kathy Ta, Managing Director Investor Relations. Please go ahead, Kathy.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Ta,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - Managing Director of IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Jonathan.
 And welcome, everyone, to Maxim Integrated's fiscal second-quarter 2015 earnings conference call. With me on the call today are Chief Executive Officer Tunc Doluca and Chief Financial Officer Bruce Kiddoo.
 I would like to highlight that we have posted a supplemental financial presentation to our external Investor Relations website. The information in this presentation accompanies the financial disclosures in our earnings press release and on this conference call.
 During today's call, we will be making some forward-looking treatments. In light of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act, I'd like to remind you that these statements must be considered in conjunction with the cautionary warnings that appear on our SEC filings. Investors are cautioned that all forward-looking statements in this call involve risks and uncertainty, and that future events may differ materially from the statements made. For additional information, please refer to the Company's Securities and Exchange Commission filings which are posted on our website or available from the Company without charge.
 Now, I'll turn the call over to Bruce.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Kathy.
 I will review Maxim's second-quarter financial results. Revenue for the first quarter was $567 million, down 2% from the first quarter, and slightly above the guidance midpoint we provided last quarter. The modest quarter-on-quarter decline was primarily driven by weaker demand for communications infrastructure products. Demand for mobility product across our customer base was modestly better than expected.
 Last quarter we announced our plans to lower Maxim's cost structure driven by the weakness we have experienced in our consumer business. We are on track to our plan to reduce operating expenses senses in specific product lines where the return is no longer adequate. We expect to fully reflect $10 million in quarterly operating expense savings in our upcoming June quarter. We're also on track to our 18-month plan to reduce COGS through the closure of our fab in San Jose, which had supported low-volume manufacturing and process technology development.
 In addition to these cost reductions, we plan to stop investment in the consumer MEMS and touch lines of business, which will enable us to save an additional $3 million to $4 million a quarter. We expect to realize these additional savings over the next two quarters. Together with our previously announced plan, these changes will substantially lower our cost structure to improve profitability at any revenue level.
 In the December quarter, our consumer business was up strongly sequentially, above our expectations due to our diversification efforts and stronger demand. Our largest mobility customer now represents roughly 15% of revenue, up modestly from last quarter, but down significantly from 28% of revenue in FY13. Our revenue mix by major market in Q2 was approximately 33% from consumer, 27% industrial, 23% communications and data center, 12% automotive, and 5% computing.
 Our industrial business was down sequentially, as expected, driven by normal seasonal trends in our core industrial end market. Our communication and data center business was down sequentially more than expected, primarily driven by weakness in our enterprise server business after a strong September quarter. We also saw broad-based weakness in optical infrastructure equipment in the quarter.
 Our automotive business was up sequentially as we continue to the electronic content growth in cars, with our broad base of customers and products. And, finally, our computing business was down sequentially.
 Turning to the P&amp;L, Maxim's gross margin, excluding special items, was 60.3%, just above the midpoint of our forecast. Sequentially, gross margin was impacted by lower utilization. Internal fab utilization declined from 71% in Q1 to 60% in Q2.
 Special items in Q2 gross margin included intangible asset amortization from acquisitions and accelerated depreciation from the closing of our San Jose fab. Operating expenses, excluding special items, were $216 million, down from $220 million in the prior quarter. The decrease in operating expenses was driven primarily by overall tight spending controls, including the initial savings from our restructuring activities.
 Special items in Q2 operating expenses included normal acquisition-related charges, charges related to the restructuring we announced last quarter, including the closure of our San Jose fab and reduction in operating expenses, and the impairment of the goodwill and other assets related to our MEMS business as a result of our decision to stop investment in consumer MEMS.
 Q2 GAAP operating income excluding special items was $126 million or 22% of revenue. The Q2 GAAP tax rate excluding special items was 20.7%, in line with expectations, and up from 16.9% in Q1 due to one-time benefits in the prior quarter. The reinstatement of the R&amp;D tax credit for calendar year 2014 had a minor benefit to our Q2 results.
 The catch-up for the first half of calendar 2014 was part of our prior fiscal year and therefore we reported this as a special item in the quarter. The balance of the credit will be spread over FY15. GAAP earnings per share excluding special items was $0.33, above, above the high end of our guided range, primarily due to slightly higher revenue and lower operating expenses.
 Turning to the balance sheet and cash flow, during the quarter cash flow from operations was $173 million, or 30% of revenue. Inventory dollars were approximately flat from last quarter. Modest declines in consumer inventory were offset by increases in industrial and automotive inventory to improve delivery performance to the customers.
 Inventory days ended at 124, down one day from Q1. Inventory in the channel remained approximately flat at 54 days, within normal levels.
 Capital additions were $17 million in the quarter, which were more than offset by $24 million in proceeds from property sales. Capital additions, even excluding the proceeds from sale of property, are well below depreciation, enabling free cash flow to grow faster than earnings. Trailing 12-month free cash flow ending in Q2 was $662 million, or 28% of revenue. This represents a 13% increase over a year ago.
 Share repurchases totaled $60 million in Q2, as we bought back just over 2 million shares. We also paid $79 million in dividends to our shareholders. The yield on our quarterly dividend of $0.28 per share is approximately 3.4% at yesterday's closing stock price. Overall, total cash, cash equivalents and short-term investments increased by $62 million in the first quarter, to $1.38 billion.
 Moving on to guidance, our beginning Q3 backlog is $378 million. Based on this beginning backlog and expected turn, we forecast Q3 revenue of $565 million to $605 million, which reflects strong growth in automotive, a seasonal uptick in industrial, and the beginning of new product shipments into mobility opportunities. We expect all of our segments to be up in Q3.
 Q3 gross margin excluding special items is forecasted at 58% to 62%, flat from the prior quarter due to lower factory utilization in Q2, offset by higher utilization and spending controls in the current quarter. Special items in Q3 gross margin are estimated at approximately $32 million, primarily for amortization of intangible assets and accelerated depreciation from our restructuring activities.
 Q3 operating expenses excluding special items are expected to be down again from the prior quarter, reflecting reduced spending in targeted product lines and continued tight expense controls. Special items in Q3 operating expenses are estimated at approximately $4 million for amortization of intangible assets.
 Our Q3 tax rate excluding special items is estimated at 21% to 23%. For Q3 GAAP earnings per share excluding special items, we expect a range of $0.32 to $0.38. For FY15, due to the sale of capital assets, net capital expenditures are expected to be below the low end of our target range of 3% to 5% of revenue. We expect to continue to repurchase shares in Q3, consistent with our buyback matrix.
 In summary, we believe our long-term financial strategy of growth, leverage and return is on track. Our revenue performance in the second quarter was better than expected and our guidance reflects better than seasonal growth in the third quarter.
 We are taking targeted steps to reduce spending to improve profitability at any revenue level. This include the actions announced this quarter to stop investments in consumer MEMS and touch product lines.
 We remain committed to our 30% operating margin target, which will benefit from expected revenue growth and planned spending reductions. And, finally, we remain focused on growing free cash flow and returning cash to shareholders as demonstrated by our growth in trailing 12-month free cash flow and industry-leading dividend yield.
 I will now turn the call over to Tunc to further discuss our business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Bruce. And good afternoon to everyone on the call. We appreciate your interest in Maxim Integrated and thank you for joining us today.
 Every year I visit our global offices to discuss the Company direction and strategy with employees. Today, I'm joining you from Munich. Bruce and Kathy are at our headquarters in San Jose.
 In November Munich was also the site of Electronica, the world's largest industrial technology trade show. Here we showcased our latest technology that will enable the smart factories of the future, wearable medical devices, and mobile payment systems.
 And at the recent CES event in Las Vegas, excitement in smartphone, wearable and automotive markets was certainly on display. We showed customers our pipeline of new automotive technologies and infotainment, safety, and driver-assistance applications.
 As 2015 gets underway, we are seeing growing business momentum in our automotive and industrial businesses. And evidence that our diversification strategy is beginning to bear fruit in consumer.
 Our December quarter revenue performance was above the midpoint of our expectations, driven by our diversification efforts in consumer, and continued strength in our automotive business. As this momentum picks up in these businesses, we are staying financially disciplined. We are on track to achieve the cost reduction plans that we announced last October. These plans included reducing R&amp;D spending in targeted areas, and reducing manufacturing costs with the scheduled closure of our San Jose fab.
 As we demonstrated last quarter, we continue to take actions that will improve Maxim's profitability and enable more focused investment in top-line growth. In keeping with this plan, we are choosing to focus our resources on product areas where we believe we have a leading market position and stop investment in areas with lower return. As a result, we have decided to stop investment in consumer MEMS and touch.
 Both in touch and in consumer MEMS, we did develop state-of-the-art solutions that deliver superior performance. However, the competitive dynamics of these market opportunities are no longer consistent with Maxim's business objectives. Consequently, we have decided to stop further investment in both of these product lines. While these are clearly difficult decisions to make, these actions will improve Maxim's profitability profile.
 Let me next provide some color on our major markets, starting with consumer. Our December quarter revenue was down significantly from the same quarter of last year. However, demand from our largest mobility customer appears to be stabilizing, and we see validation that our diversification strategy in mobility is working.
 Our December quarter consumer end market revenue was strongly up from the September quarter, better than our expectations. The growth was driven by better performance at our leading mobility customer and an uptick in revenue from other mobility customers in both tablets and in shipments for a wearable product. We expect that this market will be up again in March with the launch of a new flagship phone at our leading mobility customer and continued shipments for a wearable product.
 We are making progress in winning designs and building business relationships at Chinese smartphone manufacturers. However, in the near term, we expect this to remain a relatively small portion of our consumer revenue stream.
 Let me next turn to the industrial market. Our December quarter industrial business was up 3% from the same quarter of last year, but sequentially down, in line with seasonality. Our largest distribution partner, Avnet, is again our largest account at 19% of total Company sales.
 We are excited that our relationship with Avnet has become far more strategic over the last five years. Avnet has increasingly served as an extension of our sales team, generating new design registrations from Maxim's broad portfolio of industrial products. As a result, our revenue with them has grown over 70% over the last five years. In calendar 2014, Avnet achieved a new milestone by surpassing their stretch goal of $0.5 billion in resales for Maxim.
 Turning to our vertical industrial markets, financial terminals were flat, and medical devices and smart meters were down in December. In financial terminals, we are seeing growth in mobile payment market and have received numerous design registrations for our new comprehensive reference design platform. This mobile payment platform is enabling new emerging customers to enter into the growing mobile payment market.
 In medical, Maxim wellness measurement microcontroller for wearable medical applications was recognized by Electronic Products as their 2014 product of the year. In smart meters, we see continued deployment projects in Asia but are experiencing a sequential decline in that business due to a slowdown in the US utility meter market.
 To date, we have not seen a strong correlation between smart meter project plans and the recent lower prices of fossil fuels. Looking forward, we project March quarter industrial revenue to be up, driven by sequential growth in all of our vertical and core industrial markets except for automatic test equipment.
 Let me now provide some commentary on our distribution business. Globally, end market resales were down 4% sequentially, in line with seasonality. Overall, we saw 54 days of inventory in the channel at the end of the December quarter, which was down one day from September and in line with historical averages. We continue to observe a relatively healthy pattern in our distribution business and are starting to see signs of positive momentum in the first half of calendar 2015.
 Our December quarter automotive business was up 33% from the same quarter of last year, reflecting solid content growth in high-end and mid-range cars and a broadening customer base. Our automotive business was sequentially up in December, better than typical seasonality and in line with our expectations.
 In the March quarter we expect automotive to be strongly up, driven by our solid pipeline of design wins, which are launching in the next model year cars. A broad set of infotainment applications remains the largest driver of our growth in this business.
 Going forward, we expect that safety and driver-assistance content, known as ADAS, will be a significant growth vector for Maxim in automotive. Today, we serve the driver-assistance market in two ways -- through power management with powerful processor chips for ADAS and in high-speed video links of camera systems around the car. We expect these areas will experience healthy double-digit growth rates for years to come.
 Next, let me discuss communications and data center. Our December quarter communications and data center business was down 8% from the same quarter of last year and was sequentially down strongly. We experienced broad-based weakness across our portfolio of products in this segment.
 We are seeing a pause in the implementation of optical telecom infrastructure and base station deployments, driven primarily by inventory adjustments by our customers. In enterprise servers, we experienced a period of inventory drawdown at leading customers following a strong September quarter.
 We are still seeing signs of an industry transition from traditional servers to new architectures that are optimized for cloud computing. However, we do not expect revenue from these wins until the second half of calendar 2015.
 We expect our comms and data center business to rebound in March with the resumption of communications infrastructure deployment. We anticipate our enterprise server revenue profile to remain flat from December.
 In the computing market, December revenue was down 6% from the same quarter of last year and down sequentially, as well. We expect computing to be up in March.
 Now, to summarize our view of the March quarter, we expect all of our businesses, including consumer, to be up in March. We expect automotive to be strongly up as we deliver on our robust pipeline of design wins for the next model year cars.
 We also expect consumer to be up with the initial ramp of a new smartphone at our leading mobility customer and shipments for a wearable product at another customer. Communications and data center and industrial are expected to be up from a weak December. And computing is also expected to be up.
 In closing, we are managing our portfolio and making tough decisions to adapt to the changes in our business environment to improve Maxim's profitability. These decisions enable us to continue to invest in growth areas for the Company. We are showing excellent progress in growing revenue for new power-efficient applications in all of our markets. And we are executing on our strategy to broaden our revenue base in mobility.
 Kathy, I'll now turn the call back to you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Ta,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - Managing Director of IR   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Tunc.
 That concludes our prepared remarks and we would now welcome your questions. In the interest of reaching everyone in the queue we'd like to ask that you ask just one question with one follow up.
 Jonathan, please begin polling for questions.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions)
 Ross Seymore from Deutsche Bank.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ross Seymore,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The first one is on the consumer business and specifically the mobility side. If you could just give a little bit more color on what exactly was the surprise in the quarter. It seemed like it bounced back. The Samsung side bounced back by about 30% sequentially. And how do you manage that process looking forward so we don't get back to the same position we've hit in the last couple of years where that concentration became a negative?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ross, this is Bruce. I think what we saw was a normal inventory correction from Samsung on some of their older products. But we did see, particularly on the Note 4, which had, as you recall, a late launch in the September quarter. So, we really got the full benefit of that launch in the December quarter, and so that came in a little bit stronger than our expectations. So, I think that was an upside.
 And then just in the general market of wearables, I think we saw a little bit more strength than we had expected going into the quarter. When we look at our forecast going forward, when we look at the next quarter, Q3, we actually think Samsung is probably flat to maybe even down slightly. And I think overall we expect it to stay in the current range, given the diversification within mobility and the growth in our other markets.
 It is something we pay attention to. Obviously, the decision that we made today or announced today around consumer MEMS and touch, would also be an area where it shows we're focused on the areas where we can achieve profitable, sustainable growth. So, I think that's another area that should give people comfort that we're going to manage this business in a more sustainable way going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ross Seymore,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As my follow-up, Bruce, you talked a lot about OpEx and the incremental cuts that you just mentioned on the touch side of things. Can you give us an idea of the trajectory for the March and the June quarter? And is the math as simple as taking the September OpEx and taking either $13 million or $14 million off of that to get you to the total cuts that will be in place by the June order?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think when we look at this, we had identified $10 million that would be out of the June quarter. We're on track for that. We said the one offset to that would be to the extent that our overall profitability increased and therefore our profit-sharing accrual would offset that. So, I think that's the only thing that offsets that $10 million savings.
 The $3 million to $4 million that we identified for the additional reductions for touch and MEMS, we'll achieve that over the next month. The full benefit of that will be realized in Q1 of 2016.
 Some of this is, obviously when you're dealing with restructuring activities, some of them take some time to implement. So, that's why that takes a little bit of time to execute on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ross Seymore,  Deutsche Bank - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Harlan Sur from JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Harlan Sur,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Solid job on the quarterly execution and guide. On the March quarter and the growth there, it's in line to maybe slightly better than the seasonal trends -- automotive up, industrial up, consumer up and so on. If I look back historically, the June quarter also tends to be another solid quarter with follow-through from automotive, industrial, consumer, and maybe a little bit of help from computing, as well. So, just given your view on the current fundamental environment, would the team expect normal seasonality in June? Maybe if you can just talk about some of the potential puts and takes here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. I think when we looked at the March quarter, actually when we look at the past four years with this post recession, we actually see it's been down about 1% to 2%. And that was really because ex Samsung or consumer business is normally down in the March quarter.
 I think one of the reasons you're seeing it up 3% at the midpoint this quarter is really two things, better diversification within our mobility business and the continued very strong growth in automotive. That's become a larger part of our business, 12% of revenue in the December quarter. And we continue to see strong growth and we guided that business up strongly in the March quarter.
 When we look at the June quarter, as you say, historically, that has been a good growth quarter for us, with the industrial and automotive segments up. I would say the one thing that we don't know yet is the size of the ramp of our largest customer. And as they launch their newest flagship phone, there may be an opportunity where maybe they're a little bit more modest than in prior years in order to avoid the inventory corrections we've seen in prior years. I think that's another factor that we have to take into account, which may be an offset to the normal seasonal growth in the June quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Harlan Sur,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Thank you for that. And then auto and industrial, it's now 40% of your business. Specifically on the automotive, I think as you guys mentioned, is up 33% year over year in the December quarter. I think in the prior quarter it was up over 40%. What's the confidence level on driving automotive growth on a double-digit year-over-year trajectory this calendar year? And then if you could just talk about some of the drivers within that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll take that one. In automotive we are getting great results and we're very happy for that. Obviously, everybody knows this is a market that you invest in for a long time to get to good revenue. The good part of that is we've done a lot of that investment and continue to do so.
 Since the product lives and design-ins are very long, you can depend on revenue that you're getting that has started, to continue. And what we're doing is, we're early in this ballgame so we keep adding revenue on top of that with new design wins, and really not seeing much end of life yet because we entered the market more recently. So, that's why we have some confidence that into the future we're going to see double-digit growth for several years to come.
 In terms of the types of products that we sell or the types of technologies that we sell, most of our revenue actually comes from the infotainment side of the business. But we're also seeing new additions now in the safety. And driver assistance is certainly one part of the business.
 In that segment, for example, we do have technology that we are selling and we're seeing great success for power management. As I mentioned in my prepared remarks, the processors are getting more and more computationally powerful and that requires special dedicated power management products. We're having success there. Actually, part of that success is coming from IP that we developed for mobility. So, that shows the power of actually making these technologies for one market and our ability to sell it in another.
 The second piece is really moving data around from video cameras that are used in all kinds of safety, where cameras are now being placed on multiple sides of the cars. And this high-speed data really has to crisscross the cars to get to these processes. So, on the safety side, power management, and products that we make for moving of data [serve] these products, as we call them.
 We also have products that revenues are now modest but we believe they're going to grow into the future. [Kilasco] for example, systems that we've designed and developed. All kinds of radio products for conversion, direct RF to bits technology, that we call where you can convert either satellite radio or digital audio broadcast directly from RF to bits for the digital processors. So, these are the main areas.
 And we also have investments in growth that's coming in the future for hybrid and electric vehicles where we do the battery management functions inside of these products. So, very broad product base. Since product lines are long and most of the wins have been more recent, with each new generation of win we're adding on top of old wins that we've got. And that's why we have confidence going into the future of double-digit growth for years to come.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Harlan Sur,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for that color, Tunc. Thanks, Bruce.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Pitzer from Credit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Pitzer,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Appreciate the questions. Congratulations on the strong results. Tunc, for a lot of us this wearable market is a relatively new market. And clearly in your prepared comments you talked about it adding to December and adding again to March.
 I would if you could help us think about how we should be modeling wearables relative to your content? Is the a December-March build and then the follow-through is going to be dependent upon sell-through? Or how should we think about modeling this maybe relative to flagship launch of phones that we've seen in the past in your business model?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll be really honest with you. We know the content we have, obviously. In previous calls, we did answer questions. All of you were very interested in the dollar content but we couldn't really disclose all that. But we have stated that in one of these wearables that's high end, the content could be close to what we get in a smartphone, for example.
 Now, in terms of the sell-through and the build pattern that the customer is going to use, we really don't know, don't have a lot of details of that, frankly. It is very hard to predict, I believe, because the acceptance level by consumers is not known.
 So, the shape of that curve, how much we build in the first couple of quarters and what follows is very difficult for us to predict. And I think a lot of people, obviously our Company and the investment community, are trying to figure this out. But we also don't have a really good answer, frankly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Pitzer,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's helpful, Tunc. And then maybe as a follow-up for Bruce, Bruce, just on the gross margin line, plus or minus you guys have been at that 60% level for a bit now. I'm just curious, is there a revenue level we should be thinking about to break out above the high end of that 58% to 62% range? Or is there a time line relative to some of the restructuring that we should start thinking about breaking out of the high end of that range?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think, certainly from a -- if you think of the two things that are going to drive gross margin, one is utilization and the other is the restructuring, are the two key things. I think from a utilization point of view, obviously with the challenges we had last summer around our largest customer and utilization drops in this last quarter, we are down at 60%. We think now that there's stability at that account.
 The ability to start driving up utilization, as all of the rest of our businesses continue to grow nicely, I think that will provide the growth in the utilization. And you can track that over time. I think we even provide a chart in our supplemental earnings presentation around utilization levels and you can track that with revenue.
 The other side is the restructuring. As we've said, the savings there, the $10 million related to the San Jose fab closure is over 18 months, and really, we'll see that in FY16. But that's going to get you about 1.5 points, if you think of $10 million, 1.5 points of gross margin by itself.
 And then some of these other actions specifically around MEMS is we did have some equipment for MEMS which will also -- as a result of these actions, the depreciation expense associated with those will go down. If you put all that together, I think our view is our 61% to 64%, there's no reason, structurally, we should not be able to operate in the upper half of that range. That's certainly what -- if we get utilizations back over the 80%, we get our restructuring plan in place, that's our model to get that up into the upper half.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Pitzer,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, guys. I appreciate it. Congratulations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Covello from Goldman Sachs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Covello,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just following up on John's question there, Tunc you'd made the comment there that now that your biggest customer is stable, if we go back a year, we thought the biggest customer was stable and we were looking forward to higher utilization rates at that point. Compare and contrast today to back then, if you might. And then if you could share with us what your plans are on a qualitative basis for utilization rate increases over the next couple of quarters, that would be great. Thank you so much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. On your first question, you are reminding us of some of the painful moments that we went through last year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Covello,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Me, too.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 When we look into the future this year, what we're seeing is that, essentially, the content we've got is pretty close to what we had in the prior phone. We have reduced both our customer and, as a result, we have reduced the unit volume forecast for the phone, which we had not done that aggressively last year. So, we really have moderated what our expectations are in terms of the unit sales of their flagship phones.
 Another headwind we had last year was the effect of, in their mid-range phones, the decisions they made on their processors also resulted in some amount of loss for us, which is not present right now because that business is not in our plans at all. So, we basically have reduced the forecast that we have compared to last year. Certainly, our customer, our largest customer has done the same. That's why we feel better than we did last time.
 And the other piece of this is that they are a smaller part of our business right now, anyway, compared to where we were last year about this time. So, all of this gives us some confidence that this year, hopefully, will not be a repeat of what we saw last year.
 Now, you are going to have to remind me of the second question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Covello,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 First of all, thank you for that great explanation. But then in conjunction with that, on a qualitative basis, if you could tell us what directionally you're thinking about utilization rates over the next few quarters.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In terms of utilization rates, we do expect, if all goes as planned, we do have revenue that's expected to go up next quarter as we forecasted. That, obviously, will begin to help. I don't think in the very near term we're going to get to the utilization levels that Bruce mentioned, which are probably further out at higher revenue levels.
 But it will all depend on that revenue level and it will be pretty close. Bruce indicated that we actually do have a chart of utilization levels versus margin. But you can also look at utilization levels versus our revenue, as well. We didn't put that on that same chart, but it's a pretty easy exercise and it will give you some idea of what revenue levels we get to the utilization levels that are in the upper end, or to us much higher than 60%, or the old levels which are about 80% or so can be achieved. So, it's hard to tell the timing, but I don't believe that we're really that far away in terms of revenue increase that we might see in the coming quarters.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jim Covello,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks so much for that. Good luck.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Chin from UBS.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Chin,  UBS - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The first area I wanted to drill down on was the decision to move away from the consumer MEMS and touch insert business. Firstly, can you talk about how this might impact some of your investments in other non-consumer areas? Because, if I remember correctly from your analyst day, some of these technologies were, I think, targeted to be applied into automotive and some other adjacent areas. And, secondly, does this impact your biosensor investments at all?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, love to answer that. Let's take them one at a time. You really were asking about the impact of stopping investments in consumer MEMS and in touch and other areas. That question is, there is some impact.
 First of all, let me just clarify, make sure that we are clear about it. Even though we're stopping investment in consumer MEMS, we're taking those resources and going to apply them to automotive. That business we can continue to grow because the superior performance of our products are valued by their customers.
 Now, we obviously have to resize the amount of investment and that will be done over the next couple of quarters so that we have the R&amp;D portion commensurate with the size of that market. That decision, obviously, we're investing in automotive so that answers that question.
 The second was in touch. We'd said we could use that technology, and really use it to support automotive customers or applications, as well. Obviously, with the stopping investment that really is not going to work so that will have some impact on the automotive side of the business.
 The investment in bio and environmental sensors are pretty much independent of this, so those go forward. Where we can add value in mobile with those types of sensors, we are seeing traction, and we do continue to invest in those as a growth area.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Chin,  UBS - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great, that's helpful. As a follow-up, I wanted to ask about the enterprise power management business. You guided that to be flat for this quarter. I was wondering if, with the new Grantley server cycle still ramping up, what is the old Volterra business exposure there? And longer term, what do expect or how that should perform later in the cycle? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll take that. When we look at our server business in near term, I think, as most people know, we see softness at our largest customer. That's been playing out over the last year. The large enterprise server OEM customers have not done as well in that market, so that has impacted Volterra business.
 I think as far as the next-generation platforms, we knew going into the acquisition that that was not going to be as strong an opportunity for Volterra and, so, from that point of view any ramps in that area aren't as meaningful for us.
 And, really, the thesis going into the acquisition was around moving into the cloud computing area. And as Tunc mentioned in his opening remarks, we believe that it's a very good opportunity for us. We believe having very good traction working with some of the large cloud providers and doing servers that are optimized for the cloud environment. And that's an area where we believe in early FY16 we should be able to start seeing the initial ramps of those efforts. That will take time to ramp overall, but I think the initial indications are very good.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steven Chin,  UBS - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thanks, Tunc. Thanks, Bruce.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava from BMO.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce, I had a question on the 30% operating margin goal. Is it fair to assume, then, based on your earlier comments, that you are essentially baking in a seasonal June quarter and combined with the cost savings and the utilization going up, does that supplant that 30%? And then I had a quick follow-up, as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think, given the impact that we had last summer from a revenue point of view, I think that's going to question the timing of when we would achieve the 30%. Obviously, we're being very aggressive, as we announced last quarter and this quarter, on the ending side. And certainly the other side of that is from a revenue point of view.
 From our point of view, without giving guidance, obviously, for the fourth quarter, I think there's, as I indicated, still open questions there. So, I wouldn't necessarily tie it down to a specific quarter. We've talked about revenue levels where we should be able to get close to the 30%, and certainly our commitment is we'll just keep driving until we get to it. But I think tying it down to a specific quarter right now is still probably a little bit early.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So, what's the revenue level, if you could please remind us again, Bruce. Sorry.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think most people -- and we've just directed people back to June of last year, when we were around $645 million or so of revenue. And we were at 25% of operating margin. And then you identify the 3 points from the restructuring that we identified last quarter. We had some inventory reserves back in June of last year. And, so, that got you 4 points. And then, either you need a little bit more revenue or a little bit more cost cuts. So, I think in the mid $600 million is where I think most people have modeled that opportunity to get to a 30% op margin.
 I will say, as evidenced by the actions that we've taken, we're clearly focused on this, we're clearly continuing to manage our spending. And we remain optimistic that we're seeing a sustainable growth pattern for us.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you for the clarification, Bruce. And I gave you guys a hard time last earnings call. You guys are clearly taking some great actions in helping us, those who have stayed with you.
 My quick follow-up, then, for you, Tunc, is, we've talked about China for a while. When you talk about diversification of customers, is China a factor that will start to kick in as we exit this year? Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the Chinese front, just to give you a state of the union right now, we remain at a relatively low revenue level. I assume your question was about our smartphone sales, not the other business that we have. Is that correct, by the way?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, Tunc it is -- on you mobile side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the mobile side we are at a relatively low revenue level with the Chinese smartphone market. We do have content in multiple Chinese OEMs. And it's primarily driven by our power SOC sockets and just beginning on some audio DSM products.
 But it does take time to build these relationship with these customers. The challenge that we face is that there are a lot more SKUs than in the other two large smartphone OEMs. So, it takes time to really be able to get design wins in these multiple SKUs and really build momentum.
 So, I think that, as I said, it's relatively low right now. I do expect this to begin to grow next year. But it really is an effort to diversify the base, but it's not really going to be as large as the two customers that dominate this market because there's so many different models to win and it takes a lot more product.
 So, our strategy in China is to take the IP that we internally developed for some of these functions and find ways, with minimal R&amp;D, on making products that are fewer features for the Chinese market, because, in general, as you can tell from their own phone ASPs, the content is much less than it is in a flagship phone from the leading customers. So, it will contribute to revenue, increase revenue next year. But in the end it really does not make a huge difference in terms of revenue we can achieve from them.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ambrish Srivastava,  BMO Capital Markets - Analyst   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks for all the color. I appreciate it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Blayne Curtis from Barclays.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Blayne Curtis,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just wanted to follow-up on the mobile side. When you look over the last five, six years, you've had some fits and starts with products, and you're making the decision to get out of your MEMS and touch, which I think people were asking for you to do last call. So I applaud you for doing that. I was just curious, as you look at some of the new sockets you're winning, how do you look at this being sustainable?
 You had talked about integration as being the glue. Some of the content that you are adding may not be integrated well together. I'm just curious, as you look at your portfolio of mobile, will you have to make some hard decisions on some of your other products down the road?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 These are decisions that we have to review and make and see what the market dynamics are for each of these products. Currently, if I were to categorize it, we're going into the future. We're investing in three areas in mobile.
 One of them is power, which has always been; our strong position in that market is pretty well known. The second one really has been in audio, and that's a market where -- I would say we were a late entrant and one might say we shouldn't have done that either. But we really turned it with new technology that's highly valued by the customer, and began to grow that revenue at multiple customers. The third area we're investing in is, basically, sensors, meaning biosensors, environmental sensors, and so on.
 You are correct. These products have to be refreshed every cycle and every year. But we do have strength in that area. We're very agile in product development and new technology adoption. And the fact that they do change, the needs change every year, is actually good in one aspect because it leaves little room for competitors to be able to duplicate our efforts.
 Now, having said that, periodically we look at what the prospects of each product line is. And if one doesn't look like it's going to have the returns that fit our business objectives, then we'll get out. And, on the other hand, if we find some that we can really show and demonstrate real value to our customer, we'll get in. So, it's a dynamic field and we have to keep making these decisions of being able to invest in some and not invest in others when the time comes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Blayne Curtis,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. I do want to ask you, the opposite of mobile is probably auto, now repositioning MEMS to auto. That business you bought was originally focused there. So, were you able to keep that effort going as you're focused on mobile or are you starting over again in that end market? If it does great, will take quite a long time to get wins ramped there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Actually, thanks for asking that question. It allows me to clarify it. When we did acquire SensorDynamics and they had an effort in mobility -- you have a very good memory. No, actually, they had an automotive effort, no mobility effort. So, you remember that well.
 But at the time of the acquisition, we actually kept both developments alive. Obviously the mobility one was pretty visible, and we talked about that because it was quick ramp to revenue. But we did develop automotive products that had really good fail-safe features and high levels of accuracy. So, we did continue with that automotive investment.
 Currently what we're going to do is really put the resources that are appropriate for automotive and continue on the path to get to revenue. It will take, obviously, more time to get the automotive revenue. But regardless of that, we do know that we have differentiated technology and great IP in that acquisition that will help us.
 So, it's a continuation, really. It's not a switch from one to the other.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Blayne Curtis,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thanks, Tunc.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael McConnell from Pacific Crest Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael McConnell,  Pacific Crest Securities - Analyst   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce, just a clarification. The comment that your largest customer would be flat to slightly down in the March quarter, is that just the difficult compare versus the December quarter and the growth that you've got there that was not expected? Or should we think more of the benefit from the new flagship phone coming out being more impactful to the June quarter, to you?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think when we said flat to slightly down, that was as a percent of revenue. I was responding to Ross's question there about managing the concentration level.
 Overall, that business could actually be probably flat to slightly up if you look at absolute dollars. But the overall business, with the strength that we're seeing through our diversification efforts within mobility, with the growth that we are seeing, the strong growth that were seeing in automotive, and really we had indicated all of our markets are going to be up, was why I responded to Ross's question as a percent of the business that could be flat to slightly down.
 In answer to your comment that you made, you are correct in that it was stronger in the December quarter than we thought from that point of view. I think most people think that the Note 4 and the S5 are probably better than fear. And we've seen some stabilization there. So, I think that's a positive so the quarter-on-quarter compares are impacted a little bit by that.
 And the flip side is, again, I think your comment is accurant around the ramp of the new phone and is Samsung going to be a little bit more prudent in how they manage that ramp, both for the March quarter. And I would suggest, even -- we don't know, of course -- but potentially for the June quarter to try to manage inventory levels a little bit better coming out of the launch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael McConnell,  Pacific Crest Securities - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. And then just on the wearable device, the benefit from a build standpoint to the Company, will that continue, do you think, into June? Or, at that point, when we get into the June quarter it's really going to be dependent on sell-through for a continuation of that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As Tunc indicated, really, we just don't know, from that point of view. A, I don't think we have unique insights into what the sell-through and demand for this product will be. And, B, if we did, we couldn't say. But the short answer is, we don't know.
 I think we know what we're told. And, certainly, it's going from nothing to something. So, that's going to be positive for us. We have good content and then it's just up to how well this product sells.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael McConnell,  Pacific Crest Securities - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Understood. Okay, great. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Hettenbach from Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Hettenbach,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just following up on the wearables outside of just the focus on the flagship wearable coming out, can you give any color in terms of what you're seeing from a design perspective, and how broad of a category you think this could be from a customer basis as you move forward?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 From our design wins and the products that we have in some of the wearables that are out there, if you exclude the flagship one that's coming out -- and I liked your term, flagship. We had not thought about using that. We do have content and most of the content we've got in other wearables is currently mostly around power management type products.
 Obviously, the advantages we provide there is the level of integration, just trying to shrink the size of the overall solution because in a wearable -- in a smartphone, if we consider it if the space is limited, in a wearable it's even more limited. As a result of that, in some fitness applications and some specialty health applications, and just basic smart watch applications at other customers, we've been able to win many power products.
 Having said that, the volumes are not really that high for this category. In my view, maybe the suppliers have not really found that killer app that every consumer wants to have. But we do have the right technologies for that and it really plays to our strengths. Integration, also power operation, these are all very important.
 The battery management functions become very important for the customer and, in turn, they turn to us to give them solutions that can fit into the application. But the uptick from the end consumers has really not been that strong. Most of you already know this. I'm not telling you anything new.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Hettenbach,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Thanks for that. And then, as a follow-up, good to see the discipline around the MEMS and touch. If I would extend that further, can you touch on just your view or thinking of how you approach return on R&amp;D investment, particularly in areas like mobile that could be a little more volatile and rapid change in product cycle? So, looking out in time, how you're looking to invest in that market versus some other verticals that are stickier.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The way we think about it is that we do understand, obviously, that the mobile market, or consumer markets in general, can be a lot more volatile which means the risk profile is higher. The good news is that whether you're succeeding or not, the feedback you get is quicker, as well, which is good. But when we're making decisions on allocating resources, we try to pick projects or product lines that have higher returns basically, so that it offsets the higher risk, just like any investment decision that you make in that market versus the other markets.
 From a return time viewpoint, you really get the returns in two or three years rather than seven or eight years that you get in automotive. The decision process is just that, we expect higher return in those markets than we do in longer-lived products or more sticky markets, like in automotive or industrial or communications products. So, that's the way we think.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And, Craig, this is Bruce. I think, just as Tunc said, we always are looking for those opportunities where we think we have a sustainable advantage and which meets our profitability target.
 A perfect example, as Tunc talked about, one of our invest areas is in power management within mobility. We've had a power management socket since 2008, at least, when I joined, in the first 3G Samsung phone, and have held that power management socket.
 So, I think to the extent that we provide true value to the customer, and it's a sustainable differentiation, we're able to hold that, and, I think as most people know, at a good return. I think the key question is where are those markets where that's difficult to do. And, as you can see by our decisions today, if we don't think we have that advantage, then we will make that decision and stop the investment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Craig Hettenbach,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tore Svanberg from Stifel.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tore Svanberg,  Stifel Nicolaus - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 First, on the consumer MEMS, was that a decision based on profitability metrics, or is it more the size of the market, maybe meaning customers are starting to insource that technology more?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the consumer MEMS side, it is actually an interesting -- and I will give you some of that background I gave in my prepared remarks. We, and our team -- and I'm really proud of our team -- they were able to develop, in my mind, a great product. It had far lower power consumption and much better stability or accuracy than the products that we saw out there.
 However, these performance features we realized were really not valued by the customer, meaning that they were not valuing these, that they were not able to pay, or not willing to pay the prices that we would require to get our profitability metrics. So, when we realized that, and this happened, actually, pretty recently, frankly, we saw that was the dynamic in the market that caused us to realize that having a great product but the customer is not needing that performance, it is a signal that it would be hard for us to win sockets at the profitability levels that we expected in the market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tore Svanberg,  Stifel Nicolaus - Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for that color, Tunc. And maybe as a follow-up to Bruce. Bruce, when we look at gross margin and utilization, would it be accurate to think that what really helps utilization would be more your industrial and automotive businesses, while your consumer businesses have less of a positive benefit on utilization?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In general, our industrial products, more of them are done internally. Our consumer products can be done, generally, both internally and externally. Industrial growing is a positive thing for utilization.
 But we're also very actively managing, even for those products that can be done internally or externally, to find the right balance, to maximize our internal fab loading while continuing to support our external partners. So, while one can be done more internally and the other one can be done in both, I think we try to manage both to maximize utilizations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tore Svanberg,  Stifel Nicolaus - Analyst   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. If I could just sneak in one quick cash flow question. Right now CapEx is at 3% of revenue. How long can you stay there before we start to see a new CapEx cycle?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bruce Kiddoo,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CFO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our view is, we don't see another major CapEx cycle. And that's primarily because the next-generation technology after 90-nanometer will be outsourced completely. So, from that point of view, we don't see a major fab requirement.
 We have plenty of available space to grow in our test capacity. And we continue to look at opportunities to begin to do more of an outsourcing of that, as well.
 So, I think for us, what really drives CapEx today is, A, as the business continues to grow you need to continue to add testers. And then, to the extent that we are looking at very specific technology development to help us truly differentiate our products, whether that may be some of these sensor products, there's an investment there, as well.
 But, overall, we believe our CapEx is coming in at a very low level in this quarter, but I think most people know we normally net out the purchase of assets with the sale of assets. This quarter that number, actually, was a negative, meaning the proceeds were greater than the expenditures. But even without that, like you said, we were at the very low end, 3%. Obviously, we were a negative number if you count the proceeds.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tore Svanberg,  Stifel Nicolaus - Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Perfect. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Smigie from Raymond James.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vince Celentano,  Raymond James - Analyst   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is Vince Celentano in for Steve. I want to talk quickly about the financial terminals. Could you go through a little more about the correlation you're seeing between the growth in mobile payments in the US and the increase in demand for financial terminals?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll take that one. In terms of financial terminals, we do have a good market position in what I would call the fixed terminals in the market. This is a business we've actually developed almost over a decade or even more.
 But what we're seeing now is many vendors, or many people that want to make payments, they want the capability to do mobile payments. That really opened up a whole new market opportunity for us because our highly integrated solutions are really best suited for these tight spaces. And the security requirements we know how to meet because we have made generations of products that meet the certification requirements for security.
 What we're seeing is a lot of activity by actually new entrants coming into the field -- that's what I said in my prepared remarks -- coming into the field. And with our reference designs, actually, we are making it very easy for new people to make these mobile payment terminals.
 We see that as the large growth area all over the world, not just in the US, but in Europe, as well as in Asia, as well. So, it is a good growth opportunity for the Company and we're seeing a huge number of design wins, basically because of the fact that we have the product and we have the reference design.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vince Celentano,  Raymond James - Analyst   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. Thank you. I have just one more follow-up. From a macro standpoint, given all the weakness we have seen in Europe, does this have any material impact on the most recent quarter? And do you see it having any impact in the March quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Tunc Doluca,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - CEO   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are essentially asking what the global economics and what's happening and what's the effect of that going to be on Maxim. We certainly do watch what happens in Europe and we do see the no growth environment, so to speak. And we do see some of the slowing that's coming from China.
 The US continues to be stronger in terms of growth. We look at the industrial market, which is probably the broadest base that we've got, and probably the best signal of what the economic activity is like.
 But we really are not, even though we watch this very carefully, I'd be wrong if I said that we will not be affected by some major global economic issue -- all the indications we see so far don't show that. We're seeing the resales are healthy, and we're really not seeing a major slowdown in these regions. So, the signals are not there.
 But, obviously, all of us in the Company look at the news coming through. And that is indicating these slowdowns in actually two areas -- Europe and in China.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Vince Celentano,  Raymond James - Analyst   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. This does conclude the question-and-answer session of today's program. I'd like to hand the program back for any further remarks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Ta,  Maxim Integrated Products, Inc. - Managing Director of IR   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you, Jonathan. This does conclude Maxim Integrated's conference call. We would like to thank you for your participation and for your interest in Maxim.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for your participation in today's conference. This does conclude the program. You may now disconnect. Good day.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q2 2015 Maxim Integrated Products Inc Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>SUNNYVALE</city>
  <companyName>Maxim Integrated Products Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>MXIM</companyTicker>
  <startDate>22-Jan-15 10:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>104233</companyId>
  <CUSIP>57772K101</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2573760</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US57772K1016</ISIN>
</Event>