<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="2726217" lastUpdate="Friday, March 12, 2010 at 5:43:30pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="2726217.F" expirationDate="Friday, March 12, 2010 at 3:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of NEM.TO^F12 earnings conference call or presentation 12-Mar-10 3:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q4 2009 NEO MATERIAL TECHNOLOGIES INC Earnings Conference Call

Toronto Mar 12, 2010 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Neo Performance Materials ULC earnings conference call or presentation Friday, March 12, 2010 at 3:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Alex Caldwell
      Neo Material Technologies - Corporate Secretary
   *  Michael Doolan
      Neo Material Technologies - CFO
   *  Constantine Karayannopoulos
      Neo Material Technologies - CEO
   *  Shannon Song
      Neo Material Technologies - EVP Magnequench Division

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Daniel Kim
      Paradigm - Analyst
   *  Steve Arthur
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Justin Wu
      GMP Securities - Analyst
   *  Frederic Bastien
      Raymond James - Analyst
   *  Youssef Abboud
      Clarus Securities - Analyst
   *  Yuri Lynk
      Canaccord Adams - Analyst
   *  Russell Stanley
      Jennings - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. My name is Christopher and I will be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the Neo Material Technologies, Inc. fourth-quarter results conference call. (Operator Instructions). I would now like to turn the call over to Alex Caldwell, Corporate Secretary. You may begin your conference.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alex Caldwell,  Neo Material Technologies - Corporate Secretary   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, operator. Good morning everyone and thank you for attending Neo Material's fourth-quarter 2009 financial results conference call. To help you prepare for today's call you should have received a copy of the fourth quarter 2009 news release. 2009 consolidated financial statements and the MD&amp;A were filed on SEDAR this morning. Copies of the news release, financial statements, and MD&amp;A can also be downloaded from our website at www.NeoMaterials.com.
 Following the presentation the management team will respond to analyst questions. Alternatively, analysts, investors and members of the media may direct their inquiries to Ali Mahdavi at 416-962-3300, extension 225. Unless otherwise indicated, all the financial information reported in this call is denominated in US dollars.
 Certain statements made in this conference call are forward-looking, may not give full weight to all the potential risks and uncertainties, and are subject to risks and uncertainties. These forward-looking statements speak only as of the date made, and actual results, actions or events could differ materially from those set forth in these forward-looking statements.
 The Company has not undertaken to update any information in the foregoing reports until the effective date of future reports required by securities laws.
 On the call today are Constantine Karayannopoulos, President and Chief Executive Officer; Michael Doolan, Chief Financial Officer; and Shannon Song, Executive Vice President, Magnequench Division.
 I will now turn the call over to Michael, who will provide a review of Neo Material's results, followed by Constantine's overview of the business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning everyone. For the year ended December 31, 2009 the Company reported revenues of $187.5 million and net income of $19.7 million, or $3.17 per share on a basic and fully diluted basis.
 Operating income, plus depreciation and amortization, EBITDA, for the year was $35.1 million. This compares to 2008 revenues of $266.6 million, net income of $23.6 million, or $0.22 per share on a basic and fully diluted basis, with EBITDA of $48.8 million.
 The year-over-year reduction in revenues, EBITDA and net earnings was due to the global recession, which impacted all of our end markets, resulting in a significant drop in demand for the Company's products.
 More importantly though is the Q4 to Q4 comparison. For the fourth quarter of 2009 we reported revenues of $62.8 million and net income of $8.7 million, or $0.07 a share on a basic and fully diluted. EBITDA during the quarter was $14.6 million.
 This compares to fourth-quarter 2008 revenues of $46.6 million, a net loss of $700,000, or a loss of $0.01 per share on a basic and fully diluted basis, with EBITDA of $1.8 million.
 We have finished 2009 very strong with solid momentum, and as the world recovers, this rebound in Neo's results demonstrates just how essential the materials we supply are in everyday life.
 Constantine will provide divisional commentary in a moment, but I would like to make a few comments from a corporate perspective about our quarterly and annual results. Additionally, as this is the first call of 2010, I will address some housekeeping issues.
 Looking at the P&amp;L first. The inclusion of Recapture in this quarter will make quarter-over-quarter comparisons difficult. For example, purchase accounting requires that all assets and liabilities acquired are initially recorded at fair value. In particular this means that the Recapture inventory at the time of acquisition has been recorded at net realizable value, and as such when sold contributes no gross margin. This was the case for Q4 2009, and this will continue into the first quarter of 2010.
 The reduction in SG&amp;A is due in large part to management actions taken late in 2008 and through the early part of 2009 as a reaction to the global turndown. In the fourth quarter the savings are not as apparent as it now includes Recapture.
 When looking at the year-over-year comparison, please recall that the 2009 numbers include over $2 million of expenses related to the (technical difficulty) battle and OSC hearings in the first half of the year. Looking ahead into 2010, I would suggest a runrate for SG&amp;A expense of around $7 million per quarter.
 The stock comp expense of $2.5 million for the quarter and $6.6 million for the year is primarily the mark to market of our shared-based incentive plans, and reflects the strong recovery in our share price from the beginning of the calendar year 2009.
 The decrease in depreciation and amortization was due in part to intellectual property and other assets having been fully amortized or depreciated early on in the year, and then offset by the inclusion of Recapture in Q4. For 2010 D&amp;A will return to around 2008 levels or approximately $11.5 million.
 R&amp;D expenses are up year-over-year. And as we indicated on prior calls, R&amp;D was one area that even during the recession we did not cut back on. The increase is primarily due to increased activity within Magnequench, and in particular the Magnequench Tianjin, as well as the pickup of Recapture R&amp;D in Q4.
 I am pleased to report that as a result of the Tianjin activity, we were able to obtain the status of an advanced high-tech technology enterprise within China. But entitles the Tianjin Company to a preferential tax rate of 15% as compared to the statutory rate of 24%. Again, for 2010 I would suggest a run rate for R&amp;D of about $2 million per quarter.
 And on the income tax front we finished the full year with an effective tax rate of 23%, up slightly from 2009, in part because of the change in business mix resulting from the inclusion of Recapture. For 2010 I would expect the rate to be back down around the 20% area.
 If you did not already notice in our press release we restated the first three quarters of 2009 to correct the method of translating inventory drawdown from renminbi to US dollars at the Performance Materials rare earths plants in China.
 This resulted in an increased operating income, net income and EBITDA of $1.4 million, $0.3 million, and $0.2 million in each of Q1, Q2 and Q3, respectively. Within the financials this is reflected as a reduction to cost of sales and an increase to inventory.
 We finished the year strong -- we finished the year with a strong balance sheet and a healthy cash balance of over $57 million. As the economy recovers and Neo's business continues to grow and expand, some of the cash that we were able to squeeze out of working capital will find its way back into receivable and inventory balances, especially as we are seeing upward pressure on our raw material costs.
 We are well prepared and have the balance sheet to execute on the Company's growth strategy. I look forward to an exciting year ahead. Now I would like to turn the call over to Constantine.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning everyone, and thank you for joining us for Neo Material's year-end 2009 conference call. As you can hear, we are both battling colds, so I apologize ahead of time for clearing my throat. I will start with a review of 2009 and the fourth quarter, and then I will provide more specific divisional fourth-quarter operating details. Then finally I will close with our outlook for the coming quarters.
 It is gratifying to see that Neo Material's has exited 2009 with significant momentum. The global economic crisis deeply damaged countries, companies and individuals. It forced businesses of all sizes and in all sectors to take drastic measures to save themselves and ensure the survival of their ongoing operations.
 Neo was unavoidably impacted by the year-long global economic crisis that started in the fall of 2008. But our relentless focus over the past few years on strengthening our balance sheet, paying close attention to what our customers were telling us, and having all of our employees rowing in the same direction during the depths of the storm, helped us prepare for and navigate through these difficult times.
 During the summer of 2008 Neo's Board and management foresaw an impending slowdown in consumer spending and demand for our products in our end markets. As a result, we implemented a number of cost containment strategies, with the major focus on preserving cash as the world economy slipped into a recession in the second half of 2008.
 With massive inventory corrections throughout our supply chains multiplying the negative effects of reduced consumer demand, 2009 started off poorly, to say the least. However, we knew that our balance sheet would provide good protection for our business and keep us relatively sound.
 During the fourth quarter of 2008 and the first quarter of 2009 we reduced costs in all areas, including taking extended maintenance shutdowns and reducing working hours at all of our production facilities. This allowed us to maintain our overall employee levels, the respective skill, as well as employee morale, thereby preserving our ability to ramp up production quickly as demand started to recover in the second quarter.
 During the second half of the year our Magnequench Division quickly returned to historical levels of demand and profitability, while our Performance Materials Division continued to build momentum. We expect Performance Materials to return closer to its historically levels of production, revenues and profitability in 2010.
 Neo was well prepared to take advantage of attractive and opportunistic acquisitions due to the strength of the balance sheet. On August 31, 2009, we completed the acquisition of Recapture Metals. The expansion of Neo's offerings with Recapture's complementary products and capabilities has given us a footprint in new, growing and exciting applications, while also diversifying our production base beyond the Asia-Pacific region.
 Our integration efforts continue to be on track, and we are excited by the prospects of the minor and rare metals growth platform that Recapture has brought to Neo.
 The fourth quarter continued the trend of sequential improvement in volumes, reflecting an improvement in demand across business units, product lines, and most applications and market segments. During our third-quarter conference call I reported to you that our order book continued to indicate a strong recovery in demand, which was clearly manifested during the fourth quarter. This strength has maintained its course into the new year, notwithstanding even the traditional fourth-quarter, first-quarter seasonality, which sees a slowdown in Asian manufacturing during December and the Lunar New Year.
 Michael has already reviewed the key overall performance figures, so I will focus my comments primarily on the divisional fourth-quarter details. I will start with Magnequench, where operating income was $15.1 million on revenues of $32.9 million, compared to $4 million and $21.9 million, respectively, in the fourth quarter of 2008.
 Note that in cases like this comparisons to the fourth quarter of 2008 aren't all that meaningful. But still at 274% year-over-year improvement and operating income on a 50% revenue improvement sounds pretty good.
 Revenues and operating income were down from the third quarter by $1.1 million, as a result of high raw material costs and lower average selling prices. Lower ASPs were the result of product mix -- of a product mix rather -- that saw a higher percentage of strategic new application volumes, and a $2 a kilogram price reduction that kicked in in September, reflecting significantly lower raw material prices that had persisted since the beginning of the year up to that point.
 Neo powder volumes grew year-over-year, as well as sequentially, from 777 tonnes in the fourth quarter of 2008 and 1,268 tonnes in the third quarter of 2009, to 1,293 tonnes, even though normally the business is seasonally slower in the fourth quarter. The fourth quarter volume of 1,293 tonnes is a record fourth quarter for the Magnequench division.
 Traditional base business segments, such as hard disk drives, performed rather well in the quarter. Shipment volumes, however, were flat to slightly weaker than in the third quarter as some of the seasonal patterns returned to this part of the business. In addition to this, the hard disk drive market experienced some supply shortages for certain components, which constrained the production of new drives. Given this anomaly and the seasonal slowdown of this market for Neo powders, we are pleased with the performance of our base business.
 Shipments for new applications, such as electronic, power steering, and home appliance motors, were very strong in the quarter, and where one of the catalysts for our record volumes. A number of new applications that were originally slated for commercialization in late 2008 or early 2009 were effectively shelved at the time as the economy slowed. They are now being rolled out and that is having a noticeable effect on our new business volumes.
 Magnequench, along with its customers, continues to benefit from the end market demand for more energy-efficient products, especially in the automotive and home appliance air-conditioner markets. Our applications group has never been busier. Let me give you some examples. A number of new programs are nearing commercialization in automotive seat motors, where most Japanese, Korean, Chinese and European car companies have applications in the pipeline. This is in addition to programs that are always commercial.
 Residential hot water recirculation pumps in Europe, and one of my favorite applications that I have talked about before, ceiling fans using Neo magnet motors in India. This application is starting commercial production in May, having received -- having recently received a five star energy rating from the Indian Bureau of Energy Efficiency. A standard induction type ceiling fan sells for about $24 in India, while a 50% more energy-efficient Neo magnet fan sales for $36. Payback is less than a year in energy savings alone.
 A recent release from NIDEC, which some of you may have seen, announcing the construction of a new facility and R&amp;D center for automotive motors at its manufacturing complex in Dalian in China, has reinforced the drive towards greener, smaller, more efficient components for automobiles. The existing NIDEC plant in Dalian is already one of our -- one of the largest users of bonded Neo magnets, and we expect it to continue to get bigger as a result of this expansion.
 Price for certain rare earths, including neodymium, Magnequench's primary raw material, increased substantially in the fourth quarter. However, the cost impact of the increase on our margin was limited, as we consumed relatively lower priced raw materials purchased earlier in the year. We will continue to monitor the prices of our primary raw material inputs and adjust their Neo powder prices as necessary, as we have done in the past.
 As we work through the first quarter of 2010, we continue to see strong end market demand, coupled with relatively low inventory levels. The hard disk drive market is expected to grow as demand increases, driven by ultra low end laptops and netbooks, in China especially, and as its supply shortages are rectified.
 Moreover, we expect to see an increase in air-conditioning -- in our air-conditioner fan motor business in the quarter, as the air-conditioning markets hit their peak prior to the spring and summer months.
 Let me now turn to the Performance Materials Division. Fourth-quarter sales were $31.6 million on 1,954 tonnes. A noted increase over Q3, as demand in most of our major market segments continued to show improvement. Sales volumes increased in all geographic regions. Japan and the US, however, were the primary contributors to the increase in sales over Q3.
 Operating income in the quarter was $1.3 million compared to a loss of $150,000 in Q3 and the loss of $2.9 million in the fourth quarter of 2008. This significant improvement was the result of higher volume sales, improved selling prices, and lower production costs, which positively impacted gross margin. The benefit of lower cost raw materials purchased in the first half of 2009 worked through our inventories and margins have returned to their historical range.
 The dollar per kilogram unit margins are actually better than they appear, because a substantial order in the quarter was for commodity grade lanthanum oxide that we sold for a large customer at very low margins. We do not expect this type of business to repeat often.
 Our major market segments demonstrated continued signs of improvement. Magnetic demand was strong through the quarter, with high purity glass for optical lenses, phosphorus and electronics also demonstrating improvement.
 The demand improvement seen in Q4 has continued into the first quarter of 2010. Visibility on the other hand remains limited, and we expect our customers will continue to monitor their inventories closely.
 Both light and heavy rare earth raw material costs moved higher in the quarter, but still remain below the peak levels seen in 2008, although they are getting closer. We expect our production costs to increase as a result of higher cost raw materials, but in the near-term this entry should be mitigated by higher selling prices.
 The integration of Recapture is well underway. You will recall that Recapture produces, reclaims, refines and markets high-value niche metals in their compounds, which are primarily used in the wireless, light emitting diode or LED flat-panel displays, solar and catalyst industries. During the quarter 14 tonnes of gallium were sold to or sold on behalf of customers.
 The rhenium recycling operation in Napanee, Ontario continues to scale up, and we expect commercial sales in the first quarter of 2010.
 Over in the mid-to long-term we continue to expect global demand for the minor metals and rare earths we produce to increase, driven by uses in energy-efficient lighting, solar, hybrid electric cars, micro motors for energy-efficient devices in wireless communication. We believe the division is uniquely positioned to capitalize on this growing demand.
 Our project with Taboca, Minsur, and Mitsubishi Corp. in Brazil is moving through the pilot stage. Delays related to regulatory and transportation issues, as well as the import of certain drilling equipment, had been largely dealt with, and we expect the two laboratories that we have engaged to be starting the process development and actual processing work in the second quarter of this year. Early large-scale indications regarding the extraction of a suitable heavy rare earth mineral concentrates are quite encouraging.
 Now turning to the quarters ahead. We are looking forward to a strong year in 2010. We expect to see sustained increase in demand across both divisions for existing and new applications. In turn, our revenue and earnings power will continue to fuel the strength of our balance sheet, enabling us to identify and take advantage of our strategic growth opportunities. We continue to review accretive opportunities on an ongoing basis, while remaining truly focused on our organic growth. We are confident that the combination of our growth efforts and free cash flow generation will result in a larger and stronger Neo in the years to come.
 Needless to say, 2009 saw our Company experienced unprecedented lows during the first half, which turned into strong highs in the second. Our recovery would have been much more difficult without the continued loyalty, hard work and commitment of all of our employees. I wish to thank them sincerely. I would also like to thank our shareholders, partners and customers who stood with us during the challenging times.
 I look forward to reporting to you on the progress of the Company with our first-quarter conference call in May. And now I would like to ask the operator to open the call to any questions.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Daniel Kim, Paradigm.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Kim,  Paradigm - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Congrats on the quarter. Constantine, my first question is with regards to the [MPL] division. Neo prices have obviously been on the move. You suggested that the input prices are starting to move as well. I am wondering if you can quantify the impact it might have on Q1.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, you have asked me the wrong question. I can't talk about the Q1, really. Naturally we have not increased prices yet. We are in negotiations with our customers for price increases. I would not expect to see an effect of any price increases in the first quarter. I think it is reasonable to expect that price increases will take place in the second.
 I think the trend that you saw from the third quarter to the fourth to the first -- those should continue into the first in terms of the margin impact. However, as I did say in my comments, we are seeing very strong demand, and we are frankly a bit surprised on the lack of seasonality. We have seen lack of seasonality in previous years, but that was masked by either price increases or price reductions that really affected volumes. So this year we are not seeing that yet.
 So I am fairly bullish on the near-term, at least as far as we can see. As I said in my comments, we expect continuing growth in demand. But margins on the other hand will -- unit margins will be under a bit of pressure as higher cost raw materials are working through the P&amp;L. But again, like we have always done before, we take care of that with price increases.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Kim,  Paradigm - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are we seeing the same dynamics now happen on the Performance Materials side of your division as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, in broad strokes I would say yes. But keep in mind that the Performance Materials business is a very different -- has very different dynamics overall.
 Magnequench is effectively the market for Neo powders, and as a result, we need to be careful, as I have said before in other conference calls, not to pick winners and losers among our customers with our pricing strategies.
 And also we are working very hard with our new applications where powders -- we price our powders at lower levels compared to our base business. Again, it is a discussion we have had before. When our customers have alternatives then we can only price to their next best alternative. And that means if we are trying to convince customers to use Neo magnets instead of ferrite magnets, we are limited as to what we can charge. So naturally pretty well all of our new applications and strategic programs [at our] lower prices, and that part of the business is really growing like wildfire. So that is another factor that is putting pressure on our margins, because it is -- that segment is at lower selling prices.
 On the rare earth side -- on the Performance Materials side of the business, rather, there is a quite a bit of competition. There is no ability for any of the producers in the space to absorb raw material cost increases, so there the price increase impact is fairly immediate. And because there are really no long-term contracts in that business, all transactions are done on spot prices, prices move fairly quickly. So we have already started moving prices. As soon as we started to see raw material -- raw materials moving, our prices started moving as well. So it is a much more immediate effect on the Performance Materials side of the business versus the Magnequench side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Kim,  Paradigm - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Now could you comment at all then with regards to the new applications that you are seeing, what type of pricing environment you are seeing -- if you need to be fairly aggressive on the pricing to win this kind of marketshare in these new applications or not, compared to say your seat motor applications years ago?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, the seat motors are at new applications prices. We tend to have -- again, in very broad strokes, the kilogram -- the dollars per kilogram margin in our new applications business tends to be about order of magnitude half of what our normal dollar per kilogram gross margins are in the base business. Again, I can't give you a lot more visibility on that without really providing selective disclosures. Sorry.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Kim,  Paradigm - Analyst   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Just two last questions then. Number one, I wonder if you can give us an update on Brazil. Number two, unrelated to that, I saw in the press -- trade news that Baotou Hi-Tech has received some kind of approval to build a rare earths stockpile in China. I am wondering if you can comment on how that is going to impact you, please.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Brazil, as I said in my comments, what we have seen -- what we continue to see is pretty encouraging. We did hit a snag starting sometime in the summer. We had been expected to ship container loads of tailing samples out of the mine to two laps, one in Australian and one in Ontario. Actually I was in Australia three weeks ago and I visited the pilot plant and the lab that is going to do the work, very impressive.
 However, we hit some transportation and export restrictions or red tape, if you want, which have been overcome. And the containers are loaded and they are ready for shipment now in Brazil. So that took us -- and I'm not making this up -- it took us about six months to get through all that red tape, which unfortunately we were not expecting to take this long.
 Also, we are -- not we, Taboca, the mining company, is redrilling all tailing sites to recharacterize the deposit. And that hit a lot of red tape regarding their ability to import highly specialized drill, an ultrasonic drill that is ideal for tailings to use it. So what they tell us that finally they got approval to bring it into the country. So I expect that hopefully this -- starting perhaps next quarter that work will pick up pace considerably.
 Again, we are targeting with Taboca and Minsur and Mitsubishi at sort of the end of the year to have -- to make a decision on whether we will go to the next step and start designing specific equipment, and going on to the next phase of building a concentrator at the mine, which suggests that quite a bit of work needs to be done between now and then. But we are optimistic that it will get done. And so that is as far as Brazil goes.
 Baotou Hi-Tech, again it is -- I have said this before, but there's an awful lot of noise, both in the press, and both in the press release wars fought by junior mining firms that have woken up one day and discovered that they had rare earths in their backyard. I am naturally a bit cynical about this whole process.
 Of course, when news comes out of China, invariably because very few people, very few commentators that have emerged in the rare earth industry know what they are talking about, either about the industry itself or about China, invariably you get the wrong interpretation of events.
 The press release that Baotou Hi-Tech issued -- the Baotou Hi-Tech is the subsidiary of Baotou Steel. It is publicly listed in Shanghai. I believe it is trading at 70 times trailing EPS, which I think it is awfully nice.
 On the other hand, they have been working on this for years. Baotou Steel generates tailings from its iron ore mill that go into a very large tailings pond. These are iron ore tailings. Well, they happen to be one -- to be the largest and richest rare earth resource in the world. On the way to the tailings pond Baotou Hi-Tech, the subsidiary, takes a 20% cut off that tailings stream and recovers pretty well more like rare earth than the world needs.
 Well, what they have been talking about for years now is instead of sending the 80% of that stream, which is quite an attractive resource still, instead of sending it into the tailings pond where it gets mixed with other tailings and other wastewater and the like, and fundamentally that changes its chemistry and recoverability eventually, they have been asking the government for permission to allow them to process all of it and extract all of the rare earths available to it.
 Clearly because there is no demand in the market for all of the rare earth contained in that tailings stream, they asked for permission to build a series of warehouses where once they recover the rare earth concentrate they can store it. Their estimates are that they will need to build storage for about 300,000 tonnes of rare earth -- of contained rare earth oxides in that concentrate.
 So the -- I have seen some pretty ridiculous claims that China has decided to cut off supplies of rare earth products to the rest of the world, and they will be stockpiling for their own needs and so on. That is pretty ignorant drivel.
 Baotou Hi-Tech -- and we talked to the regulators two weeks ago when we were in Beijing. They're pretty clear the approval is for the stockpiling of rare earth concentrates, not finished products and so on. Which could also suggest that there could be a glut of concentrates, and perhaps that, depending on what Baotou Hi-Tech decides to do, that could lead to perhaps a more flexible pricing strategy for Baotou Hi-Tech. I hope that's clear.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Daniel Kim,  Paradigm - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's great. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Arthur, RBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Arthur,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Most of my questions have been addressed, but just one. Just to follow up on capacity, I haven't asked about it for quite some time, I guess. You have seen a solid recovery in the shipments across both the sectors, in particular Performance Materials this quarter. Any sense of where you're running at now in terms of utilization rates at these levels and where you might reach in 2010?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. The Performance Materials are still running comfortably. We did have that one quarter that I mentioned for commodity grade lanthanum. Without that in the mix, we are still running at somewhere -- depending on which plan we are talking about, between 70% and 80% of capacity. Of course, once we get closer to 100% there is always debottlenecking and tricks that we have up our sleeve that we can push that a little bit more.
 I also would remind our listeners that we -- if you recall, we sold one of our plans in 2007, early 2008, to Minmetals. And we have an agreement with them to manage the plant, and we have rights on its output. So if we had need for more materials out of our heavy rare earth plant, that need would be met from Minmetals.
 In fact, we have already started sourcing product from Minmetals, because for some selective elements we are close to running out of capacity. And as we have talked before, it is a balance issue. You never have demand that reflects exactly the rare earth composition in your feed material. So there is always elements that we are short of and there are always elements that we are long of. So the arrangement we have with Minmetals is working out quite well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Arthur,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And on Magnequench, still good amount of room there?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, yes. Magnequench, we are good. As we have talked before, even though I guess when you look at the rate of growth and the volumes we did in the fourth quarter, and where we expect that to be in the first quarter and beyond, the conclusion would be that we are getting pretty darn close to or nameplate capacity, if not above it.
 But as we have talked about in the past, over the years we have debottlenecked, and we have done some pretty creative debottlenecking and expansion and reengineering of the jet casters, primarily in Tianjin, but also in Korat.
 So we expect that our true capacity is in excess of 9,000 tonnes a year. So I don't think we will get there in 2010 (multiple speakers).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Arthur,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thanks very much. I will pass the line.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu, GMP Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My first set of questions is for Michael, in terms of inventory at Magnequench. I was wondering if you can talk about your raw material inventory situation there in terms of perhaps months of supply of Nd oxide.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, as you're aware, we are running down inventories in the early part of 2009. We are currently sitting on roughly about a month of raw material.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So basically your cost of that raw material, is it pretty close to where market is?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Currently. As Constantine mentioned, we had been benefiting from lower cost material working its way through, but that is going to start to show up -- the higher cost, I mean, is going to start to show up in Q1 and beyond, and Constantine indicated that we may have to respond accordingly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I am just trying to reconcile what you said earlier, Constantine, in terms of you said -- I think you said that you expect the margin performance to continue into the first quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. The trend I expect it to continue, yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, the trend as in slightly lower than what we saw in Q3 or level -- because obviously your raw material costs are going up, and you haven't increased prices yet.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So --?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I think especially when you look at what rare earth prices are doing, what neodymium prices are doing right now, and you project that through the P&amp;L you'll see a continuing margin erosion, that is why we will have to raise prices.
 On the other hand, when we look at inventories, don't forget that there is a fairly long chain. Even though we do have neodymium oxide on hand, that oxide has to be converted into metal, which has to be converted into alloy, which has to be converted into powder before it gets shipped. So there is a fairly long process.
 So by the time today's -- we expect that today's -- if we are buying raw materials today, that would hit effectively our P&amp;L as a sold product sometime in the second quarter. So there is that sort of lag effect. But there is no --.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The increase in the raw material costs are offset in part by better unit margins because of the increased volumes. So as long as we are seeing that then we get better unit plant utilization as well. So that helps to mitigate it somewhat, but it won't do it forever, obviously.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As we have said before, we were very focused on managing both businesses on a dollar per kilogram margin basis. Ultimately that is only a tool that we have, because the ultimate objective is to make sure that our bottom line grows. And that is -- so it is a game between margins per kilogram times the volume, and we are very bullish on volume growth as well.
 So, yes, I would expect unit margins to come under pressure in Q1. Again, nothing dramatic, along the lines that you saw -- along the trends that you saw before. But I also expect that our bottom line will be positively impacted by the continuing volume growth and the reduction, as Michael said, in unit variable costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just moving on in terms of new applications. Constantine, would you -- were new applications greater than 50% of your mix in the quarter on a volume basis?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, actually the new applications, and again it is something we have been talking about for years, the new applications volumes are growing faster than our base volumes. That is where the bulk of the growth is. And that, I think, eventually will be the future of our business. So we're very, very focused on new applications. So yes, in the quarter they were about 50%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So basically crossed over in the quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In terms of NIDEC, you had talked about a bit, the power steering motor applications, can you talk about what kind of volumes you are shipping for that business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I could, but I don't think I should. I don't think either Daido Electronics, our immediate customer for what we call Magnequench's [U] powders, which they turn into Magnequench free magnets. It is all jargon. I don't think they would be tightly pleased if I talked about that level -- or NIDEC, or neither would NIDEC be thrilled.
 I guess what I can say is that we saw these volumes shrink to their lowest levels in recent memory in the first quarter. And they're now probably closer to their highest level. So, yes, that business is growing, and we are told that over the next couple of years we should see a very significant increase in those volumes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Do you know if those motors or those -- all the different programs that they have, if they are 100% bonded or is there (inaudible) in that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, again NIDEC is one of the producers of electronic power steering motors. I believe the largest portion of those motors are Magnequench or Daido. They use Daido magnets. They also make motors with [Centered Magnets]. And other companies also make motors with Centered Magnets, so no, it is not all Magnequench, or it is not all [made] with Magnequench powders.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just in terms of some of the other applications -- new applications, when do you see them having -- like the seat motors, for example, I am not sure when that -- when did that program launch, and are you seeing critical mass on that program now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Again, it depends on our definition of critical mass. Our very first customer was a Japanese company, a motor company that I have talked about in the past. That business now runs with these customers -- again, it is in the early stages. They are shipping those seat motors to Europe to European models. I think we are shipping something in the order of 5 or 6 tonnes a month for that program.
 I expect that the seat motor application to be one of our fastest growing applications, because we do have some commercialization happening in -- or rather being rolled out as we speak between now and 2012. And I would expect that by that time when all of the programs that are in the pipeline become commercial, this will be one of our more significant applications.
 It might even -- I guess, when you look at our overall pie, our overall distribution among applications, it could almost, but perhaps not quite, double our current automotive exposure.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Justin Wu,  GMP Securities - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. It is helpful.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Now interestingly, I guess one thing that for me was very useful, I am sure for applications guys it wasn't news. In a lot of these programs, whether it is from Japanese producers or European producers, in addition to the weight and the energy savings, one of the main driving forces here is size reduction.
 As you move into more and more functionality in the average car, under the seat it gets awfully crowded. So we have had more than one customer tell us that, yes, they like the energy efficiency and the weight reduction, but that is not their primary objective. The primary objective is to make more room under the seat so they can stick more motors and more heaters, coolers, fans, cables and whatever else goes under a motor of a car, which is a pretty interesting way of looking at it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frederic Bastien, Raymond James.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frederic Bastien,  Raymond James - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was wondering if you and Mitsubishi are currently working on other opportunities at this time, other than the mine in Pitinga?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And as far as we know, Pitinga is one of the projects that we are working on together. We are looking at a possible opportunity in Southeast Asia, but that is still very early days. As far as I know Mitsubishi is working on nothing else related to rare earth. They are, though, looking at a number of lithium opportunities, primarily in brine lithium developments. But I don't believe they are working on anything else on rare earths.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frederic Bastien,  Raymond James - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I was just wondering if you could give us a bit more -- maybe clarity or color on -- you mentioned the high sale of the low-margin material, the lanthanide -- lanthanum in the quarter. I was wondering if you could give us an approximation of the magnitude of the volume and the impact it might have had on the average selling price.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It was in the order of 500 tonnes for the quarter. And it was -- I think by the time it moved through, was close to zero, let's say single-digit percent margins.
 I wouldn't expect that to repeat. I would still see growth in the rest of the volumes into the first -- with the first quarter and continuing strong margins, but I wouldn't -- we wouldn't be doing that very often. As I was saying, every once in a while some of our bigger customers come to us and they're looking for a bailout. They go short on some products.
 At the same time, because of what happened last year, we are not able to use up all of our export quotas room. So it served both parties. We used up a good chunk of our quotas and we bailed them out at the same time. We didn't make a lot of money on it, but I think it served both interests.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frederic Bastien,  Raymond James - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is not the business we're in, so as I said, I won't expect to keep doing this.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Frederic Bastien,  Raymond James - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fair enough, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud, Clarus Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The first question, Constantine, regarding Recapture, can you please give us an update regarding the integration? I know you mentioned you're going to use your distribution channels -- your supply channels in Asia to sell gallium. But can you update us what is going on on that front and what the strategy to drive volume over the next 12 months?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The integration is largely complete. And we have had quite a bit of work on the marketing front, plus the financial systems, accounting and production management.
 Again, the challenge in the quarter was what we always knew was going to be the case, which is Recapture was a private company. It was run approximating public company standards, but it was still a private company and not run as a public company, so we had to do quite a bit of work to change the accounting and costing systems. We have done that.
 On the marketing front, our sales group in Europe is now selling gallium. In Japan we have combined the gallium salesmen from Recapture with our Performance Materials salesforce in Tokyo. It is working very nicely.
 Also come in North America we have added gallium and indium and rhenium to the responsibilities of the Performance Materials sales organization in addition, of course, to the Recapture sales force that was in place. So it is more of an augmentation as opposed to a replacement, and it is just merging of the two groups. It is working out very well.
 I expect, again, because of Michael -- what Michael said that until we run through the Recapture inventories and we -- and freshly produced gallium finds its way through the P&amp;L in a meaningful way, I wouldn't expect a meaningful contribution to margins until probably sometime the middle of the year or so.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can you give just a rough idea about like volume or revenue what you would expect per quarter over the next few quarters -- what we should factor into our model?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 14 tonnes, as I mentioned, of gallium were sold in the fourth quarter. That is pretty good. That is pretty high. I would be doing back flips if we sold 14, 15 tonnes a quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That was at $400 per ton, right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, thereabouts, give or take. So again different grades, some of it is higher; some of it is slightly lower, but not much lower. In addition to that we are starting to make rhenium sales, and that is a pretty attractive product. And actually we haven't talked a lot about rhenium, which I think could be a tremendous growth opportunity for that business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If it works, when do you expect the impact to be?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As I said, middle of the year, third-quarter kind of timeframe.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For rhenium, not gallium only. For rhenium as well, right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, overall -- that impact will be a Recapture impact which includes rhenium and gallium. As a standalone, the rhenium it probably would be making a contribution before then, because we don't have any rhenium inventory. We just started to ship the stuff.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. Mike, just a question on the tax rate, you say 20%. And this is the average stocking to Q1. Should we -- or it goes lower as we progress?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, start in Q1, 20%. I am hopeful it will come in there less than that, and certainly we working towards a lower rate. But at this point in time I'm not prepared to signal anything lower than that at the moment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My last question is to Shannon, if she is there, is regarding the Magnequench Division. And I know Constantine he mentioned about the pricing strategy. He gave us some flavor about cutting prices in order to get into new application. Can you give us a flavor more when you negotiate with your clients, I mean, how you manage the issue, how you discuss with them the issue of volatility of raw material prices, so when they want to go and budget, for example -- sorry, (inaudible) materials instead of using ferrite magnet or Center magnet, how -- just if you give us more detail how things work out to convince them to convert -- take into consideration the cost issue?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Shannon Song,  Neo Material Technologies - EVP Magnequench Division   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As Constantine mentioned, the customer only pay (inaudible) whatever makes sense compared with their alternative. Our target for all new applications is ferrite replacement. We all know that that how the ferrite is, even though there are numerous benefits to use our magnet making new motors. So there is so much we can charge vis-a-vis ferrite. So our strategic programs, the volumes grow very fast, but strategic pricing would have to be very aggressive in order to get that volume.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You also asked about how do we handle volatility. And with strategic pricing we also make it pretty clear to customers that we cannot absorb significant price movements in the wrong direction. So it is like with every customer, we sit down and discuss with them price increases or price reductions, as the case might be. Frankly, I think for our Magnequench business this is one of the greatest impediments to having that business just explode with growth.
 If we had the ability to control our raw materials -- again, when we talk about security of supply and the efforts that we have into securing sources of supply, it is not so much that we are trying to secure access. We are trying to secure predictability of costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Correct, correct.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In which case, we could go to all of these strategic customers and do long-term deals for Neo powders, which would eliminate to some degree the volatility that we are seeing today. And if we could do that effectively, I think you could see a fantastic growth in Magnequench volumes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So what is -- how are you going to deal with that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, that is why we are in Brazil. Although Brazil is -- the Pitinga deposit is not terribly rich in neodymium. We having a number of discussions with other folks around the world in different parts of the world about doing -- if and when they are up and running, we would be -- we have had a number of discussions with folks about securing offtake agreements on the raw materials side.
 So we are not terribly concerned, as I said, about the security of supply. It is the pricing predictability that we are looking for. I think as a number of folks come onstream, and create competition for Baotou Hi-Tech -- like LYNAS, they are building their plant in Malaysia. Molycorp should be up and running in the next couple of years. There is companies around the world. Alkane in Australian has a very extensive pilot plant. There is companies here in Canada that are trying to go commercial and then mine deposits.
 I think pretty -- over the next 2 to 3 years we should be able to see some competition for Baotou Hi-Tech, and perhaps even the heavy -- if we could bring the Pitinga deposit into commercialization, we will be in great shape.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions). Yuri Lynk, Canaccord Adams.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yuri Lynk,  Canaccord Adams - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will be quick. I just want to talk about the cash balance, Constantine. It continues to grow, a cash generating Company, obviously. Are acquisitions still the number one use of cash here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Probably. Again, we can only say what we can say. We are engaged in a number of discussions with a number of folks that we've identified. We hope to put some of our cash towards that use in the not-too-distant future. But again, we are not in control of those timelines.
 But, yes, absolutely I think the use of our cash and perhaps adding some leverage would be the best way to deal with this, and to add cash and EBITDA generating capacity to our platform through acquisitions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yuri Lynk,  Canaccord Adams - Analyst   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 When you're looking at the universe of potential acquisitions, I would assume most of them are relatively small relative to the financial wherewithal the Company has. Do you think that there is room somewhere for a dividend in there, and is there any update on the Board's thoughts on dividend policy?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we just had a Board meeting this week. We did not discuss a dividend. Given the fact that we are a relatively small, medium sized company with a fairly good growth platform, I would think that -- again, if we are sitting here on this call two years from now and we haven't done anything with the cash, yes, I would say we be nuts not to have a dividend. On the other hand, if we can put that cash to good use and provide an accelerated growth to the Company, I think that would be a better use for cash.
 But as I said, we are in a number of discussions. For the time being I don't expect the dividend in the next few quarters. We are in the middle of discussions with a number of folks and that would be the primary use for our cash.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yuri Lynk,  Canaccord Adams - Analyst   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I will turn it over. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Russell Stanley, Jennings.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Russell Stanley,  Jennings - Analyst   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A quick question for me. Given where you stand on the utilization front, should we be thinking about a normal $5 million to $7 million in maintenance CapEx for 2010?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Perhaps a little higher than that. But, yes, not -- there is an additional business at Recapture. We have a few areas of investment that we are seriously looking at for CapEx.
 Magnequench, we are expanding certain capabilities. For example, last year we started a program to make -- to increase our in-house alloy making capacity. What that does is it gives us a much shorter timeline from when neodymium goes from metal to alloy. Plus, we bring it in-house. We do it on our own at a lower cost than we can do it -- then we can buy alloys from our alloy vendors.
 Overall I would say we are probably in the ballpark, but perhaps a little higher than that. Michael, do you want to --?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Michael Doolan,  Neo Material Technologies - CFO   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. I guess in terms of the routine maintenance capital, sustaining capital, yes, I would suggest you're probably spot on. But given Recapture and some of the projects that Constantine was referring to, it is going to be high single digits for the year, I would suggest.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Russell Stanley,  Jennings - Analyst   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's great. Thanks, guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In terms of -- organically, in terms of the CapEx within the business, we have made it very clear to the organization, especially Magnequench, that we will not hold back investment for any project that either brings new products to the table, or reduces costs, or improves the overall competitiveness of the Company.
 Again, when we are looking at good growth and strategic applications we need to be able to bring our costs basis down, in addition to variable fixed costs decreases as a result of volume growth. So we are looking at a number of projects that will improve our capabilities and reduce costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Russell Stanley,  Jennings - Analyst   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Perfect. Thanks for the color.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud, Clarus Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I want to clarify something I heard before about the new application. The new application you mentioned represented 50% of the total volume of Magnequench, or they grew by 50%?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, no. They are slightly above 50% for the overall volume.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh, of the total volume?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Youssef Abboud,  Clarus Securities - Analyst   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, perfect. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There are no further questions at this time.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Constantine Karayannopoulos,  Neo Material Technologies - CEO   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, thank you all for your attention. And we will talk to you again in May with our first-quarter conference call. Thanks again.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q4 2009 NEO MATERIAL TECHNOLOGIES INC Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Toronto</city>
  <companyName>Neo Performance Materials ULC</companyName>
  <companyTicker>NEM.TO^F12</companyTicker>
  <startDate>12-Mar-10 3:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>85807</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL />
  <ISIN />
</Event>