<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="6105833" lastUpdate="Friday, October 21, 2016 at 4:37:01am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="6105833.F" expirationDate="Thursday, October 20, 2016 at 9:00:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of PBCT earnings conference call or presentation 20-Oct-16 9:00pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q3 2016 People's United Financial Inc Earnings Call

BRIDGEPORT Oct 21, 2016 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of People's United Financial Inc earnings conference call or presentation Thursday, October 20, 2016 at 9:00:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Andrew Hersom
      People's United Financial, Inc. - SVP of IR
   *  Jack Barnes
      People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO
   *  David Rosato
      People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Ken Zerbe
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Bob Ramsey
      FBR Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Collyn Gilbert
      Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst
   *  Travis Potts
      Jefferies &amp; Co. - Analyst
   *  Matthew Breese
      Piper Jaffray - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good day ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the People's United Financial, Inc. third quarter 2016 earnings conference call. My name is Andrew and I will be your coordinator for today. At this time all participants are in a listen only mode. Following the prepared remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session.
 (Operator Instructions)
 As reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes. I would now like to turn the presentation over to Mr. Andrew Hersom, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations for People's United Financial, Inc. These proceed, sir.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hersom,  People's United Financial, Inc. - SVP of IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good afternoon. Thank you for joining us today. Here with me to review the third quarter of 2016 results are Jack Barnes, President and Chief Executive Officer; David Rosato, Chief Financial Officer; Kirk Walters, Corporate Development and Strategic Planning; and Jeff Hoyt, Chief Accounting Officer.
 Please remember to refer to our forward-looking statements on slide 1 of this presentation which is posted on our website, Peoples.com under Investor Relations. With that I'll turn the call over to Jack.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Andrew. Good afternoon and as always we appreciate everybody joining us today. The company's performance continues to reflect business momentum generated through our consistent solution oriented approach to banking. We have always partnered with clients to deliver thoughtful straightforward solutions that address their financial needs.
 During the quarter, I spent time meeting with our relationship managers and their clients across the footprint. As I often do throughout the year and a very much enjoy. These visits enable me to see firsthand how well we are meeting clients' needs. Once again I came away impressed with the strength of our relationships and the quality of the clients we do business with. The feedback I continually receive is that our approach to banking differentiates us in the market.
 In combination with our extensive suite of products and services, this approach has enabled us to deepen existing relationships and develop new ones. As a result, we have grown the loan portfolio for 24 consecutive quarters while maintaining exceptional asset quality. And over the same period, nearly doubled our deposit base and increased wealth management assets under discretionary management by approximately 40%.
 Now turning to the overview of the third quarter on slide 2. Our results for the third quarter reflect further improvements in profitability and continued growth in earning assets. We are pleased to report record quarterly net income of $74 million which increased 8% from both the linked and prior-year quarters as well as generated a return on average tangible equity of 10.7%. The efficiency ratio of 59.9% reflects a continued gradual improvement in this metric and demonstrates our focus on enhancing operating leverage through ongoing revenue growth and proactive expense management. Solid growth in both net interest income and noninterest income drove revenues higher by 3% on a linked quarter basis and 4% compared to the prior-year quarter.
 Expenses of $218 million which exclude $3.1 million of merger-related costs were up approximately 2% from both the second quarter and prior-year quarter primarily as a result of higher compensation and benefits costs. In the third quarter, we continued to optimize our branch network with the closing of four branches. Since the beginning of 2011, we have closed 65 branches which were mostly traditional branches. During the same timeframe, we have opened 26 branches, the majority of which are more cost efficient in-store branches.
 We remain confident in our ability to further control costs as a mindset of actively managing expenses has become very much ingrained in the culture of the Company. The loan portfolio continued to benefit from our diversified business mix. Annualized loan growth during the quarter was 5%, particularly strong results in residential mortgage as well as commercial and industrial lending. On an average basis, annualized loan growth was 8%.
 Looking ahead, the fourth quarter historically has been our strongest quarter in terms of loan originations. With pipelines ending the quarter at very solid levels, our current view is for the trend to continue. Our success gathering deposits was evidenced by annualized growth of 9% from the end of second quarter while the passive deposits declined 1 basis point.
 Recently released FDIC deposit data show our market share percentages either increased or remained consistent in each state we operate. We are particularly pleased with our continued number one market share position in Fairfield County, Connecticut and the State of Vermont.
 Before turning the call over to David to discuss the quarter in more detail, I want to take a moment to comment on our pending acquisitions. Closing and integration processes of the Suffolk Bancorp and Gerstein Fisher transactions are progressing very well. We are working closely with teams at each firm to execute our time-tested acquisition approach. We expect to close Gerstein Fisher in early November and continue to move toward closing Suffolk pending regulatory approvals.
 As a result of these integration activities over the past few months, we have come away even more excited about the expected benefits of each of these transactions, particularly the talented people that will be joining us. Each of these transactions will further grow and strengthen People's United in the New York Metro area. Since the beginning of 2010 we have made substantial progress in expanding our New York franchise both organically and via acquisitions. Over this time we built C&amp;I and commercial real estate teams in the New York Metro area, entered Manhattan with a branch on Park Avenue and Incorporated our broader stack of products and training into the branches we acquired in the 2010 Smithtown and 2012 Citizens Branch transactions.
 Additionally, we have hired local talent that both knows the markets and is well known in the market. Collectively these investments over the last six years have enabled us to significantly grow our New York loan portfolio and deposit base. This progress gives us even greater confidence in our ability to successfully continue to move our franchise forward in the New York Metro area. With that I'll pass it to David.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Jack. Turning to slide 3, net interest income increased $5.3 million or 2% on a linked quarter basis. Primarily driven by ongoing loan growth. Net interest income also benefited $1.7 million from an additional calendar day in the third quarter and $400,000 from lower deposit costs. Primarily as a result of higher average non-interest-bearing deposit balances.
 Furthermore, it is important to note the increase in LIBOR rates at a modest favorable impact on NET interest income of approximately $1 million in the third quarter. The primary offset to these increases was a $1.4 million decline in accretion from runoff of the acquired portfolio. Net interest income was also negatively impacted by $800,000 in higher borrowing costs and $500,000 from lower yields in the securities portfolio.
 Moving to slide 4, net interest margin of 2.80% increased 1 basis point from the second quarter. A higher loan portfolio yield and the additional calendar day in the third quarter each benefited the margin by 2 basis points. While the lower securities portfolio yield and higher borrowing costs rapidly reduced the margin by 3 basis points. On slide 5 you can see loan balances increased $330 million or 5% annualized from June 30 with growth in both our retail and commercial portfolios. Originated loan growth for the quarter totaled $376 million. Retail contributed $234 million of originated loan growth, which was driven by continued strong residential mortgage growth of $249 million, partially offset by lower balances in the consumer portfolio.
 As we have grown our residential mortgage portfolio in recent years, originations continue to be very high quality. The portfolios LTV and FICO metrics have remained consistent and the overwhelming majority of business retained on the balance sheet continues to be hybrid adjustable rate mortgages. For originated loans added to the portfolio during the first nine months of 2016, the average LTV is 68% and the average FICO is 762. Originated loans in the commercial portfolio increased $142 million, driven by C&amp;I growth of $141 million.
 We experienced solid production across several C&amp;I categories including large corporate, middle market, and asset-based lending. While end of period mortgage warehouse balances of $1.2 billion were consistent with June 30, average balances for the quarter were up $117 million. We experienced the [quandry] load runoff of $46 million for this quarter, compared to $73 million in the second quarter. The remaining balance of the acquired portfolio at quarter end was $645 million.
 Slide 6 shows the change in deposits by segment. Deposits grew $657 million or 9% on an annualized basis during the third quarter primarily due to higher non-interest-bearing and municipal balances. Commercial continued to benefit from franchise wide deposit gathering efforts and grew $755 million or 32% annualized during the quarter. As expected, the seasonality in our municipal business had a favorable $255 million impact on quarter end commercial balances. Retail balances declined $98 million or 2% annualized as the third quarter represents a seasonal low point for retail deposits. Following historical trends, growth is expected in the fourth quarter.
 On slide 7, we look at non-interest income which increased $5 million or 6% compared to the second quarter. Insurance revenues increased non-interest income by $2.8 million reflecting the benefit of recent acquisitions as well as the seasonal nature of insurance renewals which are higher in the first and third quarters of the year. Non-interest income also benefited from several categories including increases of $1.1 million in operating lease income, $1 million from net gains on the sales of residential mortgage loans, and $600,000 in bank service charges.
 In addition, the $2 million increase in other was driven by higher income related to a distribution from an acquired equity investment partnership. The primary offsets of these positives was a $2.1 million decrease in commercial banking lending fees, primarily due to lower commercial real estate prepayment fees resolving from a reduced level of pre-activity in our markets. On slide 8 we illustrate the key components of changes in non-interest expenses on a late quarter basis. Excluding $3.1 million of merger-related costs, which are reported in professional and outside services, third quarter expenses were $218.3 million, an increase of $5.4 million or 2.5% from the second quarter.
 Compensation and benefits increased $4.7 million primarily reflecting the impact of an additional work day and higher benefit related costs in the third quarter. The higher benefit related costs were driven in part by one additional payroll in the quarter. The largest offsets to these increases was $1.8 million in lower professional and outside services costs due to the timing of certain projects during the quarter. Before moving to the next slide, it is important to mention the FDIC role requiring banks with over $10 billion in assets to be responsible for recapitalizing the Deposit Insurance Fund which became effective on July 1. We anticipate the impact of the surcharge is expected to increase regulatory assessment expenses by $2.5 million to $3 million per annum.
 On slide 9 you can see our efficiency ratio in the third quarter of 59.9%, improved 50 basis points from the second quarter and 180 basis points from a year ago. As Jack referenced earlier, this resolve demonstrates our continued focus on enhancing operating leverage through ongoing revenue growth and proactive expense management.
 Slide 10 is a reminder of our exceptional credit quality across each of our portfolios. Originated non-performing assets as a percentage of originated loans and REO at 63 basis points remains below our peer group and top 50 banks and has continued to improve from recent quarters.
 Net charge-offs improved from already low levels to 4 basis points. The lowest level in over nine years. These levels reflect the minimal loss content in our non-performing assets. As shown on slide 11, both return on average assets and return on average tangible equity improved for the second consecutive quarter. Return on average assets of 73 basis points increased 3 basis points on a linked quarter basis and was consistent with the prior-year quarter.
 Return on average tangible equity of 10.7% increased 60 basis points from the second quarter and 20 basis points from a year go. Notwithstanding these improvements, our returns continue to be impacted by the low interest-rate environment. Turning to slide 12, capital levels at both the holding company and the bank continue to be especially strong in light of our diversified business mix and history of exceptional risk management.
 As previously discussed, we plan on issuing 200 million to 250 million of preferred before year end enabling a more optimal capital structure and enhancing our already strong capital position. While all of our regulatory ratios are above internal long-term operating targets, this issuance will further bolster ratios in the range of 60 to 80 basis points to support continued growth. On slide 13, we display our interest-rate risk profile for both parallel rate changes and yield curve twist. As you can see we remain asset sensitive though slightly less than last quarter.
 We remain well-positioned for an eventual increase in interest-rates, particularly in an immediate parallel shock scenario as our loan mix continues to trend towards floating rate loans. At quarter end, over 44% of the loan portfolio was either one-month LIBOR or prime-based compared to 43% at June 30 and 41% a year ago. Sustained lower long-term rates remain a headwind for our risk position as evidenced by our Long End down scenario on this slide.
 Before passing the call back to Jack to wrap up, I wanted to point out we revised our estimate for the full year effective tax rate resulting in an effective tax rate of 30.6% for the third quarter. The effective tax rate through nine months of 2016 is 32.4%, a decrease from 33.4% for the full year of 2015 due to our continued investment in tax preference items. With that I'd like to pass the call back to Jack for closing remarks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, David. In summary, we are pleased with our third quarter performance which includes record quarterly net income, improvement in the efficiency ratio to 59.9%, continued loan growth highlighting our diverse business mix, sustained exceptional asset quality and strong deposit growth along with lower-cost of deposits. Our integration and closing processes with Suffolk and Gerstein Fisher acquisitions are progressing very well and we are excited about the expected benefits of each of these transactions. We continue to build our readiness to cross the $50 billion asset threshold through our B50B project which we discussed in detail last quarter.
 Our goal is to complete this process internally over the next few years and avoid unusual one-time costs. We remain committed to consistently returning capital to shareholders as today the board declared a dividend for the 93rd consecutive quarter. As such, the board and management understand the importance of the dividends and a significant impact that it has on valuation of company shares. Therefore it is important to remind both current and prospective shareholders we will not move the company past the $50 billion asset threshold without knowing we have regulatory support for our dividends.
 This concludes our presentation. Now we will be happy to answer any questions that you may have. Operator, we're ready for questions.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe with Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you. Jack, you seem pretty positive in the growth in New York going forward. I am looking at the portfolio, obviously there's been a lot of growth in C&amp;I and very little in CRE. When you think about the opportunities in New York, is it solely a C&amp;I kind of opportunity or would you expect to accelerate CRE growth, given potentially other firms pulling back?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I know we are very optimistic on both parts. We have a great C&amp;I team there and we've made really great, what I would call steady progress through that timeframe. Built a really nice team and have good customer base. I also think the Suffolk team joins and integrated, I see a lot more progress on that front.
 When I think about pre-book, I know we have mentioned and announced fairly recently the addition of a senior executive in the New York market, and Mark Melchione and he has brought in a very experienced team and we are very excited about their progress. We've had some closings already and we have a very strong pipeline and we are looking forward to a positive impact there. That is what we would call our traditional pre-book. We're looking for relationship customers that will have multiple transactions with us and deposit relationships very similar to what we've experienced across the rest of the franchise. So we do continue to move away from the New York multi-family smaller transactional piece. So we see a lot of opportunity as we move forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Understood. Okay. That makes sense. David your comments about the tax rate, right at the very end there, does that imply that the tax rate is going to be lower in fourth quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. No. It's not. It will be the same. 32.4%. So we were accruing at 33.5% through the first two quarters. And we trued that up. That's all it is.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So third quarter is a little lower and fourth quarter is back to the full year. I understand.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Full year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Okay and then just one last question on the merger cost. I think Suffolk if I remember right was somewhere around $38 million of merger costs. Does that already include the $3 million that you took this quarter and what is the timing of how those might come in over the next few quarters?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The $3.1 million included costs associated with both Suffolk and Gerstein Fisher. You will probably see a small amount of costs in the fourth quarter and then the restructuring charges when we close the deal. Which should be first quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just want to remind or maybe give you more perspective on the New York lending just to make sure I interpret your question right but we really have a New York customer base that includes the customers in ABL, equipment finance, large corporate, a lot of business banking activity. So while you ask about C&amp;I and CRE if you think about our total business across the New York Metro area, it includes all of our business lines.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it, understood. I think I was just more mentally building in like ABL, etc. into the C&amp;I bucket.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Broadly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ken Zerbe,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. All right. Perfect. Thank you guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you Ken.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey, FBR Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hey, good afternoon. Thanks for taking the questions. Curios first, which line items of the $3.1 million of merger charges run through?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Professional and outside services.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. Perfect. And you mentioned the increase in FDIC assessment industrywide. Is that -- that's already in this quarter's number though, is that right?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Good.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 About $900,000. Actually $700,000.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then I guess if I back out the merger charges, I get earnings of about $0.25 this quarter, that annualizes to about $1.00. Is there any reason to think that next year earnings wouldn't be at least at that level, excluding the merger charges next year as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 They were not prepared to give any guidance for next year at this point.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. For modeling purposes, is it fair to put Suffolk sort of at the very start of next year or do you think it might be closer to the end of the quarter? Like the first quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's not in our hands at all and very difficult to call. I think you're going to have to make that decision yourself. It is purely in the regulators hands, and we have no idea when we will get any final answers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, fair enough. And then I guess on the preferred issuance, you guys have been talking about this for some time. Any sense of timing on when that will actually take place?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 As we said, and what we've been saying consistently for at least a year and a half is the size and in the back half of 2016. So on the calendar it continues to move forward but we can only be as specific as before the year is over.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That's a narrow enough window. That is fair. I guess last question and I will hop out. But you obviously had a good quarter for provision expense. I think previously you all have been talking about a number more like $10 million to $12 million. Is that still a good way to think about the fourth quarter or do you think where the world sits today it come under that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think that is still a good place in terms of looking at it. I think everybody recognizes now and through our history we have had very low nonperforming levels and charge-offs and it gets pretty bumpy at these levels. Every once in awhile you have an asset that turns heads so I think planning in the range you are talking about is appropriate.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Bob Ramsey,  FBR Capital Markets - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert, KBW.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert,  Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Good evening everyone. Just back to the discussion on loan growth. Jack, I appreciate your comments about New York. That is very helpful but if we think about how the composition of loan growth has evolved so far this year, CRE balances are down from the beginning of the year, consumer balances are down but reg mortgage balances are up quite a bit. Is that strategic in nature? Is that more just where the market is taking the portfolio? Can you give a little bit more color as to what might be driving the shifts in some of those loan balances?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. So I will go to where you started first with the CRE thinking. There is a dynamic taking place right now that involves the pullback from the New York multi-family portfolio. That is running off and we are still gauging the pace of that. Probably somewhere between $20 million and $40 million a quarter. But we will see how that goes. It has slowed as of late.
 On the other hand, we have obviously a large customer base across the rest of the footprint and now a very strengthened group in New York, and we are getting I would say good origination. I expect we will start seeing some growth in CRE as we go forward. And the only contrary I guess or signal I would give there the market does seem to be a little slower, a little softer in terms of transactions this year. So that's CRE.
 C&amp;I is very steady across the middle market. Starting to see a little better progress on business banking. ABL is having a very strong year. Mortgage warehouse is having a very strong year even though they had a flat quarter if you will or a modest quarter. And equipment finance is also doing reasonably well although slower overall than it has been in the past. And so on the residential and consumer side, the residential side there is a shift going on, the mix of purchase and refi is kind of 50/50 lately and the volumes are strong is, the pipelines are strong. The branches tend to do a little less purchase so the refi as it slowed down I think is affecting that.
 We are getting a lot more activity through the mortgage originators, mortgage account officers and we are adding as we have told you the past mortgage account officers particularly inside 495 in Boston and in New York. So those numbers of mortgage originators are up fairly considerably. And then our wholesale business is seeing a good amount of activity as well. So it's a mix of the channels if you will in the residential area. The consumer I think consumer has been flat and continues to be on the flattish side and it tends to build as we build households and it tends to pull back when refi is more active and people tend to roll their home equities outstandings into fixed rate longer terms. I just want to correct I said $20 million to $40 million a quarter. And it is monthly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 The $20 million to $40 million of multi-family runoff is per month. Not per quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert,  Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Okay that's helpful. That's good. Thank you, Jack. And then David on the margin, so 2 basis points benefit this quarter because of the calendar. Is it safe to assume that if we back that out then maybe with the trend we see moving into the fourth quarter, lower securities yields perhaps and you got the tickup as you mentioned from LIBOR that we could see some new compression coming in in the fourth quarter or do you think we have hit a low point and maybe we stabilize here?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 If you notice you have seen the pace of NIM compression slow dramatically and then this quarter actually it went up a basis point. It is too early to call a bottom in the NIM. There still is a small and shrinking differential between the existing loan portfolio and new business. And you are correct, you saw about an 8 basis point decline quarter over quarter in security portfolio yield. So the way I would answer the question is, are we buying guidance on the margin with 275 to 285 in July and it looks like we are on track to be right there in the middle of that guidance plus or minus.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert,  Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That is helpful. And then just -- the other other income line for you guys has just really been building quite a bit. What is in that line and is there anything in particular that is causing that build?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I did call out the $2 million increase was driven by an acquired private investment partnership. So there is a little bit of that in that line. That was about a little over $3 million in the quarter. There is a lot of little things that go through there. Credit card fees is probably one of the larger drivers that has been growing. We talked about that before, where a few quarters ago we entered an agreement with Elan, and we are getting a lot of traction in our customer base adopting the credit card offering that we now have. That was almost nonexistent over the last couple of years. That is the primary driver. But the rest of the stuff our fees around some retail, home equity, HELOC accounts. Things of that nature.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert,  Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. That's helpful and then just one final question on the Gerstein Fisher merger that is coming in early next month. Should we be -- is that going to have a material impact on the model at all as we think about the influence on fees and expenses as that comes in.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 What we said when we announced that deal in Q&amp;A is from a -- their annual run rate of revenue is about $17 million. We also said that it was modestly accretive to 2017.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Collyn Gilbert,  Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. All right. Thank you very much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are welcome.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Casey Haire, Jefferies.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Travis Potts,  Jefferies &amp; Co. - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hey, good afternoon. This is actually Travis Potts on for Casey. I just had one follow question on loan yields. You had a nice spike in C&amp;I. If I assume like most of that $1 million LIBOR impact was in that C&amp;I, then it accounts for about half of that increase. Can you just talk to what else is driving those loan yields higher, so any kind of lumpy fees this quarter or anything?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Rosato,  People's United Financial, Inc. - CFO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is spreads. It is a combination of LIBOR which we called out and then spreads. That entire portfolio is not one month LIBOR based.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We got a little better spread performance during the quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Travis Potts,  Jefferies &amp; Co. - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 All right, thank you guys.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are welcome.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Breese, Piper Jaffray.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Breese,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good evening guys. The Suffolk Bancorp deal. Just curious. What are some of the challenges you are facing getting that deal closed on time and is it normal regulatory delays or does it have anything to do with incrementally putting the balance sheet closer to $50 billion?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't believe it has anything to do with that. It really is the normal process that you probably are aware the process is an extended on a post crisis and I think it is generally getting slightly better as of late but what we see is transactions taking six to nine months, and we are in that timeframe. We are certainly hopeful to be on the shorter end, but we -- as I said, it is nothing in our control. So to get to the nature of your question, I don't think you should view it as it is taking longer than normal.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Breese,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, understood. And then going back to your comment around maintaining the dividend as you cross 50, could we talk about and provide a little more color around that? Is that to imply that you will cross with the dividend or potentially consider other strategic alternatives like a sale of the bank if you can't keep it?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Barnes,  People's United Financial, Inc. - President &amp; CEO   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I wouldn't over complicate that. We have gotten regulatory support to maintain our dividends and our approach to dividends over an extended period of time. Our dividend payout ratio continues to improve if you will to get lower over time. And as we move through -- go forward the next few years we expect to continue to improve our profitability, to improve that ratio, and we also expect that the regulatory view of levels of dividend payout ratio for all banks our size and banks in that 50 will evolve. And it has been evolving.
 So trying to be clear that we believe that we will continue to reduce that payout ratio and we believe that in our dialogue with regulators that we will get support. We obviously can't predict exactly where the payout ratio will be or exactly what the regulatory view will be, but we've got very good communication and relationships with our regulators, and we will approach those dialogues, I should say we have them regularly and we will continue to have them regularly. That issue will get discussed.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Breese,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Understood, thank you for that commentary. That's all I had.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen since there are no further questions in the queue I would now like to turn the call back over to Mr. Hersom for closing remarks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrew Hersom,  People's United Financial, Inc. - SVP of IR   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you again for joining us today. We appreciate your interest in People's United. If you should have any additional questions feel free to contact me at (203)338-4581. Have a great night.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Good day.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q3 2016 People's United Financial Inc Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>BRIDGEPORT</city>
  <companyName>People's United Financial Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>PBCT</companyTicker>
  <startDate>20-Oct-16 9:00pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>96345</companyId>
  <CUSIP>712704105</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>B1W41J2</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US7127041058</ISIN>
</Event>