<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="6028369" lastUpdate="Monday, May 23, 2016 at 11:49:26pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="6028369.F" expirationDate="Monday, May 23, 2016 at 8:00:00am GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of PFG.J earnings conference call or presentation 23-May-16 8:00am GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Half Year 2015\2016 Pioneer Food Group Ltd Earnings Presentation

 May 23, 2016 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Pioneer Food Group Ltd earnings conference call or presentation Monday, May 23, 2016 at 8:00:00am GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Phil Roux
      Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO
   *  Cindy Hess
      Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CFO
   *  Felix Lombard
      Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - Executive Groceries

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Anthony Geard
      Investec - Analyst
   *  Paul Steegers
      Bank of America Merrill Lynch - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and a warm welcome to our results presentation. We've changed the format somewhat for the half year in that we have a webcast, so good morning to all of those that are watching and listening in on our presentation. Cindy and I will do the presentations this morning, so that we can leave ample time for questions, given that it was quite an interesting first half and I'm sure you'll have a number of questions to put to us. Having said that, we have highly capable executives Martin, Tertius, Felix and Thushen here that can assist me in providing those answers to you.
 The first half has certainly been a bumpy, right. I guess that's the best way to explain it. Having said that, we came off a 37% growth in HEPS in the previous first half in the prior year. And the reason for this is that there were any number of environmental discontinuities that the business had to face up to. These were widely publicized. I won't go into too much detail. I'm sure you are [aware] with most of them. What's more important is the effect that it had on our business. Some of the discontinuities we've highlighted for you. Firstly, political instability. The drought, relatively low growth, in some instances, ex-growth environment, consumer weakness is evident in real and a tremendous amount of instability on the African continent. This, of course, gives rise to an effect. The first one being rand weakness. Circa 60% to 70% of Pioneer's cost base has a hard currency link to it. So you can imagine the effect that that has on our margins and how we have to react immediately on the pricing front.
 The drought was not only limited to maize as widely publicized, some of the food crops as well that serve our beverage business have also been affected by the drought conditions. Low growth, of course, gives rise to increased rivalry as we all chase market share in this type of environment and without the cost base and efficiency mindset to support that, you can expect your margins to compress. Consumer weakness interestingly enough has given rise to a number of evolving shopper habits, one of them being that shopping patterns have really been compressed to a few days in the month. And you'll see how retailers have shifted their inventory holdings and the way they restock and their inventory modeling per se and how their advertising schedules too have adapted to the way the consumer is shopping. In respect of the African stability I referred to, here it's a story of currency devaluation, the metical has devalued by over 30%, the kwacha in Zambia, I think by 100%. This, of course, puts pressure on consumer pricing, 70% of our beverage is accrued to the African continent and those are rand denominated. So we don't get the hard currency hedge advantage out of that, conversely, we have to be quite defensive in our pricing and how we go to market.
 Notwithstanding those discontinuities, we've managed to plate up, I guess, what is best referred to as a palatable sets of numbers, our revenue for continuing operations up 9%. Deleverage in our operating profit is largely as a consequence of the maize impact within our Essential Foods division, which I'll expand on later. We were more than pleased to be able to hold our all-time high operating margin of 12.3% for the period and from a dividend perspective, our Board approved an 11% increase to ZAR1.05.
 I thought I'd roll back the clock a little, some modest boasting. If one looks at the operating margins in half-one 2013, we've more than doubled the profitability over three years, giving rise to a CAGR of 29%. The income statement has been productively worked in that the gross margin expanded from 29% to 31% over this period and the margin at an EBIT level from 7% to 12.3%.
 Headline earnings per share more than doubled and our share price, of course, has more than doubled with a three-year CAGR of 25%. You should be familiar by now with our corporate strategy and the five pillars that underpin two agendas being driving above market growth and then enhancing our competitiveness through a reduction of costs in absolute terms and driving efficiencies out of our value chain enabled by a high performance team. I'm going to speak to you, give you an update on the three of those this morning. Firstly, commencing with shaping a winning portfolio. I'm pleased with the progress that we've made in owning the corporate portfolio Pioneer Foods. Now this, of course, has been overwhelmingly bolstered by the disposal of unproductive or loss making assets or those that no long are deemed to be a strategic fit and this has had a positive effect on the margin. We have, however, also made two strategic investments although small to remind you, the one in Nigeria and also Future Life. Speaking of which, the integration and innovation funnel is looking particularly attractive. You'll see our FUTURELIFE Bread on display, which we launched a month or so ago and we have some wonderful innovation in the offing. In respect of our small Nigerian asset, I'm pleased as well because I'm beginning to see green shoots in respect of a route to market being established and the factory is [Choc N Cheese] from where we bought it and the way we fixed it and put in some new equipment. Bakeries for the first half, which I'll speak to later, sustained its growth and continue to generate operating leverage, notwithstanding the fact that our Cape operation in the Western Cape we have a high market share, we refurbished one half of that plant and we've put in a whole new line into the Western Cape and to that end we couldn't be competitive in the first half. That is now up and running and we will go back and throw our way back in respect of market share.
 We continue, it's now a part of our DNA, to continually purge our portfolio of unproductive or slow moving SKUs and this gives us the efficiencies across the value chain. And I'll come back to rice again in more detail, when I speak to Essential Foods, but there's certainly been a step change in our rice performance. Our so robust acquisition funnel is highlighted in yellow, which would intimate that we're not awash with acquisition opportunities, that would probably speak to South Africa more than the rest of the world. And if there are any questions specific to that, I'm than happy to deal with those.
 On the topic of costs and efficiencies in this environment, trading environment, that we find ourselves in, if you haven't got a lid on costs and if you don't have the fanaticism about increasing efficiencies, you will experience sudden death. We've managed to contain our manpower cost, which is a big number in our income statement, to 60% of our revenue growth rate. We've delivered to enhance manufacturing efficiencies, in fact in our groceries business, in big parts thereof, we've held our costs in nominal terms. We promised you that we would eliminate ZAR50 million in fixed costs as we disposed of Pepsi and biscuits. We are firmly on track and we have a monthly tracker that provides evidence against that. The balance of our cost cash operating expenses increased less than 10% of our revenue growth rate and we can give you some more granular detail on that too, should you like.
 Unfortunately, of course, out of our hands is that our cost of sale increase was greater than our revenue growth rate and this speaks to the raw material inflation as opposed to any lack of efficiency drive in the manufacturing area, which we term conversion costs. How did that all stack-up in respect of our Power brand market share performance, it's patchy on the SASKO side that is on bread, we lost two points. Now I want to remind you that this is only the modern trade and on Essential Foods or within Essential Foods, only 30% of our business accrues to this reed.
 So whilst it's in red in bread for SASKO in the modern trade, and that's largely due to the Western Cape and some increased competition in the Natal area given that we took heaps of market share in the prior period as we filled the Shakaskraal capacity. We are not concerned about this at all, we had real volume growth and we will increase our share position again in the modern trade in the second half.
 Importantly, Weet-Bix, Safari and Spekko, some really, really good market share movements on the up, particularly Spekko as we begin to make quite meaningful inroads against testing in the core markets in Natal, and in Gauteng.
 Liqui-Fruit's market share came off somewhat but I'd urge you to look to the right hand column at the category growth and value in the modern trade was 19% given the sizzling summer that we had. And there is also new competition, Rhodes have launched into the long-life category and so to Coca-Cola have converted their Just Juice brand, which was a sparkling brand into long life juice as well. We have a very aggressive defense plan and notwithstanding this marginal fall of end market share, we had over a 7% volume growth in our long life juice internal volumes.
 At this juncture, I'd like to hand over to Cindy, who will cover off the financials. I'll be back to give you a divisional overview and also give you a feel for the outlook and what Pioneer will be doing within this environment. So thanks for now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Cindy Hess,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CFO   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, everyone. Phil Roux already sketched the very difficult environment within which we find ourselves in FMCG over the last six months. But for Pioneer, the added challenge of growing on a very strong first-half of 2015 presented a challenge to the team. We are rather pleased with our revenue growth and I'll show you that at a segmental level in the next slide. We've managed to contain our cost on every line in the income statement. And with the exceptional performance from groceries and international, we've managed to maintain our 12.3% margin, which is all-time high in the last year. Overall, we managed to grow our cash generated by operations by 39%.
 Just to highlight upfront that I'll show you revenue growth on a like-for-like basis. If you looked at the actual reported income statement, you'll see a 6% growth at the half-year. However, after backing out Pepsi, biscuits and Maitland Vinegar, which was sold on October 1, we reflect a 9% increase in revenue to ZAR10 billion at the half-year.
 Essential Foods roughly constrained by the impact within maize and wheat grew 8% to just over ZAR6 billion. Groceries on a like-for-like basis, again, up 7% to ZAR2.5 billion and international just under ZAR1.5 billion for the six months, 20% growth year-on-year. Essential Foods still contributing 60% of total revenue with the groceries business now at 25% and international at 15%.
 So we've managed to grow Group operating profit by 6% on the adjusted basis. I will talk to what that means. Most of you are familiar with adjusted basis, where we actually show real growth for the Group and that's at ZAR1.236 billion for the six months with the operating margin as earlier indicated at 12.3% on par with last year.
 Essential foods down 8% largely or solely as a result of maize and wheat. Groceries up 35% to ZAR343 million with a margin expansion from 9.6% to 13.7% for the six months. International grew its profit 16% to ZAR252 million and roughly maintained its margin in and around 18% at 17.4% for this six months.
 So with the increase in revenue of 9% as I said on the like-for-like basis, cost of goods sold increased 8% and unfortunately the impact of maize hides the real benefit from manufacturing efficiencies throughout the Group, and in fact, as I've indicated throughout the income statement, our cost containment and efficiency and procurement initiatives have really come home to drive an overall operating profit growth of ZAR1.2 billion and operating margin at ZAR12.3 billion, despite the containment or decline in the gross margin.
 In terms of rest of the income statement, I'm just going to call out one or two lines. The finance costs, which is 11% up year-on-year mainly a factor of the increase in the interest rate but also the fact that we've utilized our fleet facility in full, that's a ZAR300 million facility within this six months compared to last year. Very strong contribution from our JVs, equity accounted earnings now includes FUTURELIFE and our Nigerian joint venture, strong performance really posted from Bokomo Namibia and Botswana as well as Bowman's.
 Overall, income tax growth up ahead of our profit before tax really because of the capital gain on the sale of Maitland Vinegar. Just to reconcile our profits on an adjusted basis to the actual reported income, the Phase I BEE transaction really is a cash-settled scheme for those of you who don't know and because of the movements in our share price has a volatile impact on our actual results. So on the adjusted basis, we basically exclude this to highlight the real performance of the business.
 But after factoring that in, you'll see that the Phase I BEE transactions swung from a charge of ZAR203 million in the prior six-month period to a gain of ZAR143 million, that's as a result of our share price decreasing from the ZAR196 million at the year-end, September 30, to ZAR136 million at March 31. Items of a capital nature includes the impairment of the Quantum Foods shares that we lived with post the unbundling which were received by our SPV Phase II BEE partners, which are consolidated and there you can see the profit on disposal of our Maitland Vinegar subsidiary, ZAR24 million. So overall, including all those entries, IFRS required entries, we grew net operating profit by 52% to ZAR1.391 billion.
 So this slide, I'll probably lose you halfway through it, I lose my colleagues often when we update them. But if I do, just remember it as [leaon] on slide. So adjusted headline earnings, which is the real number and the true performance of the business, is up 7% on an absolute basis to ZAR887 million or on a per share basis to 6% at the half-year to [479 cents]. But we have to fact in from a reported point of view, the Phase I BEE income and that swing resulted in headline earnings on an absolute basis, increasing 64% and on a per share basis to [ZAR556 cents] per share, which is a 63% increase.
 The prior year, obviously, impacted by the loss on discontinuance mainly the unbundling increase of Quantum Foods that resulted in a 90% increase in earnings or EPS 89% and adjusted EPS 14%. That's off the exclusion in the Phase I BEE transaction. So just to remind you the real performance of the business, 7% up on an absolute basis to ZAR887 million from an adjusted headline earnings point of view.
 So how we managed in this difficult environment around cash. Obviously, the dynamics at full sketched within the grains business around wheat and also wheat and maize as well as a seasonal high for our food crop has put pressure on our inventory balances that investment [are of]an inventory offset by general working capital initiatives and we see a 7% decrease in the amount of investment into working capital at the half-year resulting in cash generated by operations going 39% despite that.
 As you know, March 31 at the half-year is a seasonal high and in and around 17.7%, 17.1% of total revenue, which is ahead of our peers. Have we invested that cash, our investment in property, plant and equipment at ZAR349 million in total is ZAR53 million higher than the prior half-year, mainly as a result of growth CapEx. You're aware that we've invested in our Duens Bakery, Aeroton's expansion, our Weet-Bix upgrade and several other growth CapEx that took place and is planned for the rest of the year. We are now well on our way to spending and investing ZAR930 million in CapEx for the full year.
 In terms of the other noteworthy item on the slide, our investment in joint ventures relates to the Future Life investment on December 1 of ZAR201 million and the disposal proceeds is in respect of our sale of Maitland Vinegar.
 Overall net cash at the half-year at ZAR840 million relative to our [true debt] of ZAR1.3 billion. And when I say [true debt], I exclude the [debt] relating to the Phase II transaction, which we forced to consolidate that essentially results in a net debt position of ZAR470 million and a 6% net debt to equity ratio. Important to highlight at this point is the significant gearing capacity that we have on our balance sheet. In terms of the interim dividend that was approved by our Board, [105 cents] at the half-year, representing an 11% increase on last year's interim dividend. This is very much in line with the prudent position at the half-year that we normally take, but definitely aiming for our dividend cover ratio of 2 times headline earnings.
 That's all from me. I'll now hand back to Phil to take you through the segmental results.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much, Cindy. I will now give you some more texture to the divisional performance commencing with Essential Foods, just to remind you maize, wheat, rice, legumes, bread, all forms part of [Tertius's] responsibilities. In the first instance, just to confirm, and this is being validated, sanitized by various parties, South Africa has got a white maize shortage and it's estimated at 1.2 million tons. If the legislation doesn't change and imports don't begin to flow into the country, the country will run out of maize, that's the bottom line.
 As a consequence, the raw material price on white maize specifically has increased by 90%. If one looks at the entire industry, the total [milled] tonnage of maize, it's contracted by close to 6%. One has to be aware that the maize import regulations without getting into the detail in this presentation, is particularly limiting. Zambia has closed its borders, so you cannot import from Zambia even if they had maize, they too have faced a drought, that leaves two other destinations, the USA and Mexico and Mexico is a net importer of maize.
 Turning into the wheat category, this too has contracted and it shouldn't be surprising. The wheat duty, which now represents 25% of the raw material cost, has increased by over a ZAR1,000 a ton and the new level has recently triggered to in the order of ZAR1,600 per ton, which would probably take it closer to 27%, I haven't done the number, but I can imagine 27% of the raw material cost. We have applied in discussions for relief on this duty structure, I personally met with Pravin Gordhan and we have subsequently received a letter that ITAC is investigating the whole duty structure around maize, wheat and sugar. But these things take a long time to get resolved as it goes through the various structures in government.
 There is indication of some carbohydrate substitution taking place, we are seeing some low volume growth in the bread category, some volume growth in the rice category, as the maize category contracts. Having said that, one must recognize in South Africa that maize is a center of plate item, not side of plate. It represents true food security, so you buy your 10 kilograms or your 12 kilograms and you put it in the corner of the kitchen and you know the family won't go hungry, so I suspect that consumers will come back to this category in the second half of our financial year. I think these are solid set of numbers under the circumstances. If you had to back out maize from the divisional performance, the volume and the profit will be in fact flat. Just to give you an idea of an impact of the maize price increases that we've had to contend with. Be there as it may, the numbers are the numbers, volumes are down 5%, revenue up 8% as the inflation begins to push through, operating profit down 8% and you see the compression of margin from the 12.4% to 10.6%. Now let me also emphasize that this operating margin for this agglomeration of grain type products is higher than anything you'll encounter probably in parts of the world.
 So we've, on a positive note, maintained our category leadership on maize; our bakeries, we've sustained volume growth and leverage. And a real success story, our rice business used to be loss making. It is profitable now with a low single-digit margin and our volumes increased 14% as we begin to build the brand and the equity around the Spekko brand in our competitors' historical areas of strength. The maize and wheat volume declines, of course, have had the greatest negative bearing on the portfolio performance, and our pasta and legumes have delivered a satisfactory performance.
 Turning into groceries in respect of the environmental backdrop also affected quite significantly by major raw material inflation. You can imagine wheat and maize also feeds into our breakfast business, concentrate pricing has gone through the roof, so too some of our flavors and also packaging, which is hard currency or euro based. We've seen new competitors come into our categories, Premier have a launched a new product called Thrive in an attempt to compete with Future Life. Jungle continues to assert itself and as previously mentioned on the beverage side, new entrants on long life juice. The category was bolstered, beverages that is by a sizzling summer, you would have seen some of the ABI numbers as well, we had strong double-digit over the summer period. That said, I think our performance and the extent to which we've generated leverage, which I'll show you in a minute, speaks volumes.
 At a consumer level within these grocery categories, value per se and when we talk about value for money and the way it's represented at a shopper level, we're talking about two for ones, 30% frees, we're in a value economy and consumers are responding to these and also pantry loading at a far greater extent that they used during deep-cut promotions that retailers run.
 A more granular look then at groceries, which we've given the strapline of margin excellence, which it is. Volume growth of 5% translating into 7% revenue growth, the price increases on the groceries portfolio kick-in in the second half. Five times operating leverage with a 35% lift in EBIT and the margin opening up 400 basis points from 9.6% to 13.7%. This, of course, has all come about in two ways and I can assure you it's not solely because we dispensed off loss making businesses, the organic growth in the business and the expansion of the margin off that organic base was impressive.
 It's always a consequence of prudent cost management, the conversion efficiencies I spoke of, fixed overhead elimination plan to the [cent] and we have made significant saving on logistics. And this logistics team will continue into our new financial year in a different structural way as we evolve [Tania] Food Logistic Service as a one-time initiative.
 Pleasingly also our small category showed some improvement, if you'll recall that the brands like Marmite, Moir's, Bovril had a little bit of pressure in the previous period, we seem to have done better into our first half. I thought I would split out groceries that you can see the extent to which the improvement has come through, both streams being cereals and other groceries and also beverages. So on the first one cereals and other groceries, revenue up 6%, 26% lift in profit and the margin expanding from 10% to 13.4%.
 On the beverage side, a 9% lift in revenue translating into a 44% lift in operating profit and a really pleasing increase in the margin them from 9% to 14% for beverages. This starts to resemble this grocery business a world-class groceries operating margin, get this thing to 15%, you really now you are in good company.
 Turning into international, 8% volume growth largely aided and abetted by our Fruit business, which had a good crop and we traded exceptionally well. Revenue up 20% and the deleverage in the operating profit, although it grew at 16% is largely attributed to the stoppage of our operation as we move the plant in Peterborough to our new facility, which is now up and running. And also the pressure that we're experiencing on our beverage export business, as those consumers on the rest of the continent come under pressure.
 There's a liquidity crisis on the African continent and dollars are hard to come by. That said, almost holding onto the 18% operating margin at 17.4% required a tremendous amount of trading [nerves]. So our internal beverage performance we've regarded as a solid performance, our basket selling by which we mean carrying in the balance of our groceries and Essential Foods products also begins to gain momentum.
 Nigeria settling down, not the country per se, but certainly our small asset in Nigeria and as mentioned an excellent Fruit growth and profit performance and the UK factory relocation and upgrade has gone particularly well. So what can we expect in the second half in this very interesting country and trading environment that we're operating in and what does that mean for Pioneer?
 We tried to put that into a diagrammatic view for you, inflationary pressure is here to stay, you would hear some of the retailers posturing that price increases won't be expected and that prices will be coming down, well, I can't see that happening at all. Not without volatile exchange rate and not to the extent of strength that FMCG manufacturers have. There's no way to go, we simply have to price up when these costs come at us, but, of course, what we do is apply pricing restraint, given the massive effort that we put into containing our costs and driving efficiencies.
 The uncertainty on the legislation, in particular, whether we can import maize or not will be with us until government makes a decision and there's no more to say about that. But I am delighted that they have recognized the need to review the duty structure, particularly wheat which affects us and our consumers so significantly. So consumers and households will remain under pressure. They're going to be very selective. I suspect that bodes well for an organization like ours that has a very balanced portfolio. We are in Essential Foods. We do augment that with other higher margin products. So as trading down might or might not happen, Pioneer will be and in a well position to cater to consumer needs. I think you can expect war as opposed to intense competition as we battle it out with our lead competitors namely Tiger and Premier Foods. But we are certainly up for the challenge and quite excited about that.
 Protracted currency weakness is a real concern, when you have 60% to 70% of your cost base with a hard currency link in some shape manual form, the last thing we can do with is further instability on the political front in South Africa that which we witnessed last week again with the currency drifting out to [AUD15.74]. So we certainly hope that as a country, no rash decisions will be made because the consumers will feel the brunt of it in every shape manner and form. What does this all mean for Pioneer Foods? Strategic clarity and coherence is absolutely imperative in an organization like ours. That said, you can have the most wonderful brands if you don't have people excellence, you'll come adrift and I can confidently say that we have one of the most superb management teams in the country. Our portfolio optimization continues but this takes on a different slot. We need to close out a large acquisition. We have significant headroom, relatively ungeared balance sheet and that's where we need to take Pioneer.
 Maize will have to be augmented by imports. And by this, I'm referring to our new financial year. We are adequately covered for this financial year. And government needs to act on this. We've coined the phrase, I think I got it from the investment community, in fact, one of self-help. And it's encouraging that after three years that we still have residual self-help potential at Pioneer. We haven't fully optimized our value chain, neither in terms of conversion efficiencies on the logistics side, Group procurement all through our shared service offerings that we've now consolidated. People often ask me, so how far are you down the road? I don't think the job is ever done to be quite frank, but we've got some big benefits that will flow through our income statement next year again on logistics and we will beaver away and improving our overall efficiencies throughout the business. And I will ensure that we keep a lid on costs and there will be no waste in our organization.
 Our capital projects, the three big ones, namely the Cape Town Bakery, that has been completed. I went to visit it, it looks like a small Shakaskraal, same look and feel, some thrill that we could upgrade our technology and going to put a -- product out there that's even better than the consumers are accustomed to. The Aeroton project is also well underway and so that we can assert ourselves again in our competitor's biggest markets in Gauteng. And then thirdly, our Weet-Bix project is also underway, given that we are practically out of capacity, were it not for the efficiencies that we were generating and increase throughputs, we wouldn't have had more product to sell, which fortunately we have done over the past six months.
 And then again the ungeared balance sheet, which I referred to speaks to our appetite to grow acquisitively. Organic growth out of South Africa's simply won't suffice. We are not getting caught up in fanaticism, or the frenzy for hard currency earnings because South African business people are quite fetish, two or three years ago, it was all about the African continent and now everyone seems a little bearish about that. Notwithstanding the fact that by 2020, will add close to ZAR600 million in populace to the African continent.
 So we certainly haven't turned off the lights on the African continent. We remind vigilant, but our first priority is to increase exports of our South African asset base on to the African continent, and if we find worthwhile assets that are priced appropriately, we'll do those deals, but the world's a much bigger place and we're quite excited about some of the opportunities and geographies that we visited of late and I guess, at this stage it would best be left there for obvious competitive reasons.
 I'd like to thank you very much for being attentive. We've tried to keep this particularly efficient at the half-year with only two speakers and the reason we do that is so that we can open the floor for more questions, because this is a very complicated and complex environment that we are trading-in and I'm sure you'll have any number of questions that you'd like to put to us.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Phil. Good morning, because we're broadcasting this, if you would just indicate if you have a question and I'll hand you a mic, who has the mike can hold the floor. We'll first of all take questions from you good folk and then because some people are listening in, we'll give those on the teleconference an opportunity to ask verbal questions. And finally, if there are any written questions that have come through the teleprompter we'll put them to Phil at that point. First of all here we go.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Anthony Geard,  Investec - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's Anthony Geard from Investec. Phil, can you try to gives us a little bit more color just to remind us (technical difficulty).

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much. That's Anthony from Investec. Two questions, what do we expect out of our new Peterborough facility in the UK and what the Aeroton opportunity portends? I'll start with the Aeroton one because that's a big capital investment. Anthony, it's public knowledge that Tiger Brands has a big market share position in Gauteng. So not dissimilar to what we did in Natal. This is a play for market share. And whilst we are present in a large volume context in Gauteng today, every time we upgrade our capabilities, the technology, the quality that's concomitant with that, we also install additional capacity. So we'll be going after extra market share, and, of course, enhancing the consumer offering as the final kind of test.
 In respect of the UK, we had to move the factory, that was a legislative requirement and we used that opportunity to upgrade the facility. Some of our retailing partners in the UK, Tescos and the like have been through the facility and they have actually said this was one of the best granola facilities that they've seen. Do we like the fact that it is largely a private label business in the UK, no, do we make good money out of it? Yes. But should we be able to get our hands on any smaller branded assets in the UK that bolt on to this facility, that's certainly going to be our intention.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you Phil. Anybody else?

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There is one on the left, Martin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Paul Steegers,  Bank of America Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. It's Paul Steegers from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Just a question on your gearing, you mostly got a strong balance sheet and you said you're looking for deals. To what level would you be comfortable your balance sheet or do you think any potential deals with the equity fund?

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for the question, Paul. When people ask that question, I normally play back two numbers, if they kind of corroborates each other, I'll be very pleased. So I would be very nervous to take us much below an eight times EBIT interest cover or said differently, at top 40% debt to equity ratio. Any more questions from our Cape Town audience? We needn't have rushed, only one more, good.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Audience Member   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, Phil. [Vlada Maxwell, VCM] You mentioned 15% as a kind of number at which you consider to be world class on the grocery side of the business. Do you have a similar number in mind on the Essential Foods side of the business?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you very much for the question. It all comes down to your portfolio mix really within the Essential Foods portfolio and you'll notice that I continuously referred to bakeries. We had a very modest margin three years ago, and we don't disclose our operating margin on any of the segmentals within Essential Foods. But I can assure you it's twice what it used to be given our improvements, more than double actually. So it's very important if we are to expand our margin in aggregate that Bakeries kick-in to a faster and a larger degree.
 That said, when we come out of this very, very precarious [amazing] environment that we find ourselves in, there should theoretically be some upside for us again on the margin. Now to aggregate that for you is difficult, because it is a soft commodity environment, there's heaps of competition and I think it wouldn't be prudent or wise for me to try and commit to an absolute number today. I've said repeatedly though that our target for 2018 is to corporately to try and get to 13%, 13.5% operating margin.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Any more questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for those.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, so let's just check if there's anybody on the telecall. (Operator Instructions) Any further questions? Okay, so let's just check if there's anybody on the telecall who would like to ask a question directly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So, may you'll give us the second question and Cindy will do some maths and revert you on that number.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just have a few actually. Firstly, I think the first question is for Cindy, she's given us a restated revenue line, excluding Pepsi and Moir's. (technical difficulty) excluding Pepsi and Moir's?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So will you give us the second question and Cindy will do some maths and revert to you on that number.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just on the Essential Foods division, Phil, would you say you have positive volumes on (inaudible).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the market share figure I referred to, [Simeon],was the modern trade and a smaller portion as you know accrues to the modern trade, so the total category was down 6%, total [milled] tonnage, our volumes contracted 14%.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And therefore you would say, you have the operating margin (technical difficulty) as well.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's for sure, [Simeon].
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and on rate, what was your volumes related to the (inaudible).
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Depends how you define the category.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I saw a report recently, nobody aggregates the local and traditional and the modern trade accurately. And approximately 65% to 70% of bread volumes go to the local and traditional market. So our volume growth was 2% overall.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And so would say your margin on bread increased in the first half?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We kept a steady state on our margin in the first half on bread.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. So actually a good performance. And into the second half, of course, there will be more inflation -
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. So the question is, into the second half, there would be more inflation coming through. How do you think the volumes will play out, (inaudible) what the consumer could absorb into the second half, of course, the first half had (inaudible) into it but the second half has winter as well. So just any comment, Phil, on that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Aside from the normal volume, industry related contractions on beverages you enter into winter, so obviously that's at a slower rate, not in relative terms necessarily or comparable terms. I think the consumer is going to be under a fair amount of pressure. I truly believe categories in volume terms will either be flat or begin to contract. So if you're going to have volume growth it's going to have to be at the expense of someone else. Just for a second, if I can use maize, which is rather extreme as a proxy which then of course doesn't make it an appropriate proxy but we saw softened prices significantly in an effort to [clawback] volume in the October, November, December period on maize. And the market simply didn't respond. So not only did you lose volume, your end margin also went to pot. So we had to go back to managing rand per ton margin on maize from January. I think anybody that foolishly chases volume, it's absolute vanity in this type of market. Of course, we have volume sensitive plants and we'll be mindful of that. But I think you should rather focus on your costs than chasing nebulous volume.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And just one of the question, you said (technical difficulty) in FY15.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 There is absolutely no reason to believe and we consult with Professor [William Manthley] from the University of the Free State and we consult with various other parties. There is no reason to believe that there's going to be a wonderful crop this year. So what we're referring to is next year. So there will be low [Carrion] that's for sure. And the country is left with no other option but to import. We have commenced that process, but for competitive reasons, I'm not going to commit to the extent that we have managed to augment our supply requirements in the new fiscal on maize, because I truly believe we may have comparative advantage.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Technical difficulty)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Cindy Hess,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CFO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Multiple speakers) ZAR25 million including last year's best.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So there is ZAR25 million in last year's base. So what we say is the organic growth in the margin was 300 basis points, said differently in the groceries business.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Technical difficulty)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, it's 300 basis points benefit derived from organic growth in this first half and there was a ZAR100 million loss for the full year last year that accrued to Pepsi and biscuits.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Technical difficulty)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well. I think the normal behavior of supply and demand will play out in pricing. So I can't see maize prices coming off, I mean it hit ZAR5,000 a ton again last week. So unless there's absolute confirmation that everybody will be able to fill the silos with sufficient maize. I think you can anticipate maize pricing remaining high. We're talking about the second half.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Technical difficulty)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, firstly, some of the small guys, we shouldn't be misled on that small anymore. Some of them have consolidated with other companies and entities. But yes, in totality we have the ability to fund the working capital, which is extremely intense and I don't know whether they will be able to weather that kind of pressure. You say retailers have to accept inflation, who leads the pricing [car] between producers and retailers, with retailers being able to import.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martin, damned if you do, damned if you don't in answering that question that long. For some time, I wanted to do a doctorate on who owns the equity of your brand, the custom over the consumer. South African retailers are very powerful in South Africa, that's said, we don't build brands for no reason, we are the second largest-listed FMCG Company in South Africa. I think there is a fair understanding by retailing partners that we're not here to explode consumers or make super-profits. We have [plus] restrained, we have a possible predicated on an efficiency modeling in our organization. So we all act responsibly at all times and I don't think we should get into a tussle as to who's more powerful an FMCG retailer. We've all got a charter, very choppy waters over the next six months and I hope we can all do that responsibly.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Two more questions. Is your gross free margin sustainable?

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Felix, is our gross free margin sustainable. I think so, which I'll take it definitely is.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then finally hedging policy on maize.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That's a very broad-based questions to which I wouldn't want to give a broad based response. I mean we do hedge, we take appropriate cover where necessary and we do that as a strategic activity as opposed to a tactical one. So I prefer to give my response as is.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Phil, that's the two questions.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for facilitating that Martin, thanks.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So can I just ask about - can you give us some territory on those comments about exactly what was in the base for groceries last year Cindy for - so you mentioned ZAR100 million of losses in the base for last year -

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Annualized.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Annualized. And the 25 was in respect to the first half.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martin, give that mic to Felix

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Unidentified Participant   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Can I just carry on with the second question, just perhaps on the Fruit Juice business, obviously, you've indicated the category grew very strongly. Some other players perhaps have taken some market share. Could you remind us what's your split between brand and private label and did one part of the business - one part of the category grown faster than that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'd say the split, Felix, you can correct me, private label versus our branded most probably, [95%, 5%] and then I am being generous to private label, is at?

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Felix Lombard,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - Executive Groceries   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [90:10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 [90:10]. And I only Liqui-Fruit as our power brand. You should remember that we also have fruitree, which is positioned with a three tier segmentation strategy, we have Ceres, which is Premium, we have mainstream Liqui-Fruit and we have fruitree, which completes at the bottom. So when you roll all those market shares together, I can assure you we haven't done too badly on an NFI level. If you can get an accurate read in respect of wholesale and independent trade. Felix, he wants to give you some comfortable numbers? Put it on Felix.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Felix Lombard,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - Executive Groceries   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Is there anybody who would like to ask another question before we warp up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Roux,  Pioneer Food Group Ltd. - CEO   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We look forward to having a cup of tea or coffee with you outside. Can I thank you very much for the attendance this morning. Lots of complicated members, typical trading environment, Pioneer Foods, we are certainly up for the challenge. It's going to be a very, very interesting place to do businesses in South Africa, that's for sure. Thanks so much and have a good day
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Half Year 2015\2016 Pioneer Food Group Ltd Earnings Presentation]]></eventTitle>
  <city>
  </city>
  <companyName>Pioneer Food Group Ltd</companyName>
  <companyTicker>PFG.J</companyTicker>
  <startDate>23-May-16 8:00am GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>221494</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>B2QZG93</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>ZAE000118279</ISIN>
</Event>