<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="12495190" lastUpdate="Thursday, May 2, 2019 at 12:55:21am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="12495190.F" expirationDate="Monday, April 29, 2019 at 7:30:00am GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of SO.MI earnings conference call or presentation 29-Apr-19 7:30am GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q1 2019 Sogefi SpA Earnings Call

MANTOVA May 2, 2019 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of Sogefi SpA earnings conference call or presentation Monday, April 29, 2019 at 7:30:00am GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Laurent Hebenstreit
      Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director
   *  Yann Albrand
      Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Alexandre Raverdy
      Kepler Cheuvreux, Research Division - Equity Research Analyst
   *  Martino De Ambroggi
      Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst
   *  Monica Bosio
      Banca IMI SpA, Research Division - Research Analyst
   *  Renato Gargiulo
      Fidentiis Equities S.V.S.A., Research Division - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Good morning. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome, and thank you for joining the Sogefi First Quarter 2019 Results Conference Call. (Operator Instructions) At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Laurent Hebenstreit, CEO of Sogefi. Please go ahead, sir.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you very much. Laurent Hebenstreit, Chief Executive Officer of Sogefi. Welcome to this conference call concerning the first quarter 2019 results. I'm here with Yann Albrand, Sogefi Chief Financial Officer; and Stefano Canu, Sogefi Investor Relations.
 I guess you all have the documents. We'll start on Page 2 of the document with the highlights for the first quarter 2019. The first point of the highlight is that Sogefi revenues ended up at EUR 389.9 million, let's say EUR 390 million, at constant exchange that means we are down 2.9% versus the market, which was down in terms of production of cars worldwide by 6.7%. So we did better than the guidance we initially gave as we outperformed the market.
 The EBITDA came out at EUR 41.3 million at 10.6% on sales versus 12% in 2018. EBIT at EUR 11.3 million at 2.9% on sales versus 5.6%. Net results at EUR 1.6 million versus EUR 11.2 million in 2018.
 Free cash flow at minus EUR 9.1 million versus positive EUR 9.3 in 2018. And the 2019 numbers include EUR 7.5 million impact of IFRS 16 and EUR 1.6 million of operating cash consumption, of which EUR 3.1 million due to the startup of the new production plant in Morocco.
 Finally, in terms of debt. We ended at EUR 328.9 million. The application of the IFRS determined -- IFRS 16 determined the recognition of EUR 66.8 million of financial debt for right of use. Excluding this amount, net debt would have ended up at EUR 262.1 million versus EUR 260.5 million at the end of 2018.
 At the end of the presentation, Yann Albrand will be happy to answer all your question on the various tariffs.
 Continuing now on Page 3 with revenues by geographical area. We see that Europe, which is the main reference market for Sogefi, with 62%, 63% of our sales, was down 5%. And we reported a 3.5% change or 3.6% constant exchange range, so better than the market.
 In North America, we were substantially at constant exchange rate in line with the market. South America, we ended up (inaudible) 16% lower. So here, South America is 9.6% of our sales with the heavy impact of the exchange rate, especially in Argentina. And finally, in Asia, the reference market was a minus 11.8% and we reported minus 8.6%, of which we had a very severe drop in China as we reported minus 22.5% of sales in China. China sales at EUR 17.2 million are, of course, important, but are of limited impact versus total sales of EUR 389.9 million in the quarter.
 Turning now on Page 4 to the revenues by business units. We see that at constant exchange rate, Suspensions had the higher decline at 3.9% due to the end of life of some program and reported change at minus 6.9%, so Suspensions also were more impacted in terms of exchange rate, and we see that had a significant effect on the results.
 Filtration had a limited impact of the exchange rate despite the exposure to South America. And finally, on Air &amp; Cooling, we had a counter effect because due to Canadian dollar, U.S. dollar parity versus the euro. At constant exchange rate, we were down minus 2.1% but we reported a flat sales.
 Coming to the client perspective. During the first quarter of 2019 where we had underperformance was at Ford and Fiat Chrysler mainly. Ford and Fiat Chrysler, as you know, had a difficult first quarter. And in the case of Sogefi, due to the fact that we sell Ford in China, the impact was even bigger as far as the decline of our sales whereas on reverse, Renault/Nissan and Tesla were quite strong during the first quarter. These were the points I wanted to underline. BMW still positively oriented in terms of growth.
 Moving now to Page 6 as far as what is ahead of us, which is more interesting than the past, is the future. The forecast of IHS is a reduction in terms of total production of 3.4%, so it remained a difficult environment, of course. But as we expected in our guidance, the drop in China, instead of being 13.5% in the first quarter, is forecasted at minus 3.4%. South America could be positive and what is more negative in the second quarter is the minus 7.7% in Europe.
 Having said that, I would like hand over to Yann Albrand, Sogefi Chief Financial Officer, to commence on the financial results.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Laurent. So we are moving to Slide 7 on EBITDA. As Laurent said, EBITDA margin went down from 12% in Q1 of last year to 10.6% in Q1 2019. Without any surprise, this reflects the drop in sales, which has a direct impact on EBITDA. It also reflects lower contribution in both Filtration and Suspensions, and we'll come back to that.
 Also, (inaudible) which is explaining the deterioration of EBITDA, is that in Q1, we had EUR 1.9 million of restructuring costs versus EUR 1.1 million the year before.
 If we move to the following page, so EBITDA margin by business units. In Suspensions, it goes down from 9.9% to 7.9%. So this reflects a drop in sales, of course, and also reduction in profitability in South America, it's mainly Argentina which is suffering and China where we have a tough market.
 Filtration declined from 12.2% of EBITDA to 9.6%. The margin reduction is mainly due to the drop in volumes in Europe. Also, difficult year in Brazil, which is hitting us by roughly EUR 1 million and the cost of our new startup in Morocco, which is still in ramp-up mode.
 In Air &amp; Cooling, EBITDA went up from 14.5% to 15.4%. As you saw, sales remain even. And whilst gross margin increased in percentage, the BU is now focusing on products with higher margin and this shows already in the results.
 If we move to Page 9. EBIT, as you can see, goes down from 5.6% to 2.9%. The main impact, of course, is the EBITDA reduction. There's also a secondary impact, which was evidenced in the press release. As Laurent said, on January 1, we moved to IFRS 16 on leasing. This has an impact both on P&amp;L and on an NFP. So in P&amp;L, the EBITDA was increased by EUR 3 million versus the previous year. Whilst the impact in terms of EBIT is roughly 0, it's 0.3%. So EBIT, it's less EBITDA, less impact of the IFRS 16, which is 0 at EBIT level.
 Financial results is improving with cash interest down EUR 1.3 million versus the previous year. And net income going down from 2.8% to 0.4%, still same impact, despite less tax expenses in Q1 2019. The fact remains that we still have heavy tax expense due to the fact that we still had some areas like Brazil where we are losing money, and we do not book deferred tax on areas where there may be uncertainties. So this includes all the ramp-up zones such as Morocco, so we'll wait till we have a solid profitability in such areas before we start booking deferred tax effects.
 Moving on to Page 10, cash flow. As Laurent pointed out, negative cash flow. So cash consumption of EUR 9.1 million in Q1 2019 versus positive EUR 9.3 million last year. A very significant impact is the implementation of IFRS 16. So in this EUR 9.1 million, the net impact -- so both the booking of the new lease commitments plus a minor P&amp;L impact, is a cash consumption of EUR 7.5 million. It's a booking cash entry. That's to say, it mainly reflect the recording of new lease commitments, which we now book as assets and as liabilities. So without this impact, which we wouldn't have had a year ago, the cash consumption of Q1 is only EUR 1.5 million, of which likely more than EUR 3 million from Morocco alone. A significant impact as well in terms of net financial position. So without the new IFRS, the cash position would have increased from EUR 260 million end of last year to EUR 262 million, so the minor impact. On top of this, we added EUR 66.8 million, which is just recording of all the prior lease commitments plus the new ones, which we signed in Q1 of 2019. And that we mentioned our estimation of the impact had we had IFRS 16 end 2019. So end 2018, it would have been already EUR 60 million, so which explains why the net financial position goes from EUR 262 million to EUR 329 million. Laurent?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Thank you very much, Yann, for the detailed explanation of the various elements. I would like now to turn to the outlook on Page 11. Clearly we are not satisfied with the results of the first quarter, although we expected a difficult start for the year, and let's now look at the second quarter.
 The global car market is expected to decline 3.4% in terms of car production compared to the previous year. We highlight the fact that within there, there is still a negative impact in Europe, which is 7.7%. In this environment, in the second quarter, so we see forecast lower sales reduction than the market forecasts. So in clear terms, we continue to outperform the market. And more important than the sales in terms of profitability, EBIT in percentage for the second quarter is expected to improve compared to the first quarter due to the various actions we have ongoing. We are working with the car manufacturers to make sure we pass on, continue passing on the impact of the raw materials. Noted that for the first time in 6 quarters, we have not highlighted the fact that we had negative impact because during the first quarter, we had new full effect in steel versus the first quarter of last year in terms of the net impact in our P&amp;L. We expect in the second quarter and the third quarter and the fourth quarter to continue our -- recuperate some of the negative impact of the increase of steel last year as well as having more positive trends in terms of the materials as some materials in steel are starting to go down, which is would have a positive effect on the profitability of the recent Suspensions activities.
 So in terms of profitability, EBIT for the second quarter is expected to improve compared with the first quarter. This is what we're going to share with you, and we'll be happy to now answer your questions. Thank you for your attention.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  (Operator Instructions) The first question is from Monica Bosio, Banca IMI.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Monica Bosio,  Banca IMI SpA, Research Division - Research Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The first one is on raw materials. Just to clarify, just to check. Have you just told us that in the first quarter, you didn't have any raw materials impact and that you recover in term of pricing, because just my question is if you can elaborate more on the full year indication on the raw material impact. And if you did better or worse than before, I presume better. And then the second question is on the expectation on the second quarter. I had a look at the market provider forecast. Just a flavor from you. Don't you think that the expectation for China in the second quarter might reveal too bullish? And the third question is on restructuring. In the first quarter, you had the higher restructurings year-on-year. Can you just confirm us the guidance or the indication for the full year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Monica. Laurent speaking. So on raw materials, I thank you for pointing to this important point. I confirm that in the first quarter, concerning steel, contrary to the previous 6 quarters where we reported net negative impact between purchasing prices and selling prices, including the recuperation of materials. If you remember that this cost last year EUR 12 million to Sogefi or EUR 3 million by quarter. And in this quarter, between the fact that some grades of steel has nothing to reduce and the fact that we've been doing a better job at negotiating both at the end of the year and beginning of the year, we have for Suspensions, the new full impact in our account.
 So how do we see the full year? If the trend in steel continue, which is having some grades of steel which are going down, and we need to be careful because there are movement which is still very volatile. If this movements continues, then we could have a positive effect between sales and purchasing. But at this point, I would not take it for granted. I would just confirm that in the second quarter, we expect an improvement in the Suspensions. You remember that in our guidance, we said that the recovery of the cost base of Suspension is one of the key elements of this year. We confirm this for the second quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Monica Bosio,  Banca IMI SpA, Research Division - Research Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Laurent, just as a follow-up. So at this point, can we say that the drop in the profitability of the group is mainly due -- is due exclusively to the -- sorry, is due only to the drop in volumes and to the contraction of the reference market?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The 2 main factors for the -- let me say, the main factors for the reference, one, is the volume, which we have emphasized quite a bit. The second, as Yann highlighted, is a reduction in percentage of profitability in Filtration and in Suspensions, which is not connected to raw materials because raw materials, as we said, was neutral in the quarter but is connected mainly to -- for South America -- for Suspensions, sorry, Argentina and China. And for Filtration to Europe where we had the low volume including in aftermarket and in OEM and South America and Asia. These are the main factors.
 Now having said that, we have not done a good job because our fixed costs in the second -- in the first quarter compared with first quarter of last year had increased, so this is also reducing our profitability. For this year, we did not expect the market to be as bad as it came out in the first quarter. It came out lower than what we expected, and we have not been able to flex the fixed cost, which has also had an impact. But looking at the EBIT, there is also depreciation and amortization because, as you know, we've been investing to improve the image of the plants and we have higher depreciation, amortization. Of course, with lower sales that hits the profitability. So these are the main -- the 4 main factors. But this time, it is not the steel, which is the reason why our numbers are going down. So that means with the actions we have ongoing, that's why we are reasonably confident that we will improve in the second quarter and if the economics continue sequentially quarter-over-quarter. But macroeconomics are still very volatile that's why we limited our guidance to the second quarter. Is that more clear, Monica?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Monica Bosio,  Banca IMI SpA, Research Division - Research Analyst   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Yes. And for China, your flavor on China and the restructuring?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So for China, what we've observed is that March was already better than February. And as far as Sogefi is concerned, even if there are few final risks to this guidance in China in terms of volume. We have several new products coming in, product trend in the second quarter and in the third quarter. So overall, when you consider that with the startup production of new products, China will turn to growth for Sogefi, and that might cushion some of the potentially bad surprises in volumes versus the guidance which was given.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  On restructuring, Monica, last year, we booked EUR 8.3 million of restructuring costs. This year, we are shooting for roughly EUR 10 million, the EUR 10 million is in a normal environment, is to say we need to be very prudent regarding market expectations. So if we are facing tough markets all year long, of course, we'll need to incur restructuring costs, reduce our fixed costs.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question is from Renato Gargiulo of Fidentis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Renato Gargiulo,  Fidentiis Equities S.V.S.A., Research Division - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  My first question is on your outlook for the second quarter. (inaudible)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Renato, the sound is very difficult. Maybe you want to try again?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Renato Gargiulo,  Fidentiis Equities S.V.S.A., Research Division - Analyst   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Can you hear me now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  For me, it's very difficult to hear you. Your voice is a bit staggered by the phone call, I mean. Could you try again?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Renato Gargiulo,  Fidentiis Equities S.V.S.A., Research Division - Analyst   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Well, no problem. I will try that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Now it's better. Now it's better.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Renato Gargiulo,  Fidentiis Equities S.V.S.A., Research Division - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Yes? Okay. So my question was on your outlook for the second quarter. You're expecting to outperform the total market in Q2. I was wondering given that clearly, you are -- your highest exposure is to Europe, which is expected to further slowdown now versus the first part of the year. Could you give us any more indication about which markets or which clients are you expecting to outperform versus total market? One, clearly, you were saying it's China we expect to grow. If you can provide anymore indication about your expected trend in the second quarter of the year. Then my second question is on Morocco. If can could give any update about the startup for the new production plant and the expected contribution for this year. And lastly, my last question is on Brazil. If you can give an outlook for Brazilian market going forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you very much, Renato. Concerning the second quarter, as I mentioned, we have new product starting in China. Concerning the sales in Europe for the second quarter, we see a relatively strong demand coming up from the premium. You know that one of the things we did in the last 4 years since we joined with Yann was putting more focus on the growth with premium, so we expect with Daimler and BMW to have a recovery versus the first quarter in terms of volume. And we see also a quite good volumes in Europe with the PSA Group coming up for the second quarter. So this was for the outperformance versus the market.
 Concerning Morocco, the situation is the following: we have started some of our new product and we had a high startup cost in the first quarter for product which we start in the fourth quarter. So what we will see in Morocco is sales, which will be stable during the second and the third quarter versus the first quarter with an improvement we expect in terms of less cash burn. And then in the fourth quarter, we'll have the startup of this new product, which will significantly improve the situation in terms of sales, in terms of adoption of fixed costs and in terms of cash. So situation will remain difficult in Q2 and in Q3, but we expect it to be not as difficult as Q1 because in Q1, we had more than EUR 3 million of cash in the balance sheet, which is too high.
 Coming up in terms of situation in Brazil. There's lots of uncertainty. Part of the volumes in Brazil are linked with the Argentina economy. Argentina economy is quite worrying. You know that we have more than 50% of inflation over 12 months. We have hyperinflation in Argentina. And some of the cars made in Brazil are export -- we are exporting to Argentina. The difficulty is that for the time being, the economics of Argentina is deteriorating, both in terms of purchasing power income but also in terms of financing for buying cars. And therefore, if you look at the month of April, for instance -- the month of March, sorry, the sales of cars in Argentina was at minus 54%. So the Argentina market is very depressed, and of course, this is depressing not only in the Argentina activity but also the Brazilian activity. So we do not expect a significant improvement in Brazil over the next months. Still have a very much competitive situation there in terms of aftermarket.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question is from Martino Ambroggi of Equita.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  I have a follow-up on the operating leverage because if I look at your Q1 results, you lost EUR 16 million in sales and roughly EUR 10 million of gross margin, which is quite a high percentage of sales. You provided us some more details, but could you help us in splitting this effect in terms of roughly volumes, which for sure is the main trigger -- driver price mix ForEx or in another way, what period can be considered nonrecurring, which had an impact on Q1 operating leverage?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you, Martino. Yann, you want to give some more flavor to this?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So if you compare the EBIT on the EBITDA, but we would rather go for EBIT now.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Well, actually, I was looking at gross margin, the contribution margin or EBITDA adjusted for IFRS 16, so it's roughly EUR 10 million at each level, if I'm not wrong.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. So year-on-year, roughly the volume impact is slightly higher than EUR 4 million in terms of contribution linked to volumes. The margin deterioration is roughly EUR 2.5 million. And then we had increases in fixed costs of EUR 2.3 million. And then what happened is that we had a favorable impact on IFRS 16 by EUR 3 million year-on-year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And ForEx?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  ForEx, ForEx is negative. So I have ForEx is negative, but it's not huge year-on-year. ForEx is negative by EUR 1 million of exchange differences.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Is there anything which can be considered nonrecurring and mainly the Morocco plant, the startup or anything else?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  At which level?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Gross margin, EBITDA as you prefer.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  It's not the same because in gross margin, we had the negative hit in Q1, which is linked to the fire in one of our suspension plants, which is overall, offset by insurance recovery at EBITDA level, but which is hitting the gross margin. And this, of course, will be nonrecurring because the plant is going back on track at the end of April.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So that's why, Martino, the contribution margin of Q1 is not fully comparable in yields neither the past nor the future because of these one-off events. That's why we focus the communication here on EBITDA and EBIT where these one-off events negated .
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Okay. The second question is on -- still on the guidance. If we take the minus 7.7% volumes for Europe, knowing you have 60% of sales in Europe, should we expect a performance -- okay, excluding ForEx in Q2 worse in terms of decline of sales compared to Q1 similar? Or similar?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Your question is a difference in sales Q2 to Q2 versus Q1 to Q1, is that the question?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. The question is in Q1, you had the minus 3% at constant ForEx. You are now indicating Europe production should be down 7.7%, in Q1 was down 5%. Knowing you have 60% of sales in Europe, should we expect worse or similar performance in terms of decline in sales compared to the 3% that you had in Q1?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So Martino, we expect a better performance. We expect to beat the market on a worldwide basis, and our projections for Q2 indicate that considering this decline in market most probably on sales will also decline but will -- should less decline than in Q1 versus Q1 of last year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And in terms of the EBITDA, you are referring in absolute value in your guidance. Is it referring to the absolute value? Or as a percentage of sales?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Well, actually, we are shooting for the time being for an improvement, both in absolute and percentage.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. And the underlying assumption of the restructuring costs in this guidance?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  For Q2?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  For Q2, it's roughly EUR 2 million. It was EUR 1.6 million a year ago. So for the time being, as I said before, it's business as usual in terms of restructuring that's part of the automotive business, but if the market keeps on going down, strongly down, we'll kick off some higher restructuring. But for the time being, it's not in the pipe.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Very last questions on that. The impacts of the asset deconsolidated and the updated guidance for the CapEx for the full year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Concerning the asset we are deconsolidating, this is an event, which will unfold during the second quarter, so we will inform you in due time of the parameters of this. We are not ready now to communicate about this. This was for the first question. For the CapEx, Yann?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  But maybe, Laurent, we can help the analyst. The sales of the asset to be deferred which is held for sale were EUR 63 million last year and the EBIT was EUR 1.8 million.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Martino De Ambroggi,  Equita SIM S.p.A., Research Division - Analyst   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. So CapEx now?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  CapEx, it's really based to the overall environment. We started cutting on CapEx in Q4 of last year considering the trend in sales. We shall need to view the situation very cautiously. If the market goes down, we'll cut on CapEx. If not, CapEx should be higher than last year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The next question is from Alexandre Raverdy of Kepler.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alexandre Raverdy,  Kepler Cheuvreux, Research Division - Equity Research Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  The first one regards the outlook that you provided an outlook for Q2, but if you look at the full year, what is your assumption for the full year in terms of global production? Because I think I just expect around minus 1%. We -- you have one of the competitors reporting performing that actually they expect global production to decline in the low to mid-single digits. I mean what's your assumption of that? And do you confirm that you will perform in line with the market? Or do you expect to outperform, let's say, if you have a minus 1% or minus 3%? That would be the first question. I will ask the other one afterwards.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you. Concerning the market, we stay with the initial forecast, which was to have 2019 in line with 2018. In line is bold enough to allow a few percentage points lower, but for the time being, we stick with that. In terms of performance, we are showing the first quarter will be outperforming the market. And I'm confident that in the second quarter, we should as well outperform the market by 300 to 400 basis points. And this is what we can say today.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Alexandre Raverdy,  Kepler Cheuvreux, Research Division - Equity Research Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Okay. Second question is on the tax rates. So it remained quite high in Q1. I think the full year guidance was around 50%. Is it something that you confirm? And the final question so -- also regards production. So we have some deadlines in September with the Real Driving Emissions and the WLTP on FCVs. What's your view on that? Do you expect some disruption in Europe in Q3? Or do you feel like the customers are much better prepared than last year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yann Albrand,  Sogefi S.p.A. - Group CFO &amp; Investors Relation   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  So on the tax rate, roughly it's going to be in line with the guidance we initially provided, but it can change because it's very simple. If we have drops in volumes in certain areas where the market is shaky, this triggers losses and this can trigger abnormal tax rates. So Filtration will vastly depend on market such as Mercosur where, as Laurent pointed out, the market production dropped very significantly in Q1 in Argentina and it dropped by 10% in North Brazil. So this can trigger unusual situation, but for the time being, we are not changing our guidance.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Yes. Concerning the production, RDE and LCV, the information we are having is that customers are better prepared. So we do not expect significant disruptions from there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  (Operator Instructions) Gentlemen, there are no more questions registered at this time.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Laurent Hebenstreit,  Sogefi S.p.A. - MD, GM, CEO &amp; Director   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Thank you very much for your participation to this call concerning the first quarter 2019 and the outlook for Sogefi. We wish you a very good day. Thank you very much.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q1 2019 Sogefi SpA Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>MANTOVA</city>
  <companyName>Sogefi SpA</companyName>
  <companyTicker>SO.MI</companyTicker>
  <startDate>29-Apr-19 7:30am GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>158470</companyId>
  <CUSIP />
  <SEDOL>4820668</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>IT0000076536</ISIN>
</Event>