<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="5891418" lastUpdate="Tuesday, January 19, 2016 at 8:33:23pm GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="5891418.F" expirationDate="Tuesday, January 19, 2016 at 1:45:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of UNH earnings conference call or presentation 19-Jan-16 1:45pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q4 2015 UnitedHealth Group Inc Earnings Call

Hopkins Jan 19, 2016 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of UnitedHealth Group Inc earnings conference call or presentation Tuesday, January 19, 2016 at 1:45:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Stephen Hemsley
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO
   *  Larry Renfro
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO  of Optum
   *  Dave Wichmann
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - President and CFO
   *  Dan Schumacher
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare
   *  Steve Nelson
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Medicare &amp; Retirement
   *  Austin Pittman
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State
   *  John Rex
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO of Optum
   *  Jeff Alter
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Employer &amp; Individual
   *  John Prince
      UnitedHealth Group Inc. - EVP and Chief of Operations of Optum

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Matthew Borsch
      Goldman Sachs - Analyst
   *  Josh Raskin
      Barclays Capital - Analyst
   *  Andy Schenker
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Chris Rigg
      Susquehanna Financial Group / SIG - Analyst
   *  A.J. Rice
      UBS - Analyst
   *  Kevin Fischbeck
      BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst
   *  Peter Costa
      Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst
   *  Gary Taylor
      JPMorgan - Analyst
   *  Christine Arnold
      Cowen and Company - Analyst
   *  Sarah James
      Wedbush Securities - Analyst
   *  Sheryl Skolnick
      Mizuho USA - Analyst
   *  Scott Fidel
      Credit Suisse - Analyst
   *  Ralph Giacobbe
      Citigroup - Analyst
   *  Ana Gupte
      Leerink Partners - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. I will be your conference operator today. Welcome to the UnitedHealth Group fourth-quarter and full-year 2015 earnings conference call.
 (Operator Instructions)
 As a reminder, this call is being recorded. Here is some important introductory information.
 This call contains forward-looking statements under US federal security laws. These statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from historical experience or present expectations. A description of some of the risks and uncertainties can be found in the reports that we file with the Securities and Exchange Commission, including the cautionary statements included in our current and periodic filings.
 This call will also reference non-GAAP amounts. A reconciliation of the non-GAAP to GAAP amounts is available on the financial reports and SEC filings section of the Company's investors page at www.UnitedHealthGroup.com.
 Information presented on this call is contained in the Earnings Release we issued this morning and in our Form 8-K dated January 19, 2016, which may be accessed from the investors page of the Company's website. I would now like to turn the conference over to the Chief Executive Officer of UnitedHealth Group, Mr. Stephen Hemsley. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for joining us today as we close on 2015 and look ahead to 2016. We finished 2015 in line with the guidance provided at our December investor conference, with fourth-quarter adjusted earnings per share at $1.40, bringing full-year 2015 adjusted earnings per share to $6.45.
 Overall, UnitedHealthcare had a positive year and finished with strong fourth-quarter growth, exceeding 300,000 members and growing across all its markets. Optum delivered an exceptionally strong fourth quarter with revenues up 70% and earnings up 46% over the prior year. Before we go into the business commentary, let me offer a brief recap of 2015.
 2015 UnitedHealth Group revenue grew more than 20% to $157 billion with organic revenue growth of 10%. Our cash flows were exceptional at $9.7 billion, up 21% year over year. Our dividend increased 33% to an annual rate of $2 per share this year.
 UnitedHealthcare grew to serve more than 1.7 million more people domestically as Optum grew its revenues by 42% and revenue backlog by more than 20%. Excluding the impact of individual exchange compliant products, and reserves related to the initiation of a new Medicaid contract, UnitedHealth Group still grew revenues by 19% in 2015 and grew operating earnings 15% to $11.8 billion, and that would have produced an adjusted earnings per share of $7, a 16% year-over-year increase, again absent those two items, to give you an idea of the underlying strength of the enterprise.
 We know the individual exchanges are top of mind to you, and Dave Wichmann will discuss these fully in his comments. As we said at the investor conference, the balance of our total business, the well more than $175 billion of it, is thriving, considerably stronger and better positioned than this time last year. We are committed to delivering a strong 2016 performance year in growth, in financial results, and in the quality of our services and Net Promoter Score, or NPS, performance metrics.
 2016 is off to a strong start, considerably stronger than 2015. Our initial growth trends are very encouraging and our service performance for new January business is strong. Optum's revenue backlog and pipeline have never been stronger.
 Medical costs in the fourth quarter trended slightly better than expected and we're confident our benefit businesses have appropriately priced their products for 2016. Our operating business platforms drive these results.
 So I will ask Larry Renfro to review Optum's performance for full-year 2015 and Dave Wichmann to cover UnitedHealthcare and provide some UnitedHealth Group enterprise-wide comments. Larry?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Larry Renfro,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO  of Optum   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Steve. 2015 was, without question, an exceptional performance year for Optum in revenues and earnings growth and in our preparations to set up 2016 to deliver well for the nearly 115 million people we serve. Optum's businesses have strong momentum and are producing strong, sustainable growth across the board.
 Since beginning the One Optum journey in 2011, we have compounded revenues at 23% per year and operating earnings at 34% per year. In 2015, Optum's revenues of $67.6 billion grew 42%, including organic revenue growth of 13%. OptumRx revenues grew 51% this past year to $48 billion, and even excluding the Catamaran combination posted solid double-digit organic growth.
 OptumHealth and OptumInsight together grew revenues to more than $20 billion, which is growth of 24% over 2014. Our full-year operating margin of 6.3% reflects the increased mix of pharmacy care services revenues, driven by OptumRx organic growth and five months of Catamaran business. Both OptumHealth and OptumInsight's strong full-year 2015 margins are sustainable and we project operating margin expansion for OptumRx in 2016.
 In 2015, we added to our strategic relationship portfolio which now numbers 10 and we remain focused on developing more of these comprehensive large-scale relationships. They leverage Optum's unique end-to-end capabilities to help solve the broader challenges customers and prospects are facing in a changing healthcare environment, whether they are physicians or hospitals, health benefit sponsors, governments or consumers.
 To illustrate, consider our Optum360 revenue management relationship with Dignity Health where cash flows have already improved by $0.5 billion and accounts are being settled a full eight days faster, and where our documentation technology is helping Dignity Health physicians meet demanding ICD-10 requirements, even as they are realizing a 50% gain in productivity. Or consider OptumCare, our expanding care delivery business in which we are developing some of the most impactful and durable consumer relationships. Today, we serve 7 million patients through more than 150 payer relationships across our physician practices, our community-based clinical services and our MedExpress neighborhood care centers.
 MedExpress operates at the convergence of healthcare and retail, measuring success one patient at a time. MedExpress can provide as much as 90% of the care patients receive in the ER and for as little as 10% of the cost. MedExpress mitigates costs for both payers and consumers while providing high-quality convenient care.
 We currently operate over 160 neighborhood care centers with a goal of operating several multiples of that number five years from now. Today, there are OptumCare clinics in more than 270 locations in 26 local markets, having recently added ProHealth in the Connecticut market to that distinctive high-performance practice portfolio.
 Our pipeline for growth is gaining momentum, as well. The OptumCare approach respects local market norms and expectations, and our doctors consistently deliver high-quality results for the communities they serve. We consistently outperform benchmarks around acute care re-admissions and skilled nursing facility stays.
 More than three-quarters of private Medicare patients we care for are in health plans rated four stars or better. And more than 96% of our patients would recommend our local care provider office to others.
 For patients with complex medical conditions, our integrated care model has proven distinctive results. We deliver on average a 50% reduction in overall healthcare costs for medically complex patients with very high patient and family satisfaction. A number of OptumCare's high-performing practices have been nationally recognized for their performance and counsel care initiatives, including Monarch in Southern California and ProHealth in New York Metro area.
 And, finally, our HouseCalls services continue to deliver clear and distinctive value for Medicare recipients and payers, with 98% patient satisfaction and more than 1 million visits to patients in their homes delivered in 2015 and further growth in 2016. With the market momentum we have today, and through these constantly advances capabilities, we expect OptumCare will remain a high growth business for many years to come.
 As we share other examples in future quarters that reflect Optum's growing diversification, such as our military and veterans health services, or our pharmacy care services, or our technology support services, you should see with even more clarity a pattern emerging, the application of data, technology, and services to bring better performance, helping health systems work better for everyone.
 Today revenues from our top 25 customer relationships at Optum have quadrupled over the last three years. In 2015 the average customer award size doubled across OptumHealth and OptumInsight. And we expect continued strong customer retention at OptumRx as we work to bring the powerful benefits of the OptumRx merger to these clients.
 Prominent organizations continue to inquire about how our capabilities can help them, so we are exploring potentially large and interesting new strategic relationships. In many cases these pairings could further accelerate growth in the OptumInsight backlog, which now exceeds $10.4 billion and grew by more than 20% year over year. Within the current portion of that backlog, we already cover more than 80% of OptumInsight's full-year projected 2016 revenues.
 We remain optimistic about the prospects for Optum in 2016, 2017 and beyond. For 2016, we are projecting revenues to well exceed $80 billion, which would be growth in the area of 20%, and for operating earnings to grow 30% to 34% to more than $5.55 billion. Optum is becoming an increasingly valuable business and now represents about 42% of UnitedHealth Group's consolidated operating earnings outlook.
 Now let me turn it over to Dave.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dave Wichmann,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - President and CFO   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Larry. UnitedHealthcare continues to differentiate itself from competitors on a foundation of distinctive service, product innovation, and integrated clinical and network value, and the result is strong, sustainable growth. UnitedHealthcare now serves 46.4 million medical members and we have leading market positions in all private health insurance segments of North and South America.
 Over the past five years, we have grown by nearly 13.5 million people or 40%, well-diversified across commercial, government programs, and international offerings. This reflects the deliberate diversification and consistent competitiveness of our offerings globally.
 UnitedHealthcare continued this trend in 2015 growing to serve 1.75 million more people domestically as it continues to improve its market share. UnitedHealthcare's full-year revenues grew nearly 10% to $131.3 billion. The full-year operating margins of 5.1% decreased, as expected, declining 70 basis points year over year due to the effects of public insurance exchange products.
 Full-year commercial medical cost trends of 5.5% came in at the low end of our initial outlook one year ago. Our cost trends reflect the positive, sustainable impact of higher consumer engagement, strong alignment of incentives with care professionals through value-based relationships, and improving data collection and application.
 We are equally pleased with emerging innovation trends in our business focused on advancing the consumer movement in healthcare. Today, 25 million consumers are served through our Advocate For Me service model. People served by this innovative approach are more engaged in their health and are more effective in their healthcare decision-making and are more satisfied.
 Today over 23 million consumers have joined our Rally digital health application and we are seeing steady advances in daily active use of these services, including, importantly, engagement around selecting primary care physicians, better use of urgent care over emergency care, screenings and higher adoption of personal health and condition management programs. And today our real Appeal digital medical service, designed to help manage weight and reduce the onset of diabetes, has been deployed to accounts representing 1 million people in just the last half of 2015, and with an additional 0.5 million committed for the first half of 2016.
 The initial results are encouraging, with 46% of participants achieving a meaningful reduction of 5% or more of their body weight within 16 weeks. 5% weight loss reduces the conversion to diabetes by nearly 60% according to studies conducted by the National Institute of Health. With these exceptional results, we plan to make available digitally a broader set of preventative medical services to engage people to live healthier lives to the fullest.
 Across UnitedHealthcare we intend to continue to positively impact the quality of social services, condition management, cost and quality transparency, convenient care, wellness and the overall quality of life of the consumers we serve by giving them the tools like these to engage them in their health.
 Our work is improving the quality of patient care. In Medicare we helped close 9 million gaps in care for the seniors we serve. We will serve 1.7 million members in health plans with higher star ratings in 2017 as we expect at least 63% of our members to be in a four-star plan. And we will further improve that percentage in 2018 to 80% or more.
 It is not a coincidence we are off to our strongest growth start for Medicare Advantage in Company history. We expect to close first quarter with growth of around 300,000 seniors in Medicare Advantage, and we are tracking well against our full year outlook of 325,000 to 400,000 people in net growth.
 In commercial benefits we combine tiered networks, our clinical strategies, and innovative product designs in a myriad of ways to align to a wide array of affordable price points for employers and consumers. Today one-third of our commercial customers are served through one of these more affordable plan offerings. That's double the number from five years ago and we expect that percentage to more than double again over the next five years, aiding to our exceptional growth.
 In Medicaid, over the past two years we have secured new contract awards totaling more than 2 million people. Managed Medicaid continues to emerge as the ultimate long-term sustaining solution for states, and we believe UnitedHealthcare offers our state customers the most distinctive and comprehensive set of capabilities. Like in Medicare and commercial, we are well-positioned for 2016 growth in community and state.
 Turning to exchanges, we expect to start the year at around 700,000 or fewer public exchange members, and expect these numbers will steadily decline over the course of the year. We are not pursuing membership growth and have taken a comprehensive set of actions to contain membership and sharpen performance over the balance of 2016. We have strong platinum products, increased prices, eliminated marketing and commissions, intensified clinical engagement and medical management with this membership group, and reduced operating cost, as appropriate.
 As a matter of prudence we have increased our premium deficiency reserve by $65 million above our investor comfort estimates, bringing the total fourth-quarter charge to $340 million. $245 million of that charge addresses 2016's exchange compliant product exposure. This is in addition to the unreserved losses included in our 2016 outlook.
 Combined, more than $0.5 billion is set aside for 2016. We believe we have fully captured 2016 exposure now based on our actual starting enrollment. And by mid 2016, we will determine to what extent, if any, we will continue to offer products in the exchange market in 2017.
 In Medicaid, the start of the new program in Iowa has been deferred, while the state has also increased the assigned enrollment for each contracted plan, which increases our estimate of revenues. We are in constructive discussions with the state concerning elements of an effective and sustainable managed Medicaid program to serve that market.
 As we look into 2016 and 2017, we believe UnitedHealthcare will continue to grow at a strong pace and profitably improve its market share. Fundamentally, UnitedHealthcare is emerging across the spectrum of consumer-driven products, service, wellness, transparency and, most important, care engagement and clinical quality, particularly in government programs. We have room to improve but with sharp focus on NPS and the quality of the work we do and a culture centered around helping others, we have an opportunity to offer even greater value to consumers, providers and customers alike in the coming years.
 Before Steve sums up, let me touch on the outlook for UnitedHealth Group as a whole. We are committed to strong performance in 2016 across UnitedHealthcare and Optum in service, in operations, in growth, in earnings generation and in cash flow production.
 We foresee cash flows approaching $10 billion and adjusted net earnings of $7.60 to $7.80 per share. Again, adjusted net earnings for us is GAAP EPS plus after-tax intangible amortization. We encourage everyone to move to adjusted net earnings to enable better comparability among companies and among the analyst community.
 We expect about 46% to 47% of full-year earnings in the first half of the year, with Optum at approximately 40% of its full-year plan in the first half, exactly as you saw it last year and in the past. We expect the rate of our earnings growth to strengthen during 2016. Current consensus Street estimates for first-quarter adjusted earnings per share might be slightly strong compared to our expectations at the moment.
 All-in, we have a strong view of 2016 and look forward the to this year. Steve?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Dave. At our investor conference we offered a sense of the growing innovation and entrepreneurial activity in our Company and the restless drive our team has to grow and improve performance. On the customer side, we're committed to further elevating satisfaction for consumers, care providers and all our stakeholders to levels more often seen outside our industries, to better meet the increasing expectations people and society have for healthcare.
 When our Net Promoter Scores reflect people being staunch advocates for our products and businesses because of the way we make their lives simpler and the value we provide as they define and experience it as consumers and customers, we'll be on the path to creating truly distinctive and substantial growth and brand equity. We believe a differentiated brand and reputation will drive accelerated growth in market share gains for our businesses for years to come.
 Our goal for serving you as investors in 2016 is simple -- we're committed to delivering clean, strong results this year, backed by a growing pipeline of opportunities for 2017 and beyond. We expect distinguished revenue growth, earnings and cash flow in 2016 that continue to reflect the diversity, breadth and overall strength of our enterprise and the valuable businesses we are building.
 Thank you for your interest today. And, operator, can we take some questions this morning? One per analyst, please. Thank you.
================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (Operator Instructions)
 We can take our first question from Matthew Borsch with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Borsch,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, hi, good morning. Could you just talk about what the factors were that caused you to increase your booking for anticipated losses in 2016? I think it was $45 million higher on the exchange side and $20 million higher on the Medicaid contract, if I got that right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, you do, and it's really just purely updating. I think Dan Schumacher can take you through it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, Matt. You're right, we did increase our loss expectations for 2016. What it came down to, really, as we closed out the year we took a prudent posture on the 2015 impact and then we carried that through to 2016 outlook, and then we adjusted further for a little higher enrollment expectation for 2016. So, those are the elements that played into the increase in both the 2015 impact and the assumed losses for 2016 in the individual exchange compliant plan offerings.
 And then with regard to the Medicaid portion, that's simply just a function of higher enrollment expectation as the number of carriers was reduced from four down to three. But when you put that all together, in total, as we close the year it was about $100 million of impact beyond what our guidance had assumed from December.
 So, our base business, the vast majority of our business performed exceptionally well and we delivered fully in line with the expectations as we closed out 2015. And then, as we look to 2016, we've incorporated that, again, fully into our outlook as we reaffirm our guidance for 2016.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Borsch,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And, if I could, just one related question -- in the fourth quarter on individual enrollment I think your total book is about 1.2 million. How the did that change as a result -- at the end of the year and then coming into this year as a result of the co-op insolvencies and related instability in the individual market?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dave Wichmann,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - President and CFO   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I think the last time we talked we talked about our individual exchange compliant being about 700,000 of that 1.2 million you referenced. As we closed out the year, that came in at about 650,000 lives. And then we'll expect that to grow as we step into January, and then it will start to shrink again over the course of the year as some of those enrollees trade out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Matthew Borsch,  Goldman Sachs - Analyst   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I would just say it's an overarching philosophy. Our goal in this area is to be careful, conservative and to make sure that we really capture all this so that really we derisk 2016. Next question, please.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll take our next question from Josh Raskin with Barclays.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Raskin,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, thanks. Good morning. I want to talk a little about Medicare Advantage. I know the CMS data is relatively preliminary but it certainly seems like you guys are well on pace to beat the 400,000 for the full year at the high end. So, just curious, it doesn't sound like you've gotten much star improvement this year so what made your products more attractive? Was it more retention? Is it more agents or coming from other plans? Just any color on where the growth's coming from.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. It is good growth, as Dave indicated, but Steve Nelson can really respond to that and it is a very positive story.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Nelson,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Medicare &amp; Retirement   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Steve. Hi Josh, it's Steve Nelson. Yes, very positive about the growth that we're seeing coming through the AP. Just a little insight into that growth. First, it's important to remember that it comes as a result of and after a couple years of really hard work as we repositioned this product to some of the changes in Medicare Advantage program -- introduced premiums, created a more aligned and engaged network and relationships with our providers, and meaningful improvement in stars, as you mentioned.
 And, second, we really like where the growth is coming from. I think Dave mentioned in his comments about 300,000 or so as a result of AEP. About a third of that comes from Group. So, really good insight into that pricing and that membership.
 And then within the individual business, meaningful improvement in our retention also has added to this growth. This is membership that we've been engaged with and they've been involved in our clinical programs. And it's very evenly spread across geography and products.
 But the stability of our products, the evolution of our portfolio is really resonating in the market, so I think that's all contributed to the growth. And we expect this Medicare Advantage product to continue to grow as we look to 2017 and beyond.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Raskin,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And, Steve, just a quick follow-up on that. Do you have a percentage of how many are coming from previously not in MA, whether that's agents or traditional fee for service versus how many are coming from other plans, competing plans?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Nelson,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Medicare &amp; Retirement   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's a little early to give that kind of color, but I would say, in general, in terms of how we look at the membership it's very much in line with our expectations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Josh Raskin,  Barclays Capital - Analyst   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And our next question comes from Andy Schenker with Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andy Schenker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Maybe just going back to the exchange enrollment real quickly, just a few on the membership here. Maybe if you could talk a little bit how your positioning or membership growth compared to the existing states versus the 11 new states you entered. And then related to that, obviously still a little over a week left in open enrollment, but just what kind of forecasts are you expecting for total enrollment? I assume you're trying to -- you assume there's a big jump in the last week or two but just how we should think about that 700,000 related to expectation the last two weeks. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Steve Nelson,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Medicare &amp; Retirement   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, good morning, Andy. On the exchange enrollment specifically, the 700,000 that Dave mentioned beginning January, we ended the year with just about 500,000. So, that jumped up to about 700,000 as of 1/1. We would expect that over the balance of the open enrollment period to grow something underneath, to about 800,000, something a little south of that. And then we would expect that to wear off as you pace through the year as those members attrit out.
 In terms of where it's coming from, I would tell you that the net growth is coming with a greater orientation towards those new states as well as expansion areas, but a little bit of mix of both.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andy Schenker,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Our next question comes from Chris Rigg with Susquehanna. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Rigg,  Susquehanna Financial Group / SIG - Analyst   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Thanks. Just on the last question, I got a little confused with the numbers, Dan, just on the 800,000 versus 700,000, 500,000 ending the year and 650,000-ish now. Can you just confirm, did you end the year at 650,000 or was it 500,000? And then my real question with regard to all of this, do you know how many of the people that are currently signed up were enrolled with you last year versus new membership? Thanks a lot.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Just to be clear, we ended the year with 650,000 lives in individual exchange-compliant offerings. Inside of that, 500,000 of them were on exchange. So, the balance, 150,000, was off exchange.
 And then as we step into January that exchange component, which ended the year at about 500,000, grows to about 700,000. And then as you move towards the end of the open enrollment period it grows further, up towards 800,000, something south of that, and then works its way down over the year. The off exchange is more level than what we experience in the on exchange.
 And then to your last question about mix of enrollment, more than half of the enrollment is new to us and a little less than half of the enrollment is existing enrollment base.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Rigg,  Susquehanna Financial Group / SIG - Analyst   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great, thanks a lot.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll go next to AJ Rice with UBS. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 A.J. Rice,  UBS - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, everybody. I just might ask, focus my question on Medicaid, both. Do you update your membership with one player dropping out in Iowa? Was that enough to move the needle? We've had some companies comment on concern about profitability in Medicaid year to year. Can you give us some flavor there?
 And then, finally on that, the health insurer fee question for 2017, have you gotten any clarity from CMS as it relates to either Medicaid or Medicare in how they're going to treat that or the space?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is quite an impressive single question, AJ. We'll break that up into pieces and we'll start with Austin on Medicaid.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Austin Pittman,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hey, AJ, this is Austin. How are you?
 First of all, I think you were asking about Iowa. We did increase our membership outlook and assumptions for Iowa as the state moves from four players to three.
 As far as the sustainability of the program, I think, first of all, as we stated before, we're really honored to have been selected to serve the people of Iowa. We continue to feel good about the relationship that we've developed with the state.
 We're in very productive conversations with them about really tried-and-true methods to ensure long-term stability. We feel good about where that's headed and it will become a long-term and very durable part of our portfolio.
 And, really, with regard to the rates overall, as you know, states are always pressured. There's nothing new in that. I think we're very pleased with our business, most pleased with the value that we've been able to bring to the customers and to the consumers over the years.
 We've got a very strong management team, very locally deployed and able to manage these populations and really help people in very vulnerable situations and deliver value for the long term. So I think we feel good about a pressured but stable rate environment and the growth in this market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And nothing really distinctive in terms of the rate environment, the same pressures that exist every year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Austin Pittman,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Absolutely.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, AJ, it's Dan Schumacher. On the health insurers tax, I'd be remiss if I didn't mention that from our perspective obviously the tax just increases the underlying cost of healthcare and, as a result, makes healthcare less affordable. As we look at the elimination of it for 2017, we're certainly encouraged by that and, frankly, we've been long supporters of its permanent repeal.
 Now, with that said, I'll tell you, in terms of the impact, in Medicaid we expect it to be no impact. In the commercial business, because that's priced on a policy year basis and the tax is levied on a calendar year basis, there's no impact over three years but there are some differences by year, and we expect it to actually be a drag on our 2016 earnings. We've estimated that impact to be about $100 million pretax or about $0.06 earnings per share.
 And then, lastly, in the Medicare business, the tax has not been part of the rate-setting process previously so we wouldn't expect it to be for 2017 either.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And that pressure's covered in our guidance. We basically absorb that in our guidance given the strength of the start of the year. Next question, please.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll go next to Kevin Fischbeck with Bank of America.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fischbeck,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. Thanks. Go back to the exchanges. If we shift the premium reserve from 2015 into 2016, are you saying that you expect to lose more money on exchanges in 2016 than you did in 2015? And, if so, why would that be the case? You had a chance to price up the core business.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'll have Dan answer this, but I think as a matter of prudence what we are doing is making sure that we have covered ourselves appropriately in 2016, and if that means we set aside more money between the reserves that have been set aside and what we have covered within our guidance, that is clearly our purpose. We are really focused on making sure that this item is really covered in 2016, so I think that's what you should read through in terms of our activities. Dan?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Good morning, Kevin. If you move the premium deficiency reserve and reset the years and look at it, on the individual exchange compliant plans within 2015 we lost about $475 million on the 2015 policy year. In the 2016 policy year, as Dave Wichmann mentioned, we'll lose more than $500 million. We've got about a 10% increase in the loss assumption balanced against about a 25% to 30% growth assumption in the underlying enrollment base.
 The reason that we're able to do that is to the points that you mentioned. Obviously we came in with very strong pricing, in that mid double digits, and, further, we made some strong refinements to our product portfolio. Those are the largest contributors. But beyond that, we're also working every single day to tune our operating environment, as well as focus our clinical interventions and our network orientation around this population.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fischbeck,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I guess the loss -- you mentioned half the growth will be in new states and new geographies. Is that why you have losses really at all building up? Or do you think that the core business is actually going to get worse, as well?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I think it's going up because we've got enrollment growth. And then balanced against that is our pricing, our products' positioning, our clinical interventions, our operating environment and the improvements we're making there.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan, I might point out that this is what we are providing. We are being careful in terms of making sure that we have covered this off. These are not losses that we are sustaining. These are what we have protected ourselves against in terms of 2016.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kevin Fischbeck,  BofA Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, great. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll take the next question from Peter Costa with Wells Fargo.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Costa,  Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks for the question. Previously you said that you were expecting $0.13 to $0.15, or $200 million to $225 million as additional losses from the exchange business in 2016. It seems like that grew a little bit because you talked about over $0.5 billion now in losses, including the $245 million PDR.
 But my question gets to, if that's the right number, the $0.13 to $0.15 -- and maybe correct me if I'm wrong -- that would be, say, $0.14 at the mid point added to the mid point of $7.60 to $7.80 guide. So, let's call that $7.84 of potential earnings. That's only 12% growth from the $7 number that you have, excluding the individual business item.
 Yet last year you grew 16% to get to that $7 in terms of earnings. Which of your core businesses is the one responsible for the slow down from 16% to 12%?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter, those are projected numbers. We would think that we could perform even more strongly. I think that by just isolating that against a beginning of the year range may not be a fair comparison in comparing your 16% to 12%.
 Actually, as we take a look across our spectrum of businesses, we really don't see any of these businesses in a position that they are actually -- I would say they're all stronger than they were as compared to this time last year as we enter. Clearly, across the board at Optum, the strength of the portfolio from one end to the other has advanced. And in terms of UnitedHealthcare, I think all those businesses have strengthened and I think our positioning on the exchange has strengthened. So, I think my view on this is it is a pretty positive outlook.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Costa,  Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So 16%, you'd say the difference between the 16% and the 12% then is PPD perhaps? Is that what you would say?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, I'm not sure you can, in my view, take that one element and then project against an estimated earnings range as we go out. We could be even stronger than that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Peter Costa,  Wells Fargo Securities, LLC - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll take our next question from Gary Taylor with JPMorgan.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Taylor,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hi, good morning. This is a question for Larry, I think. When we look at OptumInsight, operating income was up a couple hundred million dollars sequentially. Same case last year, it was up about $100 million sequentially in the fourth quarter. Can you just remind us the source of the seasonality in the operating income for OptumInsight, please?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. I think we'll have Larry give you some sense of the growth of momentum there and then respond to that specific question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Larry Renfro,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO  of Optum   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary, it's Larry. I think that you've seen over the last few years that the fourth quarter is obviously a dominant quarter for us. We believe that it will stay that way. If I had to break it down I'll give you three areas to think about.
 A lot of times at the beginning of the year we're making investments and those investments pay off in the fourth quarter, and you see a little bit of that happening. We're also in implementation mode during the year and those implementations and installations also come true in the fourth quarter and that enables us to obviously have a stronger position at that point.
 When you look at the products and services, there's specific products, like obviously distribution, that goes along with open enrollment. But also our pay for performance and incentives will also hit in the fourth quarter. We don't see that changing. We see that being the pattern that Optum in general will be experiencing.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Taylor,  JPMorgan - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll go next to Christine Arnold with Cowen.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Christine Arnold,  Cowen and Company - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Impressive increase in backlog for OptumInsight. Can you remind us -- I think you gave us some parameters at Investor Day -- how to translate that into expected revenue over time? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Rex,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - EVP &amp; CFO of Optum   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, Christine, it's John Rex. Good morning. When you think about the backlog, $10.4 billion backlog, you see at Insight, some of the guidance points that we provided on that is you should expect about 60% of that to be recognized in the 2016 revenues. That would equate to about 80% of the full-year revenue outlook.
 Another way to look at that is that the average duration of the backlog runs about 20 months. These have been fairly consistent numbers and I'd expect that to be fairly consistent as you look ahead, also.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Larry Renfro,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO  of Optum   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Christine, it's Larry. One thing I would add to what John said is that as of now about 90% of our 2016 revenue is locked in. Obviously that's part of the backlog.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Christine Arnold,  Cowen and Company - Analyst   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Perfect. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll take our next question from Sarah James with Wedbush Securities.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sarah James,  Wedbush Securities - Analyst   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. I just have one quick qualifier before my question. You had mentioned earlier that there are conversations with states' Medicaid rates around tried-and-true methods that ensure stability. I'm wondering if this is referencing changes in the risk adjustment methodology that can lead to some premium give backs. Or are you talking about other aspects of tried-and-true methods?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Austin Pittman,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is Austin. Really, I was talking about a whole portfolio of methods. You can think about care coordination, network management, the level of transparency that we address, the rates and emerging experience over time with states. So, you couldn't narrow it down to any one.
 We've got a very long-term history of 20- and 30-year relationships, so a lot of success in how we work with states. That's what led us to feel so confident and comfortable with where we go with Iowa and really with our whole portfolio of states.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sarah James,  Wedbush Securities - Analyst   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. It's just that I know some of your peers are trying to lobby to get those risk adjustors changed back so I wasn't sure if that was an indication that United was, as well. But it sounds like there's some other aspects that you're negotiating with.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Austin Pittman,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wouldn't comment in any further detail about the specifics of any conversation with any state.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sarah James,  Wedbush Securities - Analyst   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Got it. In the past you've talked about opportunities for growth in Medicaid outside the RFP cycle, like states a assigning LTSS or carving in other products. Do you still see that as a possibility and is there anything near term?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Austin Pittman,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Community &amp; State   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me comment on the pipeline overall, which I think is very strong. States continue to move and look to managed care as solutions for their healthcare needs. That movement continues as states really embrace this.
 I think that activity -- in fact, I think we expect to respond to over 20 RFPs this year that will be implemented in 2016, 2017 and on into 2018. So, again, when I say the pipeline is strong, it's very strong. That's heavily weighted towards more complex populations. That's really what you're talking about when you speak to LTSS and the movement of those complex populations from fee for service into managed Medicaid.
 We've got one of the largest books of business in that space. We've got a very long history at dealing with these very vulnerable people and delivering real value to those individuals, as well as value to the states.
 So I think we feel -- and Dave mentioned it in our opening comments -- uniquely positioned between UnitedHealthcare and Optum to really serve these populations, help them live healthier lives year over year, and deliver value back to the states in the process. So, I think our outlook for that continued movement, even within states where we're already providing traditional tenant population managed care, to continue to grow into those complex populations.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sarah James,  Wedbush Securities - Analyst   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll go next to Sheryl Skolnick with Mizuho USA.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sheryl Skolnick,  Mizuho USA - Analyst   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks so much. First of all, let me step back. Against the backdrop of a somewhat challenging situation with exchanges, let me -- and this shouldn't sound false -- compliment everyone from UHC to Optum to senior management on the way you performed and handled during 2015. I'm impressed by especially the fact that, from where I sit, the progress you've made with the cost structure as well as positioning of the business, I don't remember United having a better cost structure, better positioning going into a growth year in a very long time, if ever, than you've got now.
 Let me ask a question about one of those things that's interesting to me that you performed well on, which is the cash flow. It's multi-part.
 One, why the strength? Two, does this change in any way your thoughts around share repurchases versus deleveraging versus investment in the business for 2016? And, three, it seems like 2016 guidance is perhaps a little bit more conservative, if not a little modest, on the cash flow, and I was just wondering what you think might change.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dave will touch on the beginning of that and then we'll get into the share buyback, invest, et cetera as part two.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dave Wichmann,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - President and CFO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Sheryl. First, thank you for the recognition of the hard work this team has done this year, particularly in the last of half of the year, to get its cost structures aligned and to really position its business for growth in 2016 and beyond.
 Cash flows were exceptionally strong. I think you know from past calls and discussions that we've had we are very focused on cash flows, and in particular managing the balance sheet elements of our business. And the strength of the cash flows, or the departure from what our original expectations were, were really around collecting receivables more quickly and paying claims more in line with what our contractual requirements are as opposed to paying early. So, just better working capital management really contributed to that.
 As it relates to then what our priorities are for that, is around share repurchases, deleveraging and investment. We're going to continue to maintain a very balanced posture with respect to those things. Obviously it's important that we continue to delever the business, as we had indicated that we would, over the course of 18 months following the Catamaran transaction, and we continue to be committed to doing so.
 Part of that is our expectation is that we'll continue to curtail our share repurchases, at least for 2016, unless extreme circumstances arise, but for 2016 to about $1.2 billion to $1.5 billion in cash use. And as you can probably suspect by the activity that's under way in our business, we continue to be a strong investor in new capabilities organically in our business but also through acquisitive means.
 As it relates to 2016 and the cash flow, it's certainly jumping off about a $9.7 billion cash flow year. With stronger earnings expectations for 2016 you would expect that you would achieve higher cash flows. And, as a result, we used language of $9.5 billion to $10 billion of cash flows, we're now talking closer to $10 billion.
 We'll take a hard look at that over the course of the first quarter and reassess whether or not we can push that number forward. But clearly the business is operating well from a balance sheet management perspective and we'll do all we can to move the cash flow number forward.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sheryl Skolnick,  Mizuho USA - Analyst   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Excellent. Thank you so much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll go next to Scott Fidel with Credit Suisse.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Fidel,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. I just had one follow-up, first, on the exchanges. At the Investor Day I know you had talked about assuming around a negative 15% margin in the exchanges. Just as you work through the updated math, is that still how we should be thinking about that or different relative to that number?
 And then just a follow-up question. I'm just interested outside of the exchange, just on the membership front, how membership ended up developing for the rest of the commercial risk business for the 2016 enrollment period, most notably in the small group segment. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll have Dan comment on the first and then Jeff Alter speak to the business in 2016.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, Scott. Where we landed on a policy year basis as we closed out 2015, our policy year losses on the exchanges were in that mid-teens range that we talked about at the investor conference. So, 15%, 16%.
 If you look at 2016 on a policy year basis, we expect that to moderate some. We'd be into the low double digits from a margin percentage basis with higher enrollment base, lower percentage margin losses, again on those things that I talked about earlier -- so, the strength of our pricing, the repositioning of our product portfolio, and then our management efforts underneath that. Hopefully that provides a sense for what you're looking for. And then, Jeff, on enrollment.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jeff Alter,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO of UnitedHealthcare Employer &amp; Individual   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, Scott. It's Jeff Alter. We closed out 2015 with very strong growth across both our fully-insured and self-funded product. I would say driving a good part of that was increased retention of our existing clients. And in certain markets we saw the market come back to our pricing, particularly in small group.
 We also had the opportunity to win back a very large part of the Health Republic small group bloc in New York at our rates. And as you recall from early 2014, one of our headwinds was that Health Republic pricing against our small group bloc in New York, so we were in position to win that back during the fourth quarter of 2015, which is good.
 We also couple that with very strong specialty sales. Our vision and dental products are selling really well. I think it plays to our value in the marketplace, our strong brand, our consistent pricing, and the ability for folks to take advantage of our increasing innovation in the marketplace, the service that we deliver and our efforts to make the healthcare system a little simpler for our members.
 We're really encouraged by the growth that we've had over the last 18 months. We see that momentum continuing as we pace into 2016 and feel good about what that will deliver in 2016 and 2017 and beyond for our shareholders and our members.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Scott Fidel,  Credit Suisse - Analyst   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Pretty positive. Maybe we'll just take two more questions and then, as you know, John and Brett will be available through the course of the day for questions and any other areas of interest. So, maybe two more questions, please.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We can take our first question from Ralph Giacobbe from Citigroup. Please go ahead.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ralph Giacobbe,  Citigroup - Analyst   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Good morning. I just want to go back to cash flow, again. It seemed even stronger than usual.
 Are you holding back claims at all with ICD-10 implementation? And maybe, just generally speaking, are you seeing any impact at this point from a coding and acuity perspective relative to your expectations? Thanks.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Not at all. But I will let Dave handle that and others who want to comment on coding. But those are not issues at all. Dave?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dave Wichmann,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - President and CFO   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I'm not sure what to add to that, other than not at all, those are not issues at all. This is just purely really more refined cash flow management principals across the Company. The enterprise is doing well and really managing cash flows.
 Obviously the performance of the business sans exchanges is strong, and then couple that with the balance sheet management. We are not holding claims or doing anything other than paying them in accordance with contractual terms.
 It's part of the value that comes from a more integrated UnitedHealth Group than what we've experienced in the past, the more fragmented healthcare platforms or claims adjudication platforms. As we continue to move towards a common set of technologies, working more closely with Optum and UnitedHealthcare, we're seeing the benefits of strong cash flow.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And on terms of ICD-10 maybe we'll go real quickly to UnitedHealthcare as it relates to them and then flip to Optum and talk about more broadly the industry and what we're seeing.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Dan Schumacher,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CFO of UnitedHealthcare   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure, Ralph, it's Dan Schumacher. From an ICD-10 standpoint, there's really nothing to update from the investor conference and my comments there. The reality is, we are paying tens of millions of claims in the ICD-10 code set. As you look at inbound volumes, rejection rates, auto adjudication rates, throughput, ending inventory, all the way through that process stream, I would tell you all of that is in line. So, there's nothing getting hung up, nothing getting slowed down. And to Dave's' point, really around the cash flow it comes down to just managing better to contract terms as we have more of our business on common platforms, which allows us to do those kinds of offsets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In terms of OptumInsight?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Larry Renfro,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO  of Optum   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. Obviously we believe we have an extremely strong product line that we're offering that's increasing productivity and results. And I'll ask John Prince to comment on this.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 John Prince,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - EVP and Chief of Operations of Optum   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks, Larry. Ralph, in terms of ICD-10 we've been practicing and preparing for ICD-10 for years. In terms of working with our customers we've actually had great results. One of the products that has had great results is our computer-assisted coding. We've actual had a very distinctive product in the market and the customers that have used it actually have seen a significant increase in productivity versus traditional products in the market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We'll take a question from Ana Gupte with Leerink Partners.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ana Gupte,  Leerink Partners - Analyst   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Good morning. I wanted to follow up on Peter's question and your response around what I thought I heard was upside to your guidance for 2016. I'm just looking at all the things that have developed. We've got a weak flu season.
 You've pulled forward even more losses from exchanges and Medicaid. Pricing looks pretty good. Your days in claims payable have gone up year over year by three days.
 Your star membership rebalancing looks good, as well. And special enrollment periods may be a tailwind. Are there any headwinds we're missing? Or should we think that there could be upside to your consolidated care ratio and your margins that you're projecting for 2016?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Stephen Hemsley,  UnitedHealth Group Inc. - CEO   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is an excellent list. I'm not sure I could have done better myself. It is the 19th of January. I think we should be careful in terms of how we are discussing our results.
 We have to truly work through the balance of our exchange. We do think we have reserve for it and considered it appropriately into our 2016 numbers. And, as I said, it's the 19th of January and I think that we should move forward thoughtfully and prudently in our business. So, I think those are the factors.
 In terms of headwinds, as we've said before, we have less than before but we clearly have to play out the year, and that's what we intend to do. I think our focus is to really deliver a very clean, strong financial year to the marketplace to continue to advance our business, continue to innovate, continue to diversify across both the platforms of UnitedHealthcare and Optum. That's our focus.
 I think we always endeavor to try to perform better. But I think our guidance right now is a very appropriate range. I'm assuming you've taken some of the input in terms of how the quarters might play out from our commentary in the teleconference.
 So, I think we'll just end it at that. Once again I'll thank you for joining us today and I'll leave you with a few closing thoughts.
 As businesses, Optum and UnitedHealthcare we think really advanced their capabilities significantly in 2015. UnitedHealth Group's revenues and operating earnings grew significantly, as cash flows increased, as we've talked about, over 20%. And our dividend has increased and we will certainly address that in the middle of the year, as is our custom.
 UnitedHealthcare served more than 1.7 million people domestically, growing virtually in every market that we serve. And Optum grew its revenues by 42% and its backlog by more than 20%.
 In 2016 we expect to continue and accelerate this growth trend and carry it into 2017 and beyond. We intend to further differentiate our products, our services, by focusing on consistently high quality in everything we do and creating real value for customers and consumers on their terms. We remain committed to delivering clean, strong financial results, as I said, for our shareholders this year, with a growing pipeline of future opportunities.
 We appreciate your interest today. This concludes our call. And, as I said, John and Brett will be available through the course of the day. We thank you for your attention. Thank you.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's program. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.
]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q4 2015 UnitedHealth Group Inc Earnings Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>Hopkins</city>
  <companyName>UnitedHealth Group Inc</companyName>
  <companyTicker>UNH</companyTicker>
  <startDate>19-Jan-16 1:45pm GMT</startDate>
  <companyId>279087</companyId>
  <CUSIP>91324P102</CUSIP>
  <SEDOL>2917766</SEDOL>
  <ISIN>US91324P1021</ISIN>
</Event>